<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<datafile xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="wiitdb.xsd">
	<WiiTDB version="201812041646" games="101"/>
	<game name="007 James Bond">
		<id>65728A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>007 James Bond</title>
	<synopsis>007 James Bond is a shoot-'em-up game developed and published by Tsukuda Original for the SG-1000. It was ported from Parker Brothers's 1983 game of the same name, which was published for various American computers/consoles.

007 James Bond was the last SG-1000 game to be produced by the company.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Cuando se trata de acción e intriga rápidas, nadie lo hace mejor que Bond. James Bond.
Pero puedes intentarlo cuando representas escenas de cuatro grandes clásicos de películas de James Bond.
El vehículo especialmente diseñado de 007 lo llevará en el viaje de su vida, ¡por tierra, aire y bajo el mar! A través de todo, debes evitar los obstáculos, evitar a los enemigos y cumplir cuatro misiones diferentes.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>007 James Bond est un shoot-'em-up développé et publié par Tsukuda Original pour le SG-1000. 
il a été le dernier jeu SG-1000 à être produit par la société.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="06" day="30"/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Bank Panic">
		<id>65692A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Bank Panic</title>
	<synopsis>Bank Panic is an arcade shooting game developed by Sanritsu and manufactured by Sega in 1984. It was later ported by Sega to the SG-1000 and Sega Master System. An unlicensed clone called West Bank was released for several home computer systems. The same hardware would also be used for the later Sega/Sanritsu game Combat Hawk.

The player takes on the role of a sheriff in 19th century USA, protecting a bank from armed robbers. There are twelve doors arranged in a circle, with the player in the centre, which can be viewed three at a time. Robbers who appear from the doors are to be shot (after they draw their weapons, for a higher score) and customers are to be ignored while they make a deposit. Once deposits have been made from all twelve doors, the level is complete.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Asume el papel de un sheriff en los Estados Unidos del siglo XIX, protegiendo a un banco de ladrones armados. Hay doce puertas dispuestas en círculo, con el jugador en el centro, que se puede ver de tres en tres. Los ladrones que aparecen desde las puertas deben ser fusilados (después de sacar sus armas, para obtener una puntuación más alta) y los clientes deben ser ignorados mientras hacen un depósito. Una vez que se han hecho los depósitos de las doce puertas, el nivel está completo.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Bank Panic tire son inspiration de la vision "populaire" du far West et de son lot de bandits, cow-girls et autres tireurs plus rapides que leur ombre. Ici vous serez (on l'imagine car rien n'est explicité) une sorte de mercenaire, engagé par une banque pour assurer la sécurité des biens déposés par les clients et accessoirement attirer de nouveaux "épargnants".</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<synopsis>Bank Panic es un arcade de disparo desarrollado por Sanritsu y manufacturado por Sega en 1984. Tuvo su port para la SG-1000 y también para Sega Master System. Un clon sin licencia llamado West Bank fue lanzado para varios sistemas domésticos. El mismo hardware fue usado más tarde por Sega y Sanritsu para Combat Hawk.

El jugador toma el rol de un sheriff del siglo XIX en los USA y debe proteger un banco de unos ladrones. Hay doce puertas colocadas en circulo con el jugador en el centro se pueden ver tres a la vez. Los ladrones aparecen desde las puertas y se les debe disparar una vez que sacan sus armas para obtener más puntuación. No se debe disparar a los clientes del banco. Una vez que los clientes han hecho sus depósitos en todas las puertas el nivel queda completado.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sanritsu Denki Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="18">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Black Onyx, The">
		<id>65693A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Black Onyx, The</title>
	<synopsis>The Black Onyx is a role-playing game developed by Bullet Proof Software. It was released, among other consoles and computers, for the SG-1000 in 1987. It was the last SG-1000 game to be released in card form, and the last to be published by Sega, but it is currently unknown as to whether it was the last SG-1000 game. PC-8801 and MSX versions had been released in 1984 and 1985, respectively, meaning this version is unusually late. The game was followed by The Black Onyx II: Search For The Fire Crystal, which saw its original MSX release in 1984.</synopsis>
	<genre>Role playing games</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El juego tiene lugar en la ciudad de fantasía de Utsuro como una fiesta de hasta cinco héroes valientes (y personalizables) que se adentran en un laberinto subterráneo para encontrar el legendario Black Onyx y romper la maldición de la ciudad.</synopsis>
	<genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Black Onyx est un jeu de rôles développé par Bullet Proof Software. Il et sortis sur diverses consoles et ordinateurs, et sur le SG-1000 en 1987. C'était le dernier jeu SG-1000 à être distribué sous forme de cartouche, et le dernier à être publié par Sega, mais il est actuellement inconnu. Le jeu a été suivi par The Black Onyx II: Search For The Fire Crystal, qui a vu sa sortie originale sur MSX en 1984</synopsis>
	<genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>The Black Onyx</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Bullet-Proof Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1987" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Bomb Jack">
		<id>65694A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Bomb Jack</title>
	<synopsis>Bomb Jack is an arcade game developed by Tehkan which was later ported to the SG-1000 by Sega in 1985. The aim of the game is to collect all the bombs in the playfield while avoiding monsters. Extra points are awarded for collecting the bombs in a specific order.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Toma el control de Jack y recoge todas las bombas para pasar a la siguiente ronda. Esto no es tan fácil como suena con numerosos enemigos como pájaros, tortugas y momias que se interponen en el camino.

Los fondos para los Niveles consisten en ubicaciones reales como; Miami Beach, Sphynx o Sastle Neuschwanstein.
 
Tiene 99 niveles pero una vez que alcanzas 99 el juego salta de vuelta a la ronda 0. Los niveles individuales realmente se repiten mucho antes.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Bomb Jack est un jeu d'arcade développé par Tehkan qui a ensuite été porté au SG-1000 par Sega en 1985. Le but du jeu est de rassembler toutes les bombes disponible sur l'écran tout en évitant les monstres. Des points supplémentaires sont attribués pour la collecte des bombes dans un ordre spécifique.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tehkan Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Bomberman Special">
		<id>102098</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Bomberman Special</title>
	<synopsis>Bomberman Special is an MSX release in the Bomberman series of games. It was brought without a license to the SG-1000 in Taiwan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Bomberman Special es una versión lanzada para MSX de la serie de juegos Bomberman. La versión de SG-1000 salió en Taiwan sin licencia.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Bomberman Special est une version MSX du jeu de la  la série Bomberman. Il a été porté sans licence sur la SG-1000 à Taiwan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Hudson</developer>
		<publisher>DahJee</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Borderline">
		<id>65695A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Borderline</title>
	<synopsis>Borderline is a VIC Dual arcade game developed in 1980 by Sega. It is a shoot-'em-up in which the player controls a red jeep who must destroy the enemy refineries.

Borderline was ported to the SG-1000 in 1983, and has also been released as part of the Sega Ages 2500 series in Japan. The second gameplay section was also recycled for the Atari 2600 release of Thunderground, though instead of driving a jeep the player controls a tank.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Entra violentamente en la zona de energía maniobrando libremente el jeep rojo. A lo largo de las escenas primera a cuarta, continúe avanzando en un esfuerzo por destruir las fortalezas y las sedes enemigas evitando los ataques de los tanques enemigos, automóviles blindados, aviones y misiles. Comience su invasión a la siguiente escena después de destruir todas las fortalezas de la escena actual en la que está inmerso. Cuando destruye por completo la sede central en la cuarta escena final, la operación estratégica de jeep que lanzó arroja una victoria aplastante para usted !</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Borderline est un jeu d'arcade VIC Dual développé en 1980 par Sega. C'est un shoot'em-up dans lequel le joueur contrôle une jeep rouge qui doit détruire les raffineries ennemies. Borderline a été porté à la SG-1000 en 1983, et a également été publié dans le cadre de la série Sega Ages 2500 au Japon. Le jeux existe également sur Atari 2600 et se nomme Thunderground, mais au lieu de conduire une jeep, le joueur contrôle un tank.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Castle, The">
		<id>65764A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>The Castle</title>
	<synopsis>The Castle is video game developed by ASCII and released for the SG-1000 in 1986. It is a port of an MSX game of the same name, and is largely identical due to the similar hardware between the two machines. Due to the decline of the SG-1000 and emergence of the Sega Master System, the game was not released in Europe or Australia like many other SG-1000 games. The game has a fairly standard plot of rescuing a princess from a castle, though the game itself was considered very large for the time. It also contains a map system similar to that of later Metroid and Castlevania games.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El juego tiene una trama bastante estándar, rescatar a una princesa de un castillo, aunque el juego en sí se consideró muy grande para la época. También contiene un sistema de mapas similar al de los juegos posteriores de Metroid y Castlevania.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>The Castle est un jeu vidéo développé par ASCII et sorti pour le SG-1000 en 1986. Il est un port d'un jeu MSX du même nom, et est largement identique en raison du matériel similaire entre les deux machines. En raison du déclin du SG-1000 et de l'émergence du Sega Master System, le jeu n'a pas été publié en Europe ou en Australie comme beaucoup d'autres jeux SG-1000. Le jeu a une histoire assez standard ou il faut sauver une princesse d'un château, bien que le jeu lui-même ait été considéré comme très grand pour l'époque. Il contient également un système de cartes similaire à celui des jeux Metroid et Castlevania.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>The Castle</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>ASCII Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Chack'n Pop">
		<id>65697A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Chack'n Pop</title>
	<synopsis>Chack'n Pop is an arcade game developed by Taito which was subsequently ported to the SG-1000 in 1985. It follows a yellow creature named Chack'n who must traverse across several mazes blowing up monsters.

The SG-1000 version of the game includes extra cutscenes and a training level not seen in the arcade version.

Though Chack'n Pop was not a particularly successful game for Taito, it would go on to inspire the success of Bubble Bobble, which shares many of the same characters and devotes a stage to Chack'n Pop. Chack'n has also cameoed in numerous Taito games since, including Bubble Bobble, Fairyland Story, Parasol Stars, Puzzle Bobble (and sequels), Bubble Symphony, Bubble Memories and Arkanoid DS.

Curiously this SG-1000 version uses the katakana script for writing Chack'n Pop as opposed to the hiragana script used in almost every other version.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Un primer juego de acción Arcade de Taito y en muchos sentidos un precursor de su mayor éxito Bubble Bobble. El jugador controla el Chack'n pop del mismo nombre mientras intenta evitar que los monstruos destruyan sus huevos.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Chack'n Pop est un jeu d'arcade développé par Taito qui a été porté par la suite au SG-1000 en 1985. C'est l'histoire d'une créature jaune appelée Chack'n qui doit traverser plusieurs labyrinthes faisant sauter des monstres. La version SG-1000 du jeu inclut des cutscenes supplémentaires et un niveau d'entrainement non présent dans la version d'arcade. Bien que Chack'n Pop n'ait pas été un jeu particulièrement réussi pour Taito, il contribuera à inspirer le succès de Bubble Bobble, qui partage beaucoup des mêmes personnages et consacre une scène à Chack'n Pop. Chack'n a également été représenter dans de nombreux jeux de Taito depuis, notamment Bubble Bobble, Fairyland Story, Parasol Stars, Puzzle Bobble (et suites), Bubble Symphony, Bubble Memories et Arkanoid DS.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Challenge Derby">
		<id>65770A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Challenge Derby</title>
	<synopsis>Challenge Derby is a horse racing game for the SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports with Animals,Horses race</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Challenge Derby es un juego de carreras de caballos para SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes con animales,Carreras de caballos</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Challenge Derby est un jeu de course hippique pour le SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport avec animaux,Course de chevaux</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport mit Tieren,Pferderennen</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<synopsis>Challenge Derby é um jogo de corrida de cavalos para o SG-1000</synopsis>
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte com animais,Corrida com Cavalos</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Challenge Derby</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Baseball">
		<id>65698A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Baseball</title>
	<synopsis>Champion Baseball is an arcade baseball game developed by ADK. Sega distributed the game worldwide, and produced an SG-1000 port in 1983. Alpha Denshi also made a sequel, only released in arcades.

Champion Baseball is said to have been a hugely successful arcade game in Japan, even receiving its own dedicated parlours in the country (of the sort first seen with Space Invaders in 1978).</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Baseball</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Este es un juego de béisbol totalmente atractivo y emocionante en el que puedes disfrutar de todos los tipos imaginables de patrones de béisbol uno tras otro como en un juego real. Este juego te permite competir contra el equipo de la computadora (el equipo P contra el equipo C). Además, este juego ahora permite que 2 jugadores compitan entre sí y asegura que tu disfrute se verá incrementado al doble.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Béisbol</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion Baseball est un jeu d'arcade de baseball développé par ADK. Sega a distribué le jeu dans le monde entier et a produit une version pour la SG-1000 en 1983. Alpha Denshi a également fait une suite, seulement disponible en arcade. Champion Baseball est censé avoir été un jeu d'arcade très populaire au Japon, il à même reçu ses propres salons dédiés dans le pays (du genre de ceux vu avec Space Invaders en 1978).</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Baseball</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Baseball</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Baseball</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Alpha Denshi Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Billiards">
		<id>65699A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Billiards</title>
	<synopsis>Champion Billiards is a simplistic billiards game built for the SG-1000. It is the first game in Compile's "Lunar Pool" series. It was not released outside of Japan.

Unlike the other Champion Sports games, Champion Billiards is not an accurate representation of it's sport. Instead, Champion Billiards is a level-based physics game. The goal of each level is to use the red cue ball to sink the other balls.

Trivia: Breaking open the yellow ball can release a yellow Flicky.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Pool</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Champion Billiards es el primer juego en la serie "Pool Lunar" de Compile y fue lanzado sólo en Japón. A diferencia de los otros juegos de Champion Sports, no es una representación exacta ya que el objetivo es usar la bola roja para hundir las otras bolas.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Billar</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion Billiards est un jeu de billard simpliste construit pour le SG-1000. Il s'agit du premier jeu de la série "Lunar Pool". Il n'a pas été publié en dehors du Japon. Contrairement aux autres jeux Champion Sports, Champion Billiards n'est pas une représentation exacte de son sport. Au lieu de cela, Champion Billiards est un jeu ou le but de chaque niveau est d'utiliser la boule rouge pour enfoncer les autres boules.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Billard</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Billard</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Sinuca</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Boxing">
		<id>65700A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Boxing</title>
	<synopsis>Champion Boxing is a simplistic boxing game built for the SG-1000. It was later re-released in arcades for SG-1000-based arcade hardware. An MSX version was released in 1985, published by Pony Canyon.

There are five difficulty levels, and the aim is to knock out the opponent. 1 attacks, 2 selects an attack. Interestingly, if a player wins Pengo will make a cameo.

Champion Boxing is also noteworthy for being the first game coded by Yu Suzuki in his first year at Sega.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Boxing</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>La emoción se acumula gradualmente a medida que lucha en cada una de las rondas de 90 segundos en esta ronda de 8 asaltos. Tu oponente es un duro luchador rubio joven. Lanza DIRECTO, JAB y UPPERCUT golpea directamente a la cara del oponente o su cuerpo. Mantén la ráfaga de golpes rápidos y furiosos aprovechando tu trabajo de pies superior. Cálmate en el Nivel 1 y luego mejora tus habilidades limpiando consecutivamente los niveles más altos. Si, en el Nivel 5, ganas con un KO de 10, ¡te convertirás en el campeón del mundo!</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Boxeo</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion boxing est un jeu de boxe simpliste construit pour le SG-1000. Il a été porter plus tard dans les salle d'arcades. Une version MSX a été publiée en 1985, publiée par Pony Canyon. Il y a cinq niveaux de difficulté, et le but est de frapper l'adversaire. 1:attaque, 2:sélectionne une attaque. Fait intéressant, si un joueur gagne Pengo fera un brève apparition. . Champion boxing est également remarquer pour être le premier jeu codé par Yu Suzuki dans sa première année chez Sega.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Boxe</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Boxen</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Boxe</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Champion Boxing</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Golf">
		<id>65701A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Golf</title>
	<synopsis>If it's raining on Sunday ... it's CHAMPION GOLF day. You can enjoy hitting the ball with the appropriate club to match the shot, walking around the course with the considerate caddie over its extensive fairways, roughs, greens, ponds and bunker areas. Getting a "Birdie", "Eagle" or an amazing "Hole in One", or the even more miraculous "Albatross" will make you feel like you are on top of the world.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Si llueve el domingo ... es día CHAMPION GOLF. Puedes disfrutar de golpear la pelota con el palo apropiado para que coincida con el tiro, caminando por el campo con el caddie sobre sus extensos fairways, roughs, greens, estanques y áreas de bunker. Obtener un "Birdie", "Eagle" o un asombroso "Hole in One", o el aún más milagroso "Albatros" te harán sentir como si estuvieras en la cima del mundo.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion Golf est un jeu de golf pour le SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Golfe</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Champion Golf</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Logitec</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Ice Hockey">
		<id>65702A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Ice Hockey</title>
	<synopsis>Champion Ice Hockey is a simplistic ice hockey game built for the SG-1000.

You play as the Red team vs. the Blue team. One button shoots, while the other button passes. Up and down control not only your goalie, but also the direction of the scoring shot.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Hockey</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Champion Ice Hockey es un juego muy simple en el que  juega el equipo Red contra el Blue. Un botón dispara y el otro pasa. Con las direcciones arriba y abajo controlas tanto al portero como la dirección del disparo.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Hockey</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Dans Champion Ice Hockey vous pouvez jouer un match de hockey sur glace à trois niveaux de difficulté: amateur, semi-professionnel et professionnel. Un arbitre est présent pour siffler la faute. Un match dure 20 min.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Hockey</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Eishockey</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Hóquei</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Champion Ice Hockey</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Kendou">
		<id>65703A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Kendou</title>
	<synopsis>Champion Kendou is a simplistic kendou game built for the SG-1000 and MSX. It was only released in Japan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Champion Kendou es un juego de Kendo creado para SG-1000 y MSX que sólo salió en Japón.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion Kendou est un jeu de kendou simpliste construit pour le SG-1000 et MSX. Il est sorti seulement au Japon.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Champion Kendou</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Pro Wrestling">
		<id>65704A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Pro Wrestling</title>
	<synopsis>To play for a rank you 'll have to fight three matches. Winning two out of three matches promotes you t</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Wrestling</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Champion Pro Wrestling es un juego de lucha libre desarrollado para SG-1000 y después para MSX. Hay que ganar tres enfrentamiento para alzarte con la victoria.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Lucha libre</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion Pro Wrestling est un jeu de lutte sur SG-1000. Il a ensuite été porté au matériel d'arcade basé sur le SG-1000 et sur MSX. D'autres ordinateurs japonais ont reçu Champion Prowres Special à la place.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Lutte</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Wrestling</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Luta Livre</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Champion Pro Wrestling</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="02" day="01"/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Soccer">
		<id>65705A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Soccer</title>
	<synopsis>Champion Soccer is a simplistic football game built for the SG-1000. Pony Canyon later brought it to the MSX.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Soccer</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Champion Soccer es un juego de fútbol creado para SG-1000 y trasladado por Pony Canyon a MSX.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Fútbol</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion Soccer est un jeu de football simpliste construit pour le SG-1000. Pony Canyon l'a ensuite porté au MSX.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Football</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Fußball</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Futebol</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Champion Soccer</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Champion Tennis">
		<id>65706A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Champion Tennis</title>
	<synopsis>Champion Tennis is a simplistic tennis game built for the SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Tennis</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Servir, recibir y aplastar la pelota. Ataca el punto débil de tu rival. ¡Usa todos los rincones de la cancha para tu ventaja y obtén una victoria gloriosa sobre tu oponente! Este es un juego deportivo altamente intelectual y competitivo que requiere nervios y concentración agudos.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Tenis</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Champion Tennis est un jeu de tennis simpliste développé pour le SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Tennis</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Tennis</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Tênis</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Champion Tennis</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Championship Lode Runner">
		<id>65707A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Championship Lode Runner</title>
	<synopsis>This package contained 50 of the most challenging levels ever designed, and was intended for expert players only. It did not include the level editor, you had to play through the levels in</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Ábrete camino a través del laberinto para encontrar las cámaras secretas llenas de oro. Escalando y saltando a través de un laberinto de escaleras y plataformas, e incluso perforando ladrillos, tu Comando Intergaláctico debe atrapar o matar a los torpes guardias del Imperio que protegen la cámara. Pon a prueba tu estrategia en más de 75 niveles diferentes.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Lode Runner est un jeu puzzle / action développé à l'origine par Douglas E. Smith et publié par Broderbund Software en 1983. Il est sortis sur de nombreux ordinateurs domestiques et consoles de jeux vidéo de l'époque, y compris le SG-1000. Comme le port NES, cette version a seulement 50 niveaux au lieu de 150 dans la version d'origine sur Apple II, mais est beaucoup plus rapide.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Choplifter">
		<id>65708A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Choplifter</title>
	<synopsis>Choplifter is a 1982 Apple II game developed by Dan Gorlin and published by Broderbund. In the game you pilot a helicopter and must rescue people from prisoner of war camps. Sega were responsible for an arcade remake on both the Sega System 1 and Sega System 2 hardware in 1985. This version was ported to a variety of platforms, including the SG-1000 in 1985 and the Sega Master System in 1986.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Maneja un helicóptero en la mejor aventura de acción de la nación. Bolsillos de rehenes internacionales están atrapados. En todo el mundo En Oriente Medio. En los mares del sur Y en una base secreta en algún lugar de una caverna. Tú mandas un equipo de rescate de helicópteros. Y su trabajo es derribar su helicóptero, rescatar a los rehenes y devolverlos a un lugar seguro. Todo el tiempo esquivando y destruyendo el peligroso fuego enemigo. ¡Un juego de helicóptero lleno de acción en su mejor momento!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Choplifter est un jeu de 1982 sortis sur Apple II développé par Dan Gorlin et publié par Broderbund. Dans le jeu, vous pilotez un hélicoptère et devez sauver les gens des camps de prisonniers de guerre. Sega sortira un remake arcade sur les systèmes Sega System 1 et Sega System 2 en 1985. Cette version a été portée sur une variété de plates-formes, y compris la Sega Master System en 1986.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 1-Nen)">
		<id>65771A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 1-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 1-Nen) (traducción: Gramática inglesa (escuela secundaria 1er año)) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para SC-3000 (y SG- 1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100).
Fue lanzado solo en Japón.</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 1-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 2-Nen)">
		<id>172286</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 2-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eibunpou (Chuugaku 2-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer Center</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 1-Nen)">
		<id>65772A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 1-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 1-Nen) (traducción: Composición inglesa (escuela secundaria 1er año)) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para SC-3000 (y SG- 1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100).</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 1-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 2-Nen)">
		<id>102224</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 2-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 2-Nen)  (traducción: Composición en inglés (escuela secundaria de 2 ° año)) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para SC-3000 (y SG -1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100).</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eisakubun (Chuugaku 2-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 1-Nen)">
		<id>65773A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 1-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 1-Nen) (traducción: Vocabulario Inglés (escuela secundaria 1er año)) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para el SC-3000 (y SG- 1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100).</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 1-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 2-Nen)">
		<id>102225</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 2-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 2-Nen)(traducción: Vocabulario Inglés (escuela secundaria menor segundo año)) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para el SC-3000 (y SG- 1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100).</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Chuugaku Hisshuu Eitango (Chuugaku 2-Nen)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Congo Bongo">
		<id>65709A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Congo Bongo</title>
	<synopsis>Congo Bongo , originally known as Tip Top, is a 1983 arcade platformer game developed by Sega. It is often considered an isometric equivalent to Nintendo's Donkey Kong, as it stars a protagonist chasing after a large ape (in this game, called "Bongo"). However, unlike Donkey Kong, the game is set in a jungle, the graphics are more detailed and there are more enemies and traps.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Bongo es un mono travieso que incendia la tienda de safari. El cazador de safaris perdió su tienda y sus posesiones, y busca venganza del simio por su broma práctica. El cazador de safaris persigue a Bongo y atraviesa el peligroso Congo para vengarse</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Congo Bongo, à l'origine connu sous le nom Tip Top, est un jeu de plateforme d'arcade de 1983 développé par Sega. Il est souvent considéré comme un équivalent isométrique de Donkey Kong de Nintendo, car il met en scène un protagoniste poursuivant un grand singe (dans ce jeu, appelé "Bongo"). Cependant, contrairement à Donkey Kong, le jeu est situé dans une jungle, les graphiques sont plus détaillés et il y a plus d'ennemis et de pièges.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="C_so!">
		<id>65710A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>C_So!</title>
	<synopsis>C_So! (C-SO!) is a 1985 SG-1000 game developed by Compile and published by Sega. It is a port of an MSX game from the same year, which was published by Pony Canyon.



The game has the player collect various items and defeat monsters by using see-saws. In order to progress, all items must be collected and all monsters must be destroyed. There is also an edit mode, allowing the player to create their own levels.



The game was only released in Japan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>C_So! es un juego 1985 SG-1000 desarrollado por Compile y publicado por Sega. Es un puerto de un juego de MSX del mismo año, que fue publicado por Pony Canyon.nnnnEl juego hace que el jugador recoja varios objetos y derrote a los monstruos mediante el uso de sierras. Para progresar, todos los elementos deben ser recolectados y todos los monstruos deben ser destruidos. También hay un modo de edición, que permite al jugador crear sus propios niveles.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Le but du jeu est de recueillir divers éléments et vaincre les monstres en utilisant des planches à bascule. Afin de progresser, tous les éléments doivent être collectés et tous les monstres doivent être détruits. Il y a aussi un mode d'édition, permettant au joueur de créer ses propres niveaux.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>C_So!</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Doki Doki Penguin Land">
		<id>65711A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Doki Doki Penguin Land</title>
	<synopsis>Doki Doki Penguin Land is a 1985 game initially developed by Sega for the SG-1000. It is a platform-based puzzle game, where a penguin must guide an egg down the screen making sure not to break it.

The basic aim of Doki Doki Penguin Land is to guide an egg from the top of the screen to the bottom. To do so means digging downwards, making sure it does not smash in the process. As a puzzle-platformer, everything is affected by gravity, and if the egg falls from a great height, it will smash. Success is achieved by making your way down the playfield carefully.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El objetivo básico de Doki Doki Penguin Land es guiar un huevo desde la parte superior de la pantalla hasta la parte inferior. Hacerlo significa cavar hacia abajo, asegurándose de que no se rompa en el proceso. Como rompecabezas de plataformas, todo se ve afectado por la gravedad, y si el huevo cae desde una gran altura, se romperá. El éxito se logra bajando cuidadosamente por el campo de juego.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Doki Doki Penguin Land est un jeu de 1985 initialement développé par Sega pour le SG-1000. C'est un jeu de type puzzle / plate-forme, où un pingouin doit guider un oeuf vers le bas de l'écran en veillant à ne pas le casser.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Dokidoki Penguin Land</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Dragon Wang">
		<id>65712A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Dragon Wang</title>
	<synopsis>The protagonist is Wang (inspired by Jackie Chan and/or his character Thomas), hence the unfortunate title Dragon Wang. Wang is Chinese for King.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El juego fue inspirado por el clásico arcade Kung-Fu Master. Más tarde recibió una secuela llamada Kung Fu Kid.nnnnEl protagonista es Wang (inspirado en Jackie Chan y / o su personaje Thomas), de ahí el desafortunado título Dragon Wang. Wang es chino para King.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Dragon Wang est un jeu d'action pour le SG-1000. Vous jouez en tant qu'homme et devez lancer d'autres hommes à travers quatre étapes. C'est le précurseur de Kung Fu Kid sur Sega Master System.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Dragon Wang</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Drol">
		<id>65713A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Drol</title>
	<synopsis>Drol is an SG-1000 game released in 1985. Originally developed by Broderbund for various home computers in the west, it was brought to the SG-1000 by Sega and released exclusively in Japan. You play as a robot who must rescue his children.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Entra en el mundo de los sueños divertido, desafiante y lleno de suspenso de Drol, donde una pequeña niña pelirroja y su hermanito de hélice esperan tu rescate. Han sido atraídos por la maldición de un hechicero a las ruinas de una civilización perdida en varios niveles. Hipnotizados, deambulan sin rumbo por los pasillos subterráneos, ignorando los peligros que los rodean.
Es su tarea - como un héroe equipado con una mochila cohete y alcance de radar de pantalla completa - esquivar saltos de escorpiones, monstruos y serpientes, pavos voladores, espadas, dagas, flechas, imanes, hechiceros y aspiradoras (!) en sus intentos de reunir a los niños con su madre.
¡El sentido del humor irónico de Drol y las imágenes de dibujos animados increíblemente detalladas hacen de este juego un encanto!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Drol est un jeu SG-1000 lancé en 1985. Initialement développé par Broderbund pour divers ordinateurs domestiques, il a été porté à la SG-1000 par Sega et est sorti exclusivement au Japon. Vous jouez avec un robot qui doit sauver ses enfants.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Elevator Action">
		<id>65714A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Elevator Action</title>
	<synopsis>The player assumes the role of a spy infiltrating a 30-story building filled with elevators. The player is pursued by enemy agents who appear from behind closed doors. These agents must be dealt with via force or evasion. Successful completion of a level involves collecting all the secret documents and traversing the building from top to bottom. In the lower floors of the building, the elevator systems can be complex enough that puzzle-solving skills are needed. The controls consist of a 4-way joystick and two buttons, one to shoot and the other for jumping and kicking.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Como Agente 17, es su misión robar documentos del gobierno de un edificio de defensa secreta altamente custodiado. Al bajar por los ascensores y las escaleras mecánicas, debe recoger los archivos y escapar al auto de escape en el garaje. ¡Pero ten cuidado con los agentes enemigos!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Elevator Action est un jeu d'arcade développé par Taito qui a été porté plus tard au SG-1000 exclusivement pour le Japon. Il s'agit de l'un des deux jeux d'action avec élévateur à être sortis sur un système Sega, l'autre étant Elevator Action Returns.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Elevator Action</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Exerion">
		<id>65715A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Exerion</title>
	<synopsis>The FIGHTER EX rushed in and out attacking the monstrous enemy groups in the 6 mysterious, diferent DIMENSIONAL worlds.
The enemy is constantly in pursuit of the FIGTHER EX.
The figther's missile attacking the enemy come down like showers of hail. Be on the alert !!
The "Dual Beam" allows you to shoot downn the enemy, and the "Single Beam", to speedily and continuously attack it.
See how successful you are in battling the enemy through the 6 dangerous worlds !</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El FIGHTER EX se apresuró a atacar a los monstruosos grupos enemigos en los 6 misteriosos mundos DIMENSIONALES diferentes. El enemigo está constantemente persiguiendo al FIGTHER EX. El misil del figther ataca al enemigo y cae como lluvia de granizo. ¡Estén alerta!
El "Dual Beam" te permite disparar contra el enemigo y el "Single Beam" para atacarlo de forma rápida y continua.
¡Mira qué éxito tienes en luchar contra el enemigo a través de los 6 peligrosos mundos!</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Exerion est un shoot-'em-up d'arcade publié par Jaleco en 1983. Il a été porté à plusieurs systèmes comprenant le SG-1000. Exerion est un shoot'em-up très simple, mais son principal attrait à l'époque était ses fonds parallaxe, dont les positions changeaient selon les coordonnées du vaisseau du joueur. Malheureusement, les effets ne rendait pas bien sur le SG-1000, car le défilement était saccadé.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Jaleco</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Flicky">
		<id>65716A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Flicky</title>
	<synopsis>Little baby birds, PIOPIOes, are seen basking on the bright sunny terrace. It's now time for the little PIOPIOes to take their midafternoon snack. FLICKY, your mother, is coming to take all of you back home. Let's return skipping merrily hand in hand with mama FLICKY. Oh, oh, we've got a big problem!! The ill-natured stray cat (NYANNYAN) is coming. Escape by jumping over him and throwing hammers and mugs in an effort to hit and destroy the big bad cat. FLICKY, you'll feel really relieved when you have successfully taken all of your baby PIOPIOes back home, won't you?</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El pequeño bebé, PIOPIO, se ve tomando el sol en la terraza soleada brillante. Ahora es el momento para que los pequeños PIOPIOS tomen su bocadillo a media tarde, FLCKY, tu madre, viene a llevarte a todos a casa. Volvamos saltando alegremente tomados de la mano con mamá FLICKY. ¡Oh, oh, tenemos un gran problema! El gato callejero malhumorado (NYANNYAN) está por llegar. Escápese saltando sobre él y golpeando martillos y tazas en un esfuerzo por golpear y destruir al gran gato malo. FLICKY, realmente te sentirás aliviado cuando hayas llevado a todos tus PIOPIO de tu bebé a casa, ¿no es así?</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Flicky est un jeu vidéo sorti pour le matériel arcade Sega System 1 en 1984. Vous êtes un petit oiseau bleu appelé Flicky chargé de sauver les autres petits oiseaux avant qu'il ne soit mangé par les prédateurs. Il a été conçu par Youji Ishii, et a été connu comme Busty et Flippy au cours du développement.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Flicky</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Girl's Garden">
		<id>65718A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Girl's Garden</title>
	<synopsis>In order to prevent her boyfriend Minto from going to another little girl named Cocco, Papri must collect ten different flowers and return them to her boyfriend's house. Flowers must be caught in full bloom so that the number of flowers in her possession will increase; catching flowers too early will consider the flowers to be wasted and flowers caught too late will be wilted. Wilted flowers will ruin the bouquet, causing the player to lose half of the flowers.

Bears have a taste for honey and cause the player to lose one of two hearts if one of them attacks the player. However, the honey can be dropped in order to render the bear temporarily harmless to the player. Bees appear as the player's ally, giving her bonus items occasionally and extra honey if the player catches it on a flower.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Para evitar que su novio Minto vaya con otra niña pequeña llamada Cocco, Papri debe recoger diez flores diferentes y devolverlas a la casa de su novio. Las flores deben atraparse en plena floración para que la cantidad de flores en su posesión aumente; atrapar flores demasiado temprano considerará que las flores se desperdiciarán y las flores atrapadas demasiado tarde se marchitarán. Las flores marchitas arruinarán el ramo, causando que el jugador pierda la mitad de las flores.nnnnLos osos tienen gusto por la miel y hacen que el jugador pierda uno de dos corazones si uno de ellos ataca al jugador. Sin embargo, la miel puede soltarse para hacer que el oso sea temporalmente inofensivo para el jugador. Las abejas aparecen como aliadas del jugador, dándole elementos de bonificación de vez en cuando y miel adicional si el jugador lo atrapa en una flor.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Afin d'empêcher son petit ami Minto d'aller vers une autre petite fille nommée Cocco, Papri doit ramasser dix fleurs différentes et les retourner à la maison de son copain. Les fleurs doivent être prises en pleine floraison afin que le nombre de fleurs en sa possession augmente; Attraper des fleurs trop tôt gâcheras les fleurs et les fleurs prises trop tard seront fanées. Les fleurs fanées ruinerons le bouquet, causant au joueur la perte de la moitié des fleurs. Les ours sont attirés par le miel et le joueur peu perdre l'un de ces deux coeurs si l'un d'eux l'attaque . Cependant, le miel peut être laissé tomber afin de rendre l'ours temporairement inoffensif. Les abeilles apparaissent comme l'alliée du joueur, lui donnant des objets bonus et du miel supplémentaire si le joueur les attrapent sur une fleur.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Girl's Garden</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="12" day="01"/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Golgo 13">
		<id>65719A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Golgo 13</title>
	<synopsis>Golgo 13 is a shoot-'em-up game for the SG-1000 based on the Japanese manga of the same name.

The game has you shoot at windows of a passing train. Hitting objects that get in the way will make the bullet rebound and potentially kill you.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El juego te hace disparar a las ventanas de un tren que pasa. Golpear objetos que se interpongan hará que la bala rebote y potencialmente te mate.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Le jeu officiant sur une machine plutôt archaïque, le scénario est on s'en doute réduit à sa plus simple expression: l'absentéisme! Pour vous familiariser un peu avec le sujet voilà de quoi il retourne:
Golgo 13, personnage du manga éponyme de Takao Saito paru pour la première fois en 1968, est un tireur d'élite aux compétences extraordinaires, capable de réussir là où d'autres échoueraient. Vendant à prix d'or ses talents, il est l'assassin le plus recherché des polices du monde. Le jeu dans lequel vous l'incarnez sur SG-1000 nous montre un côté plutôt positif du personnage puisque même sans explications, on parvient à comprendre (imaginer) que ses actions sauvent des gens. Le but du jeu est en effet de tirer sur chacune des vitres d'un train en marche pour permettre aux occupants de fuir. Sont-ils victimes d'une prise d'otages? Le train a t'il été piégé? Nous ne le saurons jamais mais la présence d'hélicoptères armés ferait plutôt penser à une action terroriste!</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Golgo 13</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Gp World">
		<id>65720A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>GP World</title>
	<synopsis>GP World for the SG-1000 and MSX, is a loose conversion of the 1984 LaserDisc-based arcade game, GP World. It was released in 1985 exclusively in Japan.

Gameplay in this "8-bit" version of GP World is similar in concept to the arcade GP World but given the wildly differing hardware, different in execution. Most notably all graphics in the game are generated in real-time by the SG-1000 rather than streamed from a LaserDisc, which in turn leads to more predictable car physics. The concept of racing in four different types of GP is scrapped, replaced instead with a GP that spans the world and three selectable difficulties.</synopsis>
	<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>La mecánica de juego en esta versión de "8 bits" de GP World es similar en concepto al GP World de arcade pero dado el hardware tremendamente diferente, diferente en ejecución. Lo más notable es que todos los gráficos en el juego son generados en tiempo real por el SG-1000 en lugar de ser transmitidos desde un LaserDisc, lo que a su vez conduce a una física del automóvil más predecible. El concepto de carreras en cuatro tipos diferentes de GP se descarta, en su lugar se reemplaza con un GP que abarca el mundo y tres dificultades seleccionables.nnnnAl igual que el original, el juego utiliza una perspectiva en tercera persona similar a la de Turbo (aunque la cámara está situada detrás del volante), y ve al jugador competir en un coche de fórmula uno, navegando por el recorrido y evitando a otros conductores. Esta versión también es notable por tener un editor de pistas simplista. Es probable que el controlador SH-400 haya sido diseñado teniendo en cuenta este juego.</synopsis>
	<genre>Carreras, Conducción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>GP World pour le SG-1000 et MSX, est une pâle conversion du jeu d'arcade basé sur le  LaserDisc de 1984. Il est sorti en 1985 exclusivement au Japon. Le gameplay de cette version "8 bits" de GP World est semblable en concept à la version arcade de GP World mais compte tenu du matériel très différent, il se joue d'une autre manière. Plus particulièrement tous les graphiques dans le jeu sont générés en temps réel par le SG-1000 plutôt que diffusé à partir d'un LaserDisc. Le concept de la course dans quatre différents Grand Prix est mis au rebut, remplacé par un Grand Prix qui s'étend sur le monde et trois difficultés sélectionnables.</synopsis>
	<genre>Course, Conduite</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Rennen, Fahren</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>GP World</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Gulkave">
		<id>65721A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Gulkave</title>
	<synopsis>Gulkave  is an SG-1000 shoot 'em up game developed by Compile and published by Sega in 1986. It is a horizontal shooter, in which the player controls a spaceship that must destroy the 8 fortresses of the Gulbas Empire and several various enemies. Despite the limitations of the console, there are 30 "acts", and each "act" has a different background and there are numerous powerups available, setting it apart from most other SG-1000 shooters at the time.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Gulkave es un juego de disparos SG-1000 desarrollado por Compile y publicado por Sega en 1986. Es un tirador horizontal, en el cual el jugador controla una nave espacial que debe destruir las 8 fortalezas del Imperio Gulbas y varios enemigos diferentes. A pesar de las limitaciones de la consola, hay 30 "actos", y cada "acto" tiene un fondo diferente y hay numerosos potenciadores disponibles, que lo diferencian de la mayoría de los otros shooters SG-1000 en el momento.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Gulkave est un shoot'em up sur SG-1000 développé par Compile et publié par Sega en 1986. Il s'agit d'un jeu de tir horizontal, dans lequel le joueur contrôle un vaisseau spatial qui doit détruire les 8 forteresses de l'Empire Gulbas et divers ennemis. Malgré les limites de la console, il y a 30 "actes", et chaque "acte" a un fond différent et en plus de nombreux powerups sont disponibles, ce qui le distingue de la plupart des autres jeux de tirs de la SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Gulkave</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Guzzler">
		<id>65722A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Guzzler</title>
	<synopsis>Guzzler is an arcade game developed by Tehkan. It was ported to the SG-1000 by Tsukuda Original and given Othello Multivision branding. To this day the SG-1000 version stands as the only home port of Guzzler.

You play as a character who needs to absorb water to put out fires dotted around a maze. The fires also spawn fire-based enemies which can be defeated in a similar fashion. You can only store up to three shots at one time.

Compared to other SG-1000 games, Guzzler shows some very poor production values. It thrusts you into gameplay without warning (which can result in cheap deaths) and it has a broken pause feature, which although appears to work, will unpause the game after a few seconds. There are only three maps and far fewer enemies than in the arcade version and it is also a much louder game, as the SG-1000 omits a high pitched squeak every time you make a step.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Juegas como un personaje que necesita absorber agua para apagar incendios diseminados por un laberinto. Los incendios también generan enemigos basados ??en fuego que pueden ser derrotados de manera similar. Solo puedes almacenar hasta tres disparos a la vez.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Guzzler est un jeu d'arcade développé par Tehkan. Il a été porté à la SG-1000 par Tsukuda Original et a donné la marque Othello Multivision. Jusqu'à ce jour, Guzzler est uniquement sorti SG-1000. Vous jouez en tant que personnage qui a besoin d'absorber l'eau pour éteindre les feux parsemés autour d'un labyrinthe. Les feux engendrent également des ennemis à feu qui peuvent être vaincus de la même manière. Vous ne pouvez stocker que jusqu'à trois prises en même temps.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="H.e.r.o.">
		<id>65723A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>H.E.R.O.</title>
	<synopsis>H.E.R.O. is an action game originally developed and published by Activision. Sega brought it to the SG-1000 in Japan.

The objective of the game is to rescue trapped miners in a volcano. 1 drops a stick of dynamite to blow up barriers and kill enemies. 2 shoots a laser-like thing, which you can use to kill enemies. At the bottom of the screen, there is a Power meter showing you how much energy you have left; energy goes down as time goes on. Simply touch a miner to rescue him and move on to the next level.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Desesperados mineros atrapados! ¿Serán estos túneles sus tumbas? Rod Hero es su última esperanza! Su paquete de Propulsión lo impulsa hacia los pozos de la mina, ¡y al peligro!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>L'objectif du jeu est de sauver les mineurs piégés dans un volcan. 1: lancer des bâtons de dynamite pour faire sauter les barrières et tuer les ennemis. 2: tire un genre de rayon laser, que vous pouvez aussi utiliser pour tuer les ennemis. Au bas de l'écran, il y a un barre qui vous montre combien d'énergie il vous reste; L'énergie diminue avec le temps. Il suffit de toucher un mineur pour le sauver et passer au niveau suivant.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>H.E.R.O.</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Hang-on 2">
		<id>65724A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Hang-On II</title>
	<synopsis>Hang-On II is an SG-1000 sequel to the critically acclaimed Hang-On.

Despite the name, the game is meant as a direct sequel to the Mark III version of Hang-On, and is virtually identical to that game. The only difference is downgraded graphics and the addition of music from the arcade version. Meanwhile, Super Hang-On is the direct sequel to the arcade game.

It is compatible with the BH-400 bike handle controller, and would be the only SG-1000 game designed for it (though the peripheral is compatible with the Sega Master System and Sega Mega Drive).</synopsis>
	<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Hang-On II es una secuela SG-1000 del Hang-On aclamado por la crítica.nnnnA pesar del nombre, el juego es una secuela directa de la versión Mark III de Hang-On, y es prácticamente idéntica a ese juego. La única diferencia son los gráficos degradados y la adición de música de la versión arcade. Mientras tanto, Super Hang-On es la continuación directa del juego de arcade.nnnnEs compatible con el controlador de asa de bicicleta BH-400 y sería el único juego SG-1000 diseñado para ello (aunque el periférico es compatible con Sega Master System y Sega Mega Drive).</synopsis>
	<genre>Carreras, Conducción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Course, Conduite</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Rennen, Fahren</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Home Basic">
		<id>65775A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Home Basic</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Mitec</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Home Mahjong">
		<id>65725A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Home Mahjong</title>
	<synopsis>Home Mahjong is a mahjong game for the SG-1000.

The game was sold with a plastic screen that sticks to the TV during a 2 player game to hide the other players tiles from view.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Mahjong,Asiatic board game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Home Mahjong es un juego de mahjong para SG-1000. El juego se vendió con una pantalla de plástico que se pega al televisor para ocultar las fichas de los otros jugadores en el modo de juego de 2 jugadores.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas,Mahjong,Juegos de mesa asiático</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Home Mahjong est un jeu de mahjong pour le SG-1000. Le jeu a été vendu avec un écran en plastique qui se colle à la télévision lors d'une partie à 2 joueurs pour cacher au autres la vue des tuiles.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Mahjong,Jeu de societe asiatique</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle,Mahjong,Asiatische Brettspiele</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Quebra-cabeças,Mahjong,Jogo de tabuleiro Asiático</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Home Mahjong</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Hustle Chumy">
		<id>65726A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Hustle Chumy</title>
	<synopsis>Hustle Chumy is an SG-1000 and MSX game developed by Compile and released in 1984.

In Hustle Chumy players control a mouse named Chumy who needs to collect apples (and other food) in a sewer, avoiding other critters as he goes. As Chumy eats more food, his speed decreases, but his fireballs are given a longer range. Levels have varying layouts.

There are several types of enemies in the game, most of which can be defeated with fireballs.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>En Hustle Chumy, los jugadores controlan a un ratón llamado Chumy que necesita recolectar manzanas (y otros alimentos) en una alcantarilla, evitando otras criaturas a medida que avanza. A medida que Chumy come más comida, su velocidad disminuye, pero sus bolas de fuego reciben un rango más largo. Los niveles tienen diferentes diseños.nnnnHay varios tipos de enemigos en el juego, la mayoría de los cuales pueden ser derrotados con bolas de fuego.nnnnMurciélagos: los murciélagos vuelan sobre Chumy.nnMecha-Dinos: los Mecha-Dinos son indestructibles, aunque Chumy puede ralentizarlos con bolas de fuego.nnGators: los cocodrilos generalmente duermen en un lugar, pero a veces se mueven lentamente.nnGatos: los gatos pueden saltar como Chumy.nnNinjas: los ninjas deben ser golpeados con tres bolas de fuego para ser derrotados.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Dans Hustle Chumy, les joueurs contrôlent une souris nommée Chumy qui a besoin de ramasser des pommes (et autres aliments) dans un égout, en évitant d'autres créatures. Comme Chumy mange plus de nourriture, sa vitesse diminue, mais ses boules de feu ont une plus longue portée. Les niveaux ont des dispositions différentes. Il existe plusieurs types d'ennemis dans le jeu, dont la plupart peuvent être vaincus avec des boules de feu.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Hyper Sports">
		<id>65727A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Hyper Sports</title>
	<synopsis>Hyper Sports is a sports game developed by Konami and released for the SG-1000 in 1985 (following a 1984 MSX launch). The game has the player compete through a number of olympic events.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Hyper Sports es un juego deportivo competitivo que presenta siete eventos comúnmente vistos en los Juegos Olímpicos. Fue un juego de conexión para los Juegos Olímpicos de verano de 1984 en Los Ángeles, y una secuela de Track &amp; Field anterior de Konami. Al igual que con Track &amp; Field, el jugador tiene que pasar cada uno de los eventos del juego para pasar al siguiente.nnnnEl jugador, como varios atletas, participa en los siguientes siete eventos. Para progresar de uno a otro, el jugador debe aprobar un puntaje mínimo de "calificación" para cada evento. Por lo general, los eventos implican presionar los botones lo más rápido posible, o algún tiempo muy específico.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Hyper Sports est un jeu de sport développé par Konami et sorti pour le SG-1000 en 1985. Le jeu consiste à concourir à un certain nombre d'événements olympiques.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Kagaku">
		<id>102226</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Kagaku</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Kagaku (Gensokigou Master) (traducción: Chemistry (Chemical Symbols Master)) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para SC-3000 (y SG-1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100). Este se enfoca en la Tabla Periódica.</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Kagaku (Gensokigou Master)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="King's Valley">
		<id>102099</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>King's Valley</title>
	<synopsis>King's Valley for the SG-1000 released in Taiwan by Aaronix. This game requires a special adapter released by DahJee that extend the SG-1000 memory to 8 KB (read more about the DahJee adapter for SG-1000). Else it would work on a normal Asian Master System. King's Valley is pretty much in the vein of pre-scrolling item collecting arcade game, Think Lode Runner meet Pac-Man in Egyptian tomb adventure theme. A very game by Konami.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Antiguo Egipto en la época de los faraones, cuando la realeza solía enterrar incontables joyas misteriosas con ellos en sus tumbas. ¡Un viaje de aventura arqueológica al Valle del Rey (Valle de los Faraones) en busca de misteriosas joyas ocultas en las Tumbas Reales!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Aaronix</developer>
		<publisher>DahJee</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Knightmare">
		<id>102100</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Knightmare</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>La Diosa Afrodita ha sido capturada por el Rey del Inframundo y se lleva a cabo en su Castillo de la Pesadilla. Profundamente enamorada de ella, la guerrera Popolon se embarca en una misión para rescatarla. Sin embargo, el Castillo está oculto, y Popolon está plagado de pesadillas de miles de monstruos que atormentan su amor mientras lo buscan ciegamente.nnnnEntonces, una noche, la Diosa Hera le habla, le muestra un camino hacia su objetivo más allá de las laderas del Monte Atos, y le revela el poder de las joyas y cristales mágicos. Con un espíritu renovado, Popolon se dirige hacia el Castillo, para enfrentar los horrores internos.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Jumbo</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Legend of Kage, The">
		<id>102101</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Legend of Kage, The</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Este clásico juego de acción ninja apareció por primera vez en salas recreativas en 1985 y se hizo popular instantáneamente. Como el ninja de Iga llamado "Kage", los jugadores se embarcan en una aventura llena de acción a medida que avanzan hacia un castillo mágico donde la princesa "Kiri" es mantenida cautiva por "Yohshirou Yukikusa". Para mantenerse con vida, los jugadores se mueven vertical y horizontalmente a través de los entornos de bosques y castillos y ejecutan saltos masivos, todo mientras usan cuchillos de estrella arrojadiza y una espada para derrotar hordas de enemigos.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>DahJee</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Lode Runner">
		<id>65729A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Lode Runner</title>
	<synopsis>In this game, the player is required to repeatedly "think" and "take action" to go through and clear the maze scenes by solving their mysterious riddles while averting the enemy's guards who are relentlessly in pursuit of him. After collecting all of the gold chests, you must come up with fresh new ideas in order to successfully challenge the next level scene. Although your experience gained from the previous play action will help you overcome some of the future maze scenes, you still have to constantly be on the alert. You can also enjoy creating your own games by using the keyboard. This is an intriguing game which requires intellectual depth to skillfully maneuver the unknown maze structures that consecutively develop one after another.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>En este juego, se requiere que el jugador "piense" y "actúe" repetidamente para atravesar y borrar las escenas del laberinto resolviendo sus misteriosos acertijos mientras evita a los guardias enemigos que lo persiguen implacablemente. Después de recolectar todos los cofres de oro, debes inventar nuevas ideas para desafiar con éxito la escena del siguiente nivel. Aunque la experiencia adquirida con la acción de juego anterior te ayudará a superar algunas de las futuras escenas de laberintos, todavía tienes que estar constantemente alerta. También puedes disfrutar creando tus propios juegos usando el teclado. Este es un juego intrigante que requiere profundidad intelectual para maniobrar hábilmente las estructuras de laberinto desconocidas que se desarrollan consecutivamente una tras otra.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>A l'origine, les jeux vidéo étaient une simple source d'amusement, puis, avec le temps et leur évolution, leurs créateurs leur ont conféré une capacité à entraîner le joueur dans un monde imaginaire. Dans la majeure partie des cas, donc, on y joue pour se détendre ou s'évader. Certains jeux ont toutefois une aura intellectuelle indéfinissable qui les rend populaires auprès des amateurs d'amusement cérébral, ceux-là même qui préfèrent jouer aux échecs ou au Reversi qu'aux jeux d'action ou d'aventure, peu friands de sensations audiovisuelles mais toujours prêts au voyage dès que se présente un concept malin, innovant et porteur de possibilités ludiques infinies sur une base en apparence simple.

Lode Runner fait partie de ce genre. Avec des graphismes simplistes, peu ou pas de son, un principe compréhensible en un instant, ce jeu est à ce point riche en situations, pièges et tactiques de toutes sortes qu'on le croirait en y jouant issu de quelque recherche scientifique. Pourtant, à la différence de certains titres "expérimentaux" parmi lesquels Tetris fait figure de vedette incontestée, Lode Runner procure les vraies sensations d'un jeu d'action en plus de nous surprendre et nous faire découvrir sa richesse au fil de ses quelques 150 niveaux. Il est donc logique que ce classique apparu en 1983 ait inspiré nombre de clones, tous plus beaux et funs que l'original, mais dont aucun n'a égalé l'impact.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Magical Kid Wiz">
		<id>102102</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Magical Kid Wiz</title>
	<synopsis>Magical Kid Wiz for the SG-1000 released in Taiwan on a beautiful green cartridge. Developed in 1986 by Sony for the MSX, this is among the MSX games that Aaronix ported to the SG-1000 for the Taiwanese market.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Magical Kid Wiz para la videoconsola SG-1000 fue lanzado en Taiwán en un hermoso cartucho verde. Desarrollado en 1986 por Sony para MSX, es uno de los juegos de MSX que Aaronix convirtió a SG-1000 para el mercado taiwanés.

Encarnas a un pequeño mago dotado de un bastón mágico con el que podrás arrojar pequeñas bolas de fuego para ir al rescate de una hermosa princesa.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sony</developer>
		<publisher>Aaronix</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Mahjong">
		<id>65730A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Mahjong</title>
	<synopsis>This is the first mahjong game released for the SG-1000, developed and published by Sega in 1983. Unlike later mahjong games released for the system, this game is for one player only.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Mahjong,Asiatic board game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Este es el primer juego de mahjong lanzado para el SG-1000, desarrollado y publicado por Sega en 1983. A diferencia de los juegos posteriores de mahjong lanzados para el sistema, este juego es solo para un jugador.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas,Mahjong,Juegos de mesa asiático</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Mahjong ou Sega Mahjong est un jeu de mahjong pour le SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Mahjong,Jeu de societe asiatique</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle,Mahjong,Asiatische Brettspiele</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Quebra-cabeças,Mahjong,Jogo de tabuleiro Asiático</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Sega Mahjong</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Monaco Gp">
		<id>65732A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Monaco GP</title>
	<synopsis>A red formula car travelling at high speed through the streets, speeding up, jumping, maneuvering to the right and left to avoid the cars obstructing the way and reckless cars coming close to your machine, ........ Be on the lookout for an ambulance suddenly passing by ......... And keep an eye out for the signposts!! Thrill-packed challenges such as the slip zones, dangerous construction sites as well as sharp curves and narrow bay bridges also appear. When in the tunnel, the headlights of your car are the only thing you can rely upon. After improving your skill by going through the beginner's level 1, you can move on to the more difficult high levels 2 and 3.</synopsis>
	<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Un fórmula rojo que viaja a alta velocidad por las calles, se acelera, salta, maniobra a la derecha e izquierda para evitar que los autos obstruyan el camino y los autos imprudentes que se acercan a su máquina ........ Esté en el busque una ambulancia que pase de repente ......... ¡Y esté atento a las señales! También se presentan retos emocionantes como las zonas de deslizamiento, los sitios de construcción peligrosos, así como las curvas pronunciadas y los puentes estrechos de la bahía. Cuando está en el túnel, los faros de su automóvil son lo único en lo que puede confiar. Después de mejorar tu habilidad pasando por el nivel 1 de principiante, puedes pasar a los niveles altos más difíciles 2 y 3.</synopsis>
	<genre>Carreras, Conducción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Monaco GP est un jeu d'arcade de 1979 créé par Sega. Le jeu est très simple - tout ce que le joueur doit faire, c'est éviter les voitures et les obstacles sur une piste. Il peut accélérer et freiner et deux joueurs peuvent jouer en même temps.

Le jeu a seulement été porté à la Sega SG-1000 en 1983.</synopsis>
	<genre>Course, Conduite</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Rennen, Fahren</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Music">
		<id>102227</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Music</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>"Cualquiera puede componer fácilmente música en la pantalla del televisor. Además, puede ingresar las notas de su música favorita usando el TECLADO y ¡disfrute de su SC-3000!nnnnUna de las funciones más efectivas del software "MUSIC" es el sonido de la computadora de acordes de agudos.nnnnLos bellos tonos con un rango de 4 octavas producidos realmente llaman la atención.nnnnPuedes componer y organizar música de pop a clásica a tu gusto y disfrutar realmente de la sensación de ser cantante y compositor ".</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Music</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Mitec</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="N-sub">
		<id>65735A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>N-Sub</title>
	<synopsis>A big battle develops on a cobalt blue sea. Fire a torpedo when you find the enemy's ships. Avoid the destroyer's attack by using your missiles, torpedoes and depth bombs. Counterattack and sink the enemy's ships. The enemy attack becomes more intense with each new round!</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Una gran batalla se desarrolla en un mar azul cobalto. Dispara un torpedo cuando encuentres las naves enemigas. Evite el ataque del destructor mediante el uso de misiles, torpedos y bombas de profundidad. Contraatacar y hundir las naves del enemigo. ¡El ataque enemigo se vuelve más intenso con cada nueva ronda!</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>N-Sub est un jeu d'arcade sorti par Sega en 1980. Il est semblable à l'Heli Fire de Nintendo, mais actuellement personne n'est sûr qui est venu en premier. Il est également très similaire à Deep Scan, sauf plutôt que de contrôler un bateau tirant sur des sous-marins, vous êtes un sous-marin tirant sur des bateaux (et d'autres sous-marins). Comme il s'agissait d'un jeu VIC Dual, il était souvent présent avec un autre jeu en salle d'arcade.

Il a été porté à la SG-1000 en 1983, bien que comme avec tous les jeux SG-1000, il a seulement vu le jour dans les régions du Japon et en Europe.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>N-Sub</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Nihonshi Nenpyou">
		<id>102228</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Nihonshi Nenpyou</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Nihonshi Nenpyou (traducción: Japanese History Chronology) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para SC-3000 (y SG-1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100). Este se enfoca en la historia japonesa.</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Nihonshi Nenpyou</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Ninja Princess">
		<id>65734A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Ninja Princess</title>
	<synopsis>Ninja Princess known as Sega Ninja in the west, is a Sega System 1 arcade game by Sega. It is a top-down shooter/action game, in which you play as a princess disguised as a ninja who is attempting to stop the evil tyrant Gyokuro.

The game was ported to the SG-1000 in 1986 exclusively for Japan, with an MSX port following shortly afterwards. It was also brought to the Sega Master System as The Ninja, however The Ninja makes several adjustments to the story and characters, as well as updating the gameplay.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Ninja Princess conocida como Sega Ninja en el oeste, es un juego de arcade Sega System 1 de Sega. Es un juego de disparos / acción de arriba hacia abajo, en el que juegas como una princesa disfrazada de ninja que intenta detener al malvado tirano Gyokuro.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Ninja Princess, connue sous le nom de Sega Ninja à l'ouest, est un jeu d'arcade Sega System 1 de Sega. Il s'agit d'un jeu de tir / action de haut en bas, dans lequel vous jouez avec une princesse déguisée en ninja qui essaie d'arrêter le tyran Gyokuro.

Le jeu a été porté à la SG-1000 en 1986 exclusivement pour le Japon, avec un port MSX qui a suivi peu de temps après. Il a également été porté au Sega Master System.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Ninja Princess</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Okamoto Ayako No Match Play Golf">
		<id>65779A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Okamoto Ayako no Match Play Golf</title>
	<synopsis>Okamoto Ayako no Match Play Golf is a golf game for the Othello Multivision, released by Tsukuda Original. It is also compatible with the Sega SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sports,Sports / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Okamoto Ayako no Match Play Golf es un juego de golf para Othello Multivision, lanzado por Tsukuda Original. También es compatible con la Sega SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Deportes,Deportes / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Okamoto Ayako no Match Play Golf est un jeu de golf pour la Othello Multivision, publié par Tsukuda Original. Il est également compatible avec la Sega SG-1000.</synopsis>
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Sport,Sport / Golf</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Esporte,Esporte / Golfe</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Orguss">
		<id>65737A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Orguss</title>
	<synopsis>Orguss is a shoot-'em-up game developed and published by Sega for the SG-1000. In the game, the player takes control of a robot which can transform into a starship. It is based on the science fiction anime series Super Dimension Century Orguss.

The player can swap between robot and starship modes freely, though both come with their own set advantages and disadvantages. In robot mode, you are able to destroy ground targets and have greater freedom across the screen at the expense of being a bigger target for enemies. You can shoot rapidfire, but move slower. In starship mode you cannot destroy ground targets, but are less likely to be destroyed thanks to the smaller surface area of the ship.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>En el juego, el jugador toma el control de un robot que puede transformarse en una nave estelar. Está basado en la serie de anime de ciencia ficción Super Dimension Century Orguss.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Orguss est un shoot-'em-up développé et publié par Sega pour le SG-1000. Dans le jeu, le joueur prend le contrôle d'un robot qui peut se transformer en un vaisseau spatial. Il est basé sur la série d'anime de science-fiction Super Dimension Century Orguss.

Le joueur peut échanger librement entre le robot et le vaisseau spatial, bien que les deux viennent avec leurs propres avantages et inconvénients. En mode robot, vous êtes en mesure de détruire les cibles au sol et d'avoir une plus grande liberté à travers l'écran au détriment d'être une cible plus grande pour les ennemis. Vous pouvez tirer repidement, mais bouger plus lentement. En mode vaisseau, vous ne pouvez pas détruire les cibles terrestres, mais vous etes moins susceptibles d'être détruit étant une cible plus petite.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Othello">
		<id>65738A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Othello</title>
	<synopsis>Othello is an SG-1000 video game based on the board game Othello.

Two versions of Othello exist for the SG-1000. The first version, released in 1983, was built into the Othello Multivision (which is where the system gets its name from). Sega would later re-release this game in cartridge form in 1985, offering significant graphical and AI improvements over Tsukuda Original's version.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Asiatic board game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Othello (? ? ?) es un videojuego SG-1000 basado en el juego de mesa Othello.

Existen dos versiones de Othello para el SG-1000. La primera versión, lanzada en 1983, fue incorporada en Othello Multivision (que es de donde toma su nombre el sistema). Más tarde, Sega volvería a lanzar este juego en forma de cartucho en 1985, ofreciendo importantes mejoras gráficas y de IA sobre la versión de Tsukuda Original.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas,Juegos de mesa asiático</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Othello est un jeu vidéo SG-1000 basé sur le jeu de société Othello.

Deux versions d'Othello existent pour le SG-1000. La première version, sortie en 1983, a été intégrée dans la Multivision Othello (d'où le système tira son nom). Sega republiera plus tard ce jeu sous forme de cartouche en 1985, offrant des améliorations graphiques significatives et une intelligence artificiel plus poussée.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Jeu de societe asiatique</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle,Asiatische Brettspiele</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Quebra-cabeças,Jogo de tabuleiro Asiático</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Othello</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Pacar">
		<id>65739A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Pacar</title>
	<synopsis>PACAR, a mischievous car, runs through the 3D routes freely advancing and reversing at fast and slow speeds. Try to delete all the dots on the screen while avoiding the 2 kinds of enemy cars. When you pass through the special dots, PACAR becomes more and more invincible as it increases its power and will be free from damage even when it crashes into the enemy car. Keep up the torrid pace and destroy as many of the enemy cars as possible!</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>PACAR, un coche travieso, recorre las rutas 3D avanzando y retrocediendo libremente a velocidades rápidas y lentas. Intenta eliminar todos los puntos en la pantalla mientras evitas los 2 tipos de coches enemigos. Cuando pasas por los puntos especiales, PACAR se vuelve cada vez más invencible a medida que aumenta su poder y quedará libre de daños incluso cuando se estrelle contra el vehículo enemigo. ¡Mantén el ritmo tórrido y destruye la mayor cantidad de autos enemigos posible!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Pacar est un jeu SG-1000 initialement publié en 1983. Il est essentiellement un mélange entre deux jeux Namco; Pac-Man et Rallye X.

C'est la suite de Head-On, qui a été publié un an avant Puck-Man. Cependant, Pacar est plus  un clone de Puck-Man qu'une vraie suite de Head-On</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Pachinko">
		<id>65740A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Pachinko</title>
	<synopsis>Pachinko is an SG-1000 game developed and published by Sega in 1983. It is, as the name suggests, a video game version of Pachinko, a popular game in Japan. The game did not see an international release.

Pachinko is an extremely rare game for the SG-1000. Soon after release, it was recalled from sale due to a game-breaking bug (need to verify) and very few copies remain in the hands of collectors. This is probably the very first instance of a recall in Sega's history (?).</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Pachinko es un juego SG-1000 desarrollado y publicado por Sega en 1983. Es, como su nombre indica, una versión de videojuego de Pachinko, un popular juego en Japón. El juego no vio un lanzamiento internacional.

Pachinko es un juego extremadamente raro para el SG-1000. Poco después de su lanzamiento, fue retirado de la venta debido a un error que rompe el juego (necesidad de verificar) y muy pocas copias quedan en manos de los coleccionistas. Esta es probablemente la primera instancia de un retiro en la historia de Sega (?).

A partir de 2013, una subasta reciente del juego en Yahoo Japón se ganó por ¥ 113,500, pero se sabe que se vende al alza desde ¥ 200,000.

El error fue corregido y el juego fue relanzado unas semanas más tarde como una "secuela", Pachinko II, que es mucho más común.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Pachinko est un jeu SG-1000 développé et publié par Sega en 1983. Il est, comme son nom l'indique, une version de jeu vidéo de Pachinko, un jeu populaire au Japon. Le jeu n'a pas vu  le jour hors du Japon.

Pachinko est un jeu extrêmement rare pour le SG-1000. Peu de temps après la sortie, il a été rappelé de la vente en raison d'un bug game-breaking (besoin de vérifier) et très peu d'exemplaires restent dans les mains des collectionneurs. C'est probablement la toute première instance d'un rappel de jeu dans l'histoire de Sega.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Quebra-cabeças,Cassino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Pachinko</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Pachinko 2">
		<id>65741A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Pachinko II</title>
	<synopsis>Pachinko II is the bug fixed version of Pachinko and a "sequel", which was released for the SG-1000 in 1984.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Pachinko II es la secuela de Pachinko, y fue lanzado para el SG-1000 en 1984.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle,Casino</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Quebra-cabeças,Cassino</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Pippols">
		<id>140812</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Pippols</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Pippols es un juego de acción de Konami. La versión MSX del juego fue llevada al SG-1000 en Taiwán. Requiere que se ejecute el adaptador de 8kB RAM.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Jumbo</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Pitfall 2 - The Lost Caverns">
		<id>65742A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Pitfall II - The Lost Caverns</title>
	<synopsis>Pitfall II: The Lost Caverns is the sequel to Pitfall and was released for a variety of systems during the mid-1980s including the SG-1000 in 1985. Gameplay is similar to the original game, but the levels are more maze-like.

Sega's version of Pitfall II was tweaked significantly from its western counterparts released for the Atari 2600, ColecoVision etc. The gameplay is largely the same, but there are many additions. These include a Lives system, mine-carts, balloons, and a final Demon boss. The SG-1000 version is directly inspired by the arcade game, and though cannot match the same level of graphical quality, it is arguably the nicest looking home port of the game.</synopsis>
	<genre>Platform</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Aquí estoy, Pitfall Harry, cayendo en picado hacia el oscuro trueno del agua corriendo debajo ... y pensando en la noche en que llamó David Crane. "Espero que estés bien descansado", había dicho. Demasiado descansado, dije. Estaba listo para la acción. Me preguntó si había escuchado historias sobre las legendarias cavernas perdidas de Machu Picchu en Perú. O de un rugiente, afluente subterráneo inexplorado del río Urubamba repleto de cascadas y anguilas eléctricas mortales. "Sí, he dicho. Me preguntó si conocía al infame y maldito Raj Diamond. O del robo reciente de lingotes de oro del depósito de lingotes de oro de EE. UU. En Fort Knox. ¿Y si hubiera oído hablar de murciélagos vampiros? ¿Ranas venenosas? Escorpiones Albino? ¿El temido cóndor andino? "Sí, he dicho. ¿Y aún podría correr? ¿Escalada? ¿Saltar? ¿Podría ... nadar? "Si si SI SI." "Bien", dijo Crane. "¿Entonces lo harás?" "Por supuesto", dije. Si tan solo hubiera sabido ..</synopsis>
	<genre>Plataforma</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Plateforme</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Plattform</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Pitfall II : The Lost Caverns</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Activision</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Pop Flamer">
		<id>65743A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Pop Flamer</title>
	<synopsis>"POP FLAMER" is a mouse which operates a flamethrower.nnYou as a player attempt to break balloons and supply fuel for the flamethrower while eliminating the 3 kinds of MONSTERS and the obstacle FROG which is obstructing the routes. However, be carefuk of the tranquizing beam from the "HARADON". When you are exposed to this beam, you will not be able to move temporality! When the POP  FLAMER takes a "power-up drink", it ohanges into a "SUPER MOUSE" and you can score high points by swallowing the nearby MONSTERS in one gulp!!</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>"POP FLAMER" es un ratón que maneja un lanzallamas.nnTú, como jugador, intenta romper globos y suministrar combustible para el lanzallamas mientras elimina los 3 tipos de MONSTRUOS y el obstáculo RANA que está obstruyendo las rutas. Sin embargo, sea cuidadoso con el haz tranquilizador del "HARADON". Cuando estés expuesto a este rayo, ¡no podrás mover la temporalidad! Cuando el POP FLAMER toma una "bebida de encendido", se transforma en un "SUPER MOUSE" y usted puede obtener puntos altos tragando los MONSTRUOS cercanos de un trago !!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Pop Flamer est un jeu d'arcade développé par Jaleco en 1982, et a été porté sur la SG-1000 en 1983 par Sega. Dans le jeu, le joueur contrôle une souris armée d'un lance-flammes qui doit éclater des ballons tout en évitant les ennemis.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Jaleco</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Q*bert">
		<id>65744A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Q*bert</title>
	<synopsis>Q*bert is an arcade game by Gottlieb. It was ported to the SG-1000 by Tsukuda Original, who marketed it for their Othello Multivision console.

The objective of the game is to turn all the cubes on screen to a desired colour by moving Q*bert on top of them. Q*bert can only move in diagonals, and the player needs to be careful not to either send Q*bert off the edge or have him collide with enemies/obstacles. Occasionally cylindrical platforms appear on the edge of the screen, which when jumped on, will take Q*bert to the top.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Hop Q*bert sube y baja los escalones de una pirámide "tridimensional", cambiando el color de cada paso a medida que aterriza. Completa toda la pirámide y Q*bert se mueve a una pirámide más desafiante. ¡Pero cuidado! Las astutas criaturas de arcade están aquí también, y buscan Q*bert. Salte rápidamente del peligro - o remonte hasta la seguridad en un disco volador. Pero mira dónde te mueves Q*bert. ¡Un salto de la pirámide y se perderá en el espacio!</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Q * bert est un jeu d'arcade de Gottlieb. Il a été porté pour la SG-1000 par Tsukuda Original, qui l'a commercialisé pour sa console Othello Multivision.

L'objectif du jeu est de transformer tous les cubes sur l'écran à une couleur désirée en déplaçant Q * bert au-dessus d'eux. Q * bert ne peut se déplacer que dans les diagonales, et le joueur doit être prudent de ne pas envoyer Q * bert hors de la pyramide ou de lui faire heurter les ennemis / obstacles. Parfois, des plates-formes cylindriques apparaissent sur le bord de l'écran, qui, lorsqu'ils sont emprunté, ramènera Q * bert au sommet.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Q*bert</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Rally-x">
		<id>102103</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Rally-x</title>
	<synopsis>Rally-X is a 1980 arcade game by Namco which was brought to the MSX in 1984. It was subsequently ported to the SG-1000 in Taiwan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Rally-X es un juego de arcade de 1980 de Namco que fue llevado al MSX en 1984. Posteriormente fue trasladado al SG-1000 en Taiwán.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>DahJee</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Road Fighter">
		<id>102104</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Road Fighter</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Road Fighter es un juego de carreras desarrollado por Konami. Jumbo llevó la versión MSX del juego al SG-1000 en Taiwán. Se desconoce si tenían una licencia para hacerlo. Más tarde se lanzó en Corea del Sur como una tarjeta para el Sistema Maestro de Sega.</synopsis>
	<genre>Carreras, Conducción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Course, Conduite</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Rennen, Fahren</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Jumbo</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Rock N' Bolt">
		<id>65745A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Rock n' Bolt</title>
	<synopsis>Before you awaits the construction world's most complicated, confused mess of mind-boggling blueprints, bolts, beams and girders.nnYou and you alone will have to figure it all out and put it all together. And you don't have all day.nnIt's a dazzling, dizzying, incredibly exciting high-rise challenge. All 100 floors of it.nnYou'll spin, leap and dance your way from beam to beam, puzzle to puzzle. Earn bonus wages and hire extra workers.nnSo, grab your hat and strap on your boots. You're about to discover how hot music and high energy can help fill a very, very tall order.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Antes de que esperes la confusión más complicada y confusa del mundo de la construcción de planos, pernos, vigas y vigas alucinantes.nnTú y solo tú tendrás que resolverlo todo y ponerlo todo junto. Y no tienes todo el día.nnEs un reto de gran altura deslumbrante, vertiginoso e increíblemente emocionante. Todos los 100 pisos de ella.nnTú girarás, saltarás y bailarás de haz en haz, de rompecabezas en rompecabezas. Gana sueldos extra y contrata trabajadores adicionales.nnEntonces, coge tu sombrero y ponte las botas. Estás a punto de descubrir cómo la música caliente y la alta energía pueden ayudar a llenar un orden muy, muy alto.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Rock n 'Bolt est un jeu de réflexion développé par Activision, publié pour un certain nombre d'ordinateurs personnels et de consoles, y compris le SG-1000 en 1985. Il suit Louie le constructeur qui doit boulonner les plates-formes mobiles à leur emplacement correct dans un délai fixé.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Activision</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Safari Hunting">
		<id>65747A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Safari Hunting</title>
	<synopsis>Go deep into the jungle and hunt fierce animals. Your weapon is a mighty tranquilizer gun. Capture the sleeping snakes, gorillas, lions and elephants by putting them in a cage. Capture as many animals as possible, while considering the effective time of the tranquilizer and the available quantity of fuel.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Sumérgete en la jungla y caza animales feroces. Tu arma es una poderosa arma tranquilizadora. Capture las serpientes dormidas, los gorilas, los leones y los elefantes colocándolos en una jaula. Capture tantos animales como sea posible, mientras considera el tiempo efectivo del tranquilizante y la cantidad de combustible disponible.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Le jeu a été apporté au SG-1000 en 1983 avec le nom de Safari Hunting mais c'est en fait Tranquillizer Gun qui est un jeu d'arcade de 1980 développé par Sega pour le matériel VIC Dual. Vous êtes un chasseur, qui doit faire son chemin autour d'un labyrinthe, tirer sur des animaux et traîner leurs corps jus-qu'à son camion.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Safari Race">
		<id>65748A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Safari Race</title>
	<synopsis>On the vast savanna plain, the SAFARI RACE has just gotten underway. Keep running at full speed, passing other cars while avoiding various wild animals that cross the road. Drive fast, ever onward, taking into consideration the limited time, fuel consumption and dangerous sharp curves. Pass through the checkpoints. Run your car at full throttle towards the goal with the engine operating at its maximum capacity.</synopsis>
	<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>En la vasta llanura de sabana, la SAFARI RACE acaba de ponerse en marcha. Sigue corriendo a toda velocidad, pasando por otros vehículos mientras evitas varios animales salvajes que cruzan la calle. Conduzca rápido, siempre hacia adelante, teniendo en cuenta el tiempo limitado, el consumo de combustible y las curvas peligrosas. Pase por los puntos de control. Haga funcionar su automóvil a máxima aceleración hacia la meta con el motor funcionando a su capacidad máxima.</synopsis>
	<genre>Carreras, Conducción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Safari Race est un jeu de course pour le SG-1000, développé et publié par Sega en 1984. Le joueur doit conduire à travers diverses «sections», en évitant la faune et d'autres voitures tout en s'assurant de ne pas manquer de carburant.

Le jeu est remarquable pour l'utilisation de voitures sous licence, potentiellement le premier jeu vidéo à le faire. Le joueur contrôle une Lancia Stratos HF, et d'après la boîte, certaines des voitures rivales sont des Audi Quattros.</synopsis>
	<genre>Course, Conduite</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Rennen, Fahren</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Sannin Mahjong">
		<id>65780A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>San-nin Mahjong</title>
	<synopsis>Sannin Mahjong is a mahjong game for the SG-1000. It is sometimes also known as 3-nin Mahjong, meaning three player mahjong. This number of players is not possible in either of Sega's own versions of the game, Mahjong and Home Mahjong.</synopsis>
	<genre>Mahjong,Asiatic board game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Sannin Mahjong es un juego de mahjong para el SG-1000. A veces también se lo conoce como 3-nin Mahjong, que significa mahjong de tres jugadores. Esta cantidad de jugadores no es posible en ninguna de las versiones propias de Sega, Mahjong y Home Mahjong.</synopsis>
	<genre>Mahjong,Juegos de mesa asiático</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Sannin Mahjong est un jeu de mahjong pour le SG-1000. Il est parfois aussi connu comme 3-nin Mahjong, ce qui signifie trois joueurs mahjong. Ce nombre de joueurs n'est pas possible dans les deux versions de Sega, Mahjong et Home Mahjong.</synopsis>
	<genre>Mahjong,Jeu de societe asiatique</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Mahjong,Asiatische Brettspiele</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Mahjong,Jogo de tabuleiro Asiático</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="3">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Sega Flipper">
		<id>65749A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Sega Flipper</title>
	<synopsis>A catchy rhythmical flipper sound accompanies this computer pinball video game. Featuring a D.T. (drop target) that enables you to earn bonus points and a K.H. (kicker hole) that entitles you to earn bonus points X a multiplication rate! Take good aim, and shoot away! Here's wishing you success as you merrily flip your way around the playfield in search of the proverbial "high score".</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Un sonido de aleta rítmica pegadizo acompaña este videojuego de pinball de la computadora. Con un D.T. (drop target) que te permite ganar puntos de bonificación y un K.H. (kicker hole) que le da derecho a ganar puntos de bonificación X una tasa de multiplicación! Apunta bien, ¡y dispara! Aquí te deseo éxitos mientras giras alegremente por el campo de juego en busca de la proverbial "puntuación más alta".</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Sega Flipper est un jeu de flipper sorti pour le SG-1000 en 1983. En Nouvelle-Zélande, il est connu comme Video Flipper.

Il a été l'un des premiers jeux vidéo de flipper, étant sorti un an plus tôt que les tentatives de Jaleco et Nintendo, mais quatre ans après le Video Pinball d'Atari. Contrairement à Video Pinball, Sega Flipper utilise de la couleur.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action,Pinball</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Ação</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Sega Flipper</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Sega-galaga">
		<id>65717A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Sega Galaga</title>
	<synopsis>Take control of a fighter space craft and shoot down the invading aliens. Watch out for the swooping motherships, which will try to steal your fighter. Rescue captured fighters to double your firepower. Earn Perfect Bonuses as you battle your way through wave after wave in different challenging stages.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Toma el control de una nave espacial de combate y derriba a los alienígenas invasores. Ten cuidado con las naves nodrizas, que intentarán robarte a tu luchador. Rescata guerreros capturados para duplicar tu potencia de fuego. Obtén bonos perfectos mientras te abres camino a través de ola tras ola en diferentes etapas desafiantes.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Sega-Galaga est le port pour SG-1000 de Galaga, et est étrangement le seul port à recevoir un changement de nom.

Le joueur pilotes un vaisseau spatial et doit détruire tous les ennemis à l'écran, semblable à Space Invaders et Galaxian. Cependant, les ennemis de Galaga ont le pouvoir de capturer votre vaisseau (ce qui signifie que le joueur perd une vie). 
Toutefois, si vous êtes en mesure de détruire l'ennemi qui a capturé votre vaisseau, vous êtes en mesure de le récupéré est donc d'avoir 2 vaisseaux à la fois, doublant votre puissance de feu au détriment de devenir une cible plus grande.

Bien que Sega-Galaga est essentiellement le même jeu que la version arcade, les limitations de la SG-1000 font que les graphiques et le son ne sont pas aussi avancés. Aussi les «challenging stages» ont été omis, ce qui signifie que chaque stage est identique au précédent.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Sega-Galaga</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Sekaishi Nenpyou">
		<id>102229</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Sekaishi Nenpyou</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Sekaishi Nenpyou (Monbushou Shidouyouryou Junkyo) (traducción: World History Chronology (basado en el Currículo del Ministerio de Educación)) es parte de una serie de juegos educativos para el SC-3000 (y SG -1000 cuando se combina con el teclado SK-1100). Este se enfoca en la historia mundial.</synopsis>
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Sekaishi Nenpyou</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Serizawa Hachidan No Tsumeshogi">
		<id>65750A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Serizawa Hachidan No Tsumeshogi</title>
	<synopsis>Serizawa Hachidan no Tsumeshogi is a 1982 arcade game by Sega. It was subsequently ported to the SG-1000.

The arcade version is extremely rare and poorly documented.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Casual Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Serizawa Hachidan no Tsumeshogi es un juego de arcade de 1982 de Sega. Posteriormente fue portado al SG-1000.nnnnLa versión arcade es extremadamente rara y está mal documentada.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas,Juego casual</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Serizawa Hachidan no Tsumeshogi est un jeu d'arcade de 1982 de Sega. Il a ensuite été porté à la SG-1000.

La version arcade est extrêmement rare et mal documentée.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game,Casual Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle,Gelegenheitsspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Quebra-cabeças,Jogo casual</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Serizawa Hachidan no Tsumeshougi</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Shinnyuushain Tooru-kun">
		<id>65751A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Shinnyuushain Tooru-kun</title>
	<synopsis>Shinnyuushain Tooru-Kun is a game for the SG-1000. It was originally an arcade game by Konami known as Mikie outside Japan.

An unlicensed version was released for the Sega Master System in South Korea.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>ÉL UTILIZÓ TODO EL ODIO, PERO SU CEREAL ...
Pero ahora Mikie tiene novia.
Y a él le gusta tanto, que hará cualquier cosa para enviarle un mensaje.
El problema es que mucha gente realmente no quiere que él llegue. Mucha gente GRANDE. Maestros Todo el personal de cocina. Y el conserje más malo que hayas conocido.
Lo están persiguiendo por toda la escuela. Desde su salón de clases, hasta el vestuario, la cafetería, el gimnasio, el patio de recreo.
¿Por qué?
Él es solo un niño pequeño.
Él realmente necesita un poco de ayuda.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Shinnyuushain Tooru-Kun est un jeu pour le SG-1000. Il est à l'origine un jeu d'arcade de Konami connu comme Mikie en dehors du Japon.

Une version sans licence a été publiée pour le Sega Master System en Corée du Sud.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Shinnyushain Tooru Kun</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Sindbad Mystery">
		<id>65752A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Sindbad Mystery</title>
	<synopsis>Sindbad Mystery is an arcade game developed by Sega for Sega G80 (raster) hardware in 1983. It was ported to the SG-1000 in the same year. It follows a boy named Sindbad who must avoid monsters while piecing together a treasure map, similar to Pac-Man. He can also use a digging mechanic to trap enemies, similar to Heiankyo Alien and Space Panic.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>SINDBAD, un chico aventurero, viene a TREASURE ISLAND. Él quiere encontrar el tesoro exitosamente a través de las pistas en el MAPA DEL TESORO abriendo el? paneles. Para desafiarlo, los MONSTRUOS están aquí y allá, holgazaneando en las rutas laberínticas de la isla. Junta tu coraje, tira la PIEDRA hacia adelante y destruye los MONSTRUOS. ¡Después de encontrar con éxito el TESORO, sigamos con la próxima aventura en otra ISLA TESORO más maravillosa!</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Sindbad Mystery est un jeu d'arcade développé par Sega pour le matériel Sega G80 (raster) en 1983. Il a été porté à la SG-1000 dans la même année. 
Vous êtes un garçon appelé Sindbad qui doit éviter les monstres tout en reconstituant une carte du trésor, semblable à Pac-Man. Il peut également utiliser une pelle mécanique pour piéger les ennemis, semblable à Heiankyo Alien et Space Panic.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Sokoban">
		<id>65754A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Soukoban</title>
	<synopsis>Sokoban is a puzzle game developed by Thinking Rabbit. Sega ported it to the SG-1000 in 1985. Neither version left Japan.

Sokoban is the basis for Shove It! ...The Warehouse Game, released for the Sega Mega Drive.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>¡Sokoban es la base de Shove It! ... The Warehouse Game, lanzado para la Mega Drive de Sega.</synopsis>
	<genre>Rompecabezas</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Sokoban est un puzzle développé par Thinking Rabbit. Sega a porté le jeu à la SG-1000 en 1985. Aucune version n'a quitté le Japon.

Sokoban est la base de Shove It! ... The Warehouse Game, sorti pour le Sega Mega Drive.</synopsis>
	<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Puzzle</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<synopsis>Sokoban é um jogo de quebra-cabeça desenvolvido pela Thinking Rabbit. A Sega o portou para o SG-1000 em 1985. Nenhuma versão saiu do Japão.

Sokoban é a base para o Shove It! ... The Warehouse Game, lançado para o Sega Mega Drive.</synopsis>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Soukoban</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Thinking Rabbit</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Armor">
		<id>65783A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Space Armor</title>
	<synopsis>Space Armor is a 1984 shoot-'em-up game developed and published by Tsukuda Original. It was built with the Othello Multivision in mind, but like all Multivision games, is also compatible with the SG-1000. Space Armor was not released outside of Japan.

The game is built similarly to Namco's Xevious, in that it is a vertical shooter where one button fires at flying targets and the other at ground targets.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Fue construido teniendo en cuenta Othello Multivision, pero al igual que todos los juegos de Multivision, también es compatible con el SG-1000. Space Armor no fue lanzado fuera de Japón.nnnnEl juego está construido de forma similar al Xevious de Namco, en el sentido de que es un tirador vertical en el que un botón dispara a los objetivos voladores y el otro a los objetivos en el suelo.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Space Armor est un shoot-'em-up de 1984 développé et publié par Tsukuda Original. Il a été construit avec la Multivision Othello en vue, mais comme tous les jeux Multivision il est  également compatible avec le SG-1000. Space Armor n'a pas été distribué en dehors du Japon.

Le jeu est construit de manière similaire à Xevious de Namco, en ce sens qu'il est un shooter  vertical où un bouton tire les cibles volantes et l'autre les cibles au sol.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Space Armor</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Invaders">
		<id>65755A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Space Invaders</title>
	<synopsis>Earth is under attack from rows of bomb dropping aliens, and you need to defend it! The rows of aliens begin at the top of the screen, and you control a laser cannon at the bottom of the screen. Your goal is to earn points by shooting the aliens before they can land. The aliens march back and forth, and each time the end of the screen is reached they will drop one row closer to the bottom. Shoot them all, and you move on to the next (tougher) level, but if even one of them lands the game is over. 

Surprisingly the SG-1000 port of the game was one of the most accurate of its time, surpassing the NES and MSX versions which were the console's main competitors. Though it adds more color (the arcade version was simply black and white, with translucent overlays to mimic color), the SG-1000 version retains all the original graphics, whereas other ports (especially for Atari systems) re-drew the invaders due to various graphical restrictions.

The SG-1000 version does not appear to have been released outside of Japan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>¡Atención todos los terrícolas! Se han identificado infinidad de hordas alienígenas cerca de ti. Evita que los peligrosos Space Invaders aterricen en tu territorio. Usa tu cañón para defenderte de las oleadas de invasores alienígenas descendentes. ¡No dejes que caigan al suelo o todo habrá terminado para ti y la Tierra! ¡Destrúyelos y gana puntos!</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Space Invaders est un jeu d'arcade de 1979 développé par Taito. 
Le joueur contrôle un vaisseau qui peut se déplacer vers la gauche ou vers la droite et doit détruire les vagues d'aliens (ou «envahisseurs») avant qu'ils n'atteignent le sol. Space Invaders a été porté à une variété de consoles de jeux vidéo et d'ordinateurs, y compris le SG-1000 en 1985.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Mountain">
		<id>65784A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Space Mountain</title>
	<synopsis>Space Mountain is an SG-1000 game developed and published by Tsukuda Original with the Othello Multivision in mind. It is a very primitive third-person space ship shooter, in which the player has to gun down enemy craft before infiltrating a base.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Pilota tu caza tipo X-Wing contra enemigos TIE Fighter Fighter en este original juego SG-1000 de Tsukuda Original.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Space Mountain est un jeu SG-1000 développé et publié par Tsukuda Original. Il s'agit d'un jeu de tir à la 3ème personne très original, dans lequel le joueur doit abattre une embarcation ennemie avant d'infiltrer une base.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Space Mountain</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Tsukuda Original</developer>
		<publisher>Tsukuda Original</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Space Slalom">
		<id>65757A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Space Slalom</title>
	<synopsis>Space Slalom is a video game developed by Orca and published by Sega for the SG-1000 in 1983.

Though on the surface it appears to be a space-themed vertical shoot-'em-up, there is actually no shooting involved. The player controls a shuttle and must navigate it through a course defined by coloured stars, similar to ski slaloms. The player must also avoid obstacles, and will be awarded with extra points depending on on his/her speed across the course.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Aunque en la superficie parece ser un shoot-em-up vertical con temática espacial, en realidad no hay tiroteos. El jugador controla un transbordador y debe navegarlo a través de un recorrido definido por estrellas de colores, similar al esquí de slalom. El jugador también debe evitar obstáculos, y se le otorgarán puntos extra según su velocidad en el recorrido.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Space Slalom est un jeu vidéo développé par Orca et publié par Sega pour la SG-1000 en 1983.

Bien qu'à première vue, il semble être un shoot-'em-up verticale, il n'y a aucun tir impliqué. Le joueur contrôle une navette et doit la guider à travers un parcours défini par des étoiles de couleur, semblable au slalom de ski. Le joueur doit également éviter les obstacles, et les points lui seront attribués en fonction de sa vitesse sur le parcours.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Ação</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Space Slalom</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Orca</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Force">
		<id>65758A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Star Force</title>
	<synopsis>Star Force is a 1984 arcade vertical shoot-'em-up developed by Tehkan (now Tecmo), which was later brought to the SG-1000 in 1985.

The SG-1000 version of the game was released on both cartridge an on Sega Card.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Moverse en la oscuridad del cosmos es un planeta malvado y misterioso llamado GORDESS. Todos dejaron de luchar contra GORDESS debido a su increíble poder, hasta que un día un soldado que montaba un patrullero espacial desafió a GORDESS a luchar. ¡Únete a STAR FORCE y viaja a través de la galaxia para vencer a GORDESS!</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Star Force est un shoot-'em-up vertical d'arcade de 1984 développé par Tehkan (maintenant Tecmo), qui a ensuite été porté à la SG-1000 en 1985.

La version SG-1000 du jeu a été libérée à la fois en format cartouche et sur carte Sega.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Jacker">
		<id>65759A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Star Jacker</title>
	<synopsis>A "new feeling" space game. Glorious space troops fight against invading "Dester" army. Avoid UFO's continuous attacks weaving left and right, up and down. Counter-attack by using your fire button. Lead the space troops to the Carrier passing through the various mysteriy zones.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Un juego espacial de "nueva sensación". Gloriosas tropas espaciales luchan contra el ejército invasor "Dester". Evite los ataques continuos de OVNIS que se entrelazan a izquierda y derecha, arriba y abajo. Contraataque usando su botón de fuego. Dirige las tropas espaciales al Portador que pasa por las diversas zonas misteriosas.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Star Jacker est un jeu vidéo shoot'em up sorti pour Sega System 1 arcade hardware en 1983. Contrairement à la plupart des shoot'em ups, le joueur initialement contrôle trois navires spatiaux, en perdant un chaque fois que le joueur meurt. Cela signifie que sur la première vie, vous aurez trois fois le montant de la puissance de feu que sur votre dernière.

Comme Xevious, il existe deux types d'armes: les lasers avant pour les ennemis volants et les bombes pour les bases.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Star Jacker</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="07" day="15"/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Star Soldier">
		<id>140813</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Star Soldier</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Starbrain, una súper computadora gigante programada para la destrucción, está amenazando al Imperio Galáctico. Como un soldado estrella experto y experimentado, necesitas pilotar al César en la estación espacial que Starbrain ha ocupado. La estación espacial está fuertemente custodiada por naves enemigas y extrañas criaturas robóticas. Podrás encontrar diferentes armas en el camino para encender al César y aumentar las posibilidades de una misión exitosa. Star Soldier es un shooter de desplazamiento vertical estilo arcade para un jugador.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Super Tank">
		<id>65761A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Super Tank</title>
	<synopsis>Super Tank is a shoot-'em-up game for the SG-1000. The player drives a tank and is tasked with shooting at and destroying enemy units and structures.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Super Tank es un juego de shoot-em-up para el SG-1000. El jugador maneja un tanque y tiene la tarea de disparar y destruir unidades y estructuras enemigas.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Super Tank est un shoot-'em-up pour le SG-1000. Le joueur conduit un tank et est chargé de tirer et de détruire des unités ennemies et des structures.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Super Tank</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Tank Battalion">
		<id>102105</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Tank Battalion</title>
	<synopsis>Tank Battalion is a 1980 arcade game by Namco which was brought to the MSX in 1984. It was subsequently ported to the SG-1000 in Taiwan and Sega Master System in South Korea.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>En Tank Battalion, controlas un tanque en un laberinto. Uno tras otro, los tanques enemigos entran al laberinto, y debes dispararles a todos antes de que alcancen y destruyan tu base. Las paredes del laberinto se pueden disparar y destruir. Después de que se destruyan todos los tanques blancos, se pasa al siguiente nivel. Cada diseño de nivel requiere diferentes tácticas, dependiendo de las formaciones de las paredes. Algunos puntos en ciertos niveles hacen que las tácticas de emboscada sean perfectas, en otros niveles debes avanzar y retroceder para erradicar los tanques enemigos. De vez en cuando aparece un tanque rojo, dispara para obtener puntos de bonificación.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>DahJee</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Tanoshii Sansuu (Elementary School 4th, vol.1)">
		<id>102230</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Tanoshii Sansuu (Elementary School 4th, vol.1)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Tanoshii Sansuu (Elementary School 4th, vol.1)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer Center</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 5-Nen Jou)">
		<id>167354</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 5-Nen Jou)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 5-Nen Jou, vol.1)</title>
	</locale>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 6-Nen Ge)">
		<id>167355</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 6-Nen Ge)</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<genre>Educacional</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Ludo-Educatif</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Lernspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Tanoshii Sansuu (Shougaku 6-Nen Ge)</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Stratford Computer Center</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Terebi Oekaki">
		<id>65762A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Terebi Oekaki</title>
	<synopsis>Terebi Oekaki is the game packaged with the Sega Graphic Board for the SG-1000. It is a simple paint program.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<genre>Acción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Twinbee">
		<id>102106</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Twinbee</title>
	<synopsis>TwinBee is a 1985 arcade game by Konami which was brought to the MSX in 1986. The MSX version was subsequently ported to the SG-1000 in Taiwan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Los jugadores controlarán a los luchadores que se llaman 'TwinBee' y 'WinBee', que el Dr. Cinnamon desarrolló, y desafiarán la lucha al ejército.nnHay dos versiones, 'Bubble system' y 'ROM', en este trabajo. Por favor, disfrute las diferencias de cada tablero.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Jumbo</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Uranai Angel Cutie">
		<id>129673</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Uranai Angel Cutie</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Uranai Angel Cutie es un juego misceláneo, desarrollado y publicado por Sega, que fue lanzado en Japón en 1984.</synopsis>
	<genre>Juego casual</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Casual Game</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Gelegenheitsspiel</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Uranai Angel Cutie</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Wonder Boy">
		<id>65765A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Wonder Boy</title>
	<synopsis>WONDER BOY starts off a long and hazardous journey in pursuit of KING, who has kidnapped his girlfriend, TINA. KING lives in a faraway place, inhabited by monstrous creatures and full of many surprises. On the way, our hero has to collect food to increase his energy. WONDER BOY's ultimate mission is to rescue TINA and prove to one and all that true love always triumphs.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action,Platform</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Como Tom-Tom, el Wonder Boy, depende de ti rescatar a tu novia Tanya de las viles garras del monstruo que la ha secuestrado. Para hacerlo, debes navegar una serie de mundos en una carrera contra el tiempo para alcanzar tu objetivo. En el camino, lucharás contra enemigos y recogerás fruta que aumentará la cantidad de tiempo que tienes para completar tu misión.</synopsis>
	<genre>Acción,Plataforma</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>WONDER BOY commence un voyage long et dangereux à la poursuite de KING, qui a enlevé sa petite amie, TINA. KING vit dans un endroit lointain, habité par des créatures monstrueuses et pleines de surprises. Sur le chemin, notre héros doit rassembler des aliments pour augmenter son énergie. La mission ultime de WONDER BOY est de sauver TINA et de prouver à tout le monde que le vrai amour triomphe toujours.</synopsis>
	<genre>Action,Plateforme</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Action,Plattform</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Ação,Plataforma</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Yamato">
		<id>65766A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Yamato</title>
	<synopsis>Avoid the enemy's attack by torpedoes and missiles. Shoot down the missiles. Be careful, YAMATO will explode if it is hit broadside. Aim at the enemy and fire the guns. Attack enemy's planes by using your quick-friring guuns. Can YAMATO survive through this fierce battle?</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Evite el ataque del enemigo con torpedos y misiles. Dispara a los misiles. Ten cuidado, YAMATO explotará si es golpeado de costado. Apunta al enemigo y dispara las armas. Ataca los aviones enemigos usando tus guuns de ataque rápido. ¿Puede YAMATO sobrevivir a través de esta batalla feroz?</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Yamato est un jeu d'arcade développé par Sega en 1983. Il fonctionne sur le matériel conçu par Nichibutsu pour le jeu de 1980 Crazy Climber. Il a ensuite été porté au SG-1000 plus tard dans l'année.

Dans le jeu, le joueur prend le contrôle du cuirassé Yamato (qui a été coulé au large de Kyuushuu pendant la Seconde Guerre mondiale), le but étant de tirer sur les navires et les avions ennemis tout en évitant les missiles et les torpilles.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="03" day="01"/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Yie Ar Kung-fu 2">
		<id>102107</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Yie Ar Kung-fu 2</title>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Veinte años después de la derrota de Chop Suey Gang por Lee, uno de sus miembros resurge con otros siete señores de la guerra y se proclama el Emperador Yie Gah. Formado en el arte de Kung Fu por su padre, el hijo de Lee, Lee Young, se propone derrotar a esta nueva amenaza y salvar a China de su mala influencia.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Beat'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<genre>Tir,Beat'em All</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Beat'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Briga de rua</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>DahJee</publisher>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Zaxxon">
		<id>65767A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Zaxxon</title>
	<synopsis>ZAXXON thrusts you into the depths of outer space. Test your pilot skills as you strap into the command position. Prepare for an action-packed challenge of space survival. Score points as you dive, climb, and swoop down to destroy the enemy's floating fortress. Dodge deadly laser barriers, enemy missiles, and rapid gunfire! Destroy enemy fuel tanks and your own supply is replenished. Survive the enemy's fighter fleet attack and face the ultimate challenge... the powerful, armored ZAXXON ROBOT.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>ZAXXON te empuja hacia las profundidades del espacio exterior. Pon a prueba tus habilidades como piloto en la posición de comando. Prepárese para un desafío lleno de acción de supervivencia espacial. Sume puntos mientras bucea, asciende y desciende para destruir la fortaleza flotante del enemigo. ¡Esquiva las barreras láser mortales, los misiles enemigos y los disparos rápidos! Destruye los tanques de combustible enemigos y tu propio suministro se repone. Sobrevive al ataque de la flota de combate del enemigo y enfrenta el último desafío ... el poderoso robot blindado ZAXXON.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Zaxxon est un shoot'em up d'arcade sorti par Sega. Il est nommé d'après son utilisation révolutionnaire de projection axonométrique (bien que plus spécifiquement, il utilise la projection isométrique) et est sortis sur le matériel d'arcade en 1982.

Zaxxon a été le premier jeu vidéo à utiliser une perspective isométrique, un style graphique qui serait largement utilisé dans les années qui vont suivre. C'était une première tentative d'ajouter une profondeur tridimensionnelle au genre shoot'em up. Le terme "perspective isométrique" a été initialement inventé par Sega en référence à Zaxxon.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Zippy Race">
		<id>65768A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Zippy Race</title>
	<synopsis>The player takes control of a motorcyclist who's in a race to be the first to traverse the United States from the west to the east coast, starting in Los Angeles and ending up in New York City.

Gameplay consists of the player dodging cars and other roadway hazards on their way to the next checkpoint. Players can either accelerate or hit the brakes on their motorcycle so they can avoid getting into an accident. Accidents cause the player to lose fuel and running out of fuel can end the game. So players must keep an eye out on the fuel gauge, which can be refilled by fuel barrels littered throughout each stage. Each car the player passes betters their ranks which increases their score.

The SG-1000 version of the game is one of two SG-1000 releases to see four separate Japanese releases (the other being Monaco GP) - three on cartridge with each of the SG-1000's box designs, and one on Sega Card. Despite this it did not see a release outside of Japan.</synopsis>
	<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>El objetivo del juego es llegar al final de cada etapa de la carrera de motos de costa a costa del personaje del jugador desde Los Ángeles hasta Nueva York antes de que se agote el suministro de combustible. En el camino, el corredor debe evitar el tráfico vehicular y tener en cuenta las bifurcaciones en el camino, recolectando combustible extra y obteniendo bonificaciones cuando aparecen.</synopsis>
	<genre>Carreras, Conducción</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Vous devez contrôlez un pilote moto, en évitant les voitures et les obstacles tout en s'assurant qu'il ne manque pas de carburant. Le joueur voyage à travers les États-Unis d'Amérique, d'où le titre de Motorace USA.</synopsis>
	<genre>Course, Conduite</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Rennen, Fahren</genre>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="1">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
	<game name="Zoom 909">
		<id>65769A</id>
	<locale lang="EN">
	<title>Zoom 909</title>
	<synopsis>Zoom 909 is an arcade game developed by Sega for VCO Object arcade hardware. It was released worldwide in 1982, however after obtaining a license for Buck Rogers, western versions of the game became known as Buck Rogers: Planet of Zoom. Both Zoom 909 and Buck Rogers: Planet of Zoom are largely the same game minus some minor graphical differences.

Though most home ports of the game are based on Planet of Zoom, Zoom 909 was brought to the Japanese MSX in 1983 and SG-1000 in 1985. These versions take more liberties with the formula, introducing a top-down stage as level 3.</synopsis>
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="ES">
	<synopsis>Es el siglo 25. Eres Buck Rogers peleando la batalla de Planet Zoom. Con habilidad se desliza a través de mensajes de electrones de zapping. Esquiva y destruye tolvas espaciales y platillos alienígenas. ¡Tu carrera contra la muerte acaba de comenzar! Prepárate para la batalla con tu enemigo más poderoso ... ¡el barco madre! Nunca es fácil cuando es hacer o morir. Debes golpear el centro muerto de la Nave Madre. Cualquier cosa menos solo desperdiciará el combustible precioso. Apúntate, pero date prisa ... ¡tu combustible está peligrosamente bajo!</synopsis>
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="FR">
	<synopsis>Zoom 909 est un jeu d'arcade développé par Sega pour le matériel d'arcade VCO Object. Il a été publié en  1982 dans le monde entier, mais après avoir obtenu une licence pour Buck Rogers, les versions occidentales du jeu on été connues sous le nom Buck Rogers: Planète of Zoom. Les deux, Zoom 909 et Buck Rogers: Planet of Zoom sont en grande partie identiques excepté quelques différences graphiques.</synopsis>
	<genre>Tir,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="DE">
	<genre>Shooter,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="PT">
	<genre>Tiro,Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</locale>
	<locale lang="JA">
	<title>Zoom 909</title>
	</locale>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<date year="1985" month="" day=""/>
		<rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
		<input players="2">
			<control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
			<control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
			<control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
			<control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
		</input>
	</game>
</datafile>
