<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="wiitdb.xsd">
  <WiiTDB version="201812041646" games="106"/>
  <game name="A.e.">
    <id>38966A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>A.E.</title>
      <synopsis>A port of the classic computer game, A.E. (Which stands for Anti Environmental) is a most unusual 5200 prototype.  It was never announced by Atari nor was it mentioned in any internal documents. A.E. is an arcade style shooting game in which you have to shoot down waves of evil flying mechanical stingrays in order to save your planet.

The Atari 5200 version only has four levels as opposed to ten that the computer versions boast. The loading times for the levels are also longer due to hardware constraints of the Atari 5200.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter / Vertical,Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>A.E. (que significa Anti Environmental) es el prototipo 5200 más inusual. Nunca fue anunciado por Atari ni fue mencionado en ningún documento interno. R.E. es un juego de disparos de estilo arcade en el que tienes que derribar oleadas de malvadas mantarrayas mecánicas para salvar tu planeta.</synopsis>
      <genre>Tiro / Vertical,Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Tir / Vertical,Tir</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <synopsis>Ein Port des klassischen Computerspiels A.E. Es ist ein ungewöhnlicher 5200-Prototyp. Es wurde nie von Atari angekündigt, noch wurde es in internen Dokumenten erwähnt. In der Tat erschien A. E. gerade aus heiterem Himmel eines Tages, als ein Sammler eine Kopie in einer Kiste mit alten 5200 Prototypen fand. Warum Atari erwägt, ein zwei Jahre altes Computerspiel auf die 5200 zu portieren, ist unklar, aber die Ergebnisse waren einzigartig ...nnnnA.E. ist ein Arcade-Stil-Shooter, in dem Sie Wellen von bösen fliegenden mechanischen Stachelrochen abschießen, um Ihren Planeten zu retten. Für den Fall, dass Sie sich über den Namen wundern, steht A.E. für Anti Environmental, da die bösen Stringrays die Umgebung zerstören wollen (mmkay ...). Warum die Programmierer sich dafür entschieden haben, Stachelrochen als Feind zu fliegen, ist jedermanns Vermutung, aber ich ziehe es vor, sie als böse Außerirdische von einer mysteriösen Angriffskraft zu betrachten, die als A.E bekannt ist. So oder so, diese kleinen Kerle sind tödlich!</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter / Vertikal,Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Tiro / Vertical,Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Broderbund</developer>
    <publisher>Broderbund</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Adventure 2">
    <id>37916A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Adventure II</title>
      <synopsis>This homebrew Atari 5200 cartridge is a direct, yet unofficial sequel to the Atari 2600 action role-playing classic Adventure. The player controls an unnamed knight on a quest to return the stolen chalice to the Seashore Kingdom's Castle. Like the original, Adventure II is played from top-down perspective, with player roaming the large game world.. The player character can carry one item at a time which are used to solve puzzles.
While the main player graphic remains a square, the world of Adventure II is far larger and more robust than the original. The game's 32k cartridge features 4 distinct kingdoms, complete with unique inhabitants, items and secrets.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Este cartucho homebrew Atari 5200 es una secuela directa, aunque no oficial, de la aventura clásica Atari 2600 de rol y acción. El jugador controla a un caballero sin nombre en una misión para devolver el cáliz robado al Castillo del Reino de Seashore. Al igual que el original, Adventure II se juega desde la perspectiva cenital, con el jugador deambulando por el gran mundo del juego. El personaje del jugador puede llevar un elemento a la vez que se utilizan para resolver acertijos.
Mientras que el pesonaje principal del jugador sigue siendo un cuadrado, el mundo de Adventure II es mucho más grande y más robusto que el original. El cartucho de 32k del juego presenta 4 reinos distintos, con habitantes únicos, objetos y secretos.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción,Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action,Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action,Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Ação,Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Square Trio</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="2007" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Asteroids">
    <id>38967A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Asteroids</title>
      <synopsis>Trapped in space somewhere between the planets Ortanus and Earth, your ship is suddenly surrounded by a field of massive asteroids. And, as if that weren't enough excitement for one day, a group of alien saucers stage a surprise attack. Quickly you take over the controls to save your ship from imminent doom. You must thrust away from the path of the oncoming asteroids. Put up shields to protect the ship. Hyperspace into thin air. Flip over and get the asteroids attacking from behind. It's all in your hands now. Good luck!</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Atrapada en el espacio en algún lugar entre los planetas Ortanus y la Tierra, tu nave se ve repentinamente rodeada por un campo de asteroides masivos. Y, como si eso no fuera suficiente emoción para un día, un grupo de platillos alienígenas realiza un ataque sorpresa. Rápidamente tomas los controles para salvar a tu nave de una condena inminente. Debes alejarte del camino de los asteroides que se aproximan. Coloca escudos para proteger el barco. Hiperespacio en el aire. Da la vuelta y consigue que los asteroides ataquen desde atrás. Todo está en tus manos ahora. ¡Buena suerte!</synopsis>
      <genre>Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Tir</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Astro Chase">
    <id>37917A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Astro Chase</title>
      <synopsis>As pilot of a spaceship, your job is to save the planet Earth! Eight mega mines are slowly homing in, and you need to destroy them all before they reach Earth. Trying to stop you are a variety of flying saucers which will constantly be chasing you around the planet. Your ship is equipped with lasers which can be used to destroy enemy saucers and the mega mines. Located throughout the space around Earth are eight shield depots; if you fly through one of these, you will temporarily become invincible. Your spaceship also has a limited energy supply; if you get too low on energy, it can be resupplied at one of the generators located in the four corners of the play area. When all of the mega mines have been destroyed, you will move on to the next, faster chase!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>A bordo de tu lanzadera, debes salvar la tierra del ataque enemigo. Si te mantienes cerca del suelo, destruirás los barcos hostiles que intentan acercarte a él.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>A bord de votre navette, vous devez sauver la terre de l'attaque ennemie. En restant à proximité de la terre, vous détruirez les vaisseaux hostiles qui tentent de s'y approcher.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>First Star Software, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="7">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Ballblazer">
    <id>37918A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Ballblazer</title>
      <synopsis>In the year 3037, the most competitive sport in the known universe is Ballblazer. For the first time ever, humans from the planet Earth have won the right to compete in the final round of the Ballblazer Championship, to fight for Earth's honor and the title Masterblazer!

Ballblazer is a 3D futuristic soccer-like game, where the player (inside a Rotofoil) is set on a one-on-one 1,155 square playing field (the Grid). The objective of the player to kick a floating ball (Plasmorb) inside the opponent's goal (Goalbeams). A player may compete against a human or computer opponent.

The Rotofoil is equipped with a multi-purpose forcefield. This forcefield when in short distance of the Plasmorb will act as a pull field, automatically pulling the Plasmorb towards to player. When a player in possession of the Plasmorb shoots, the forcefield will act as push field and launches the ball. When the match starts, the player must move down field and attempt to gain possession of the Plasmorb using the joystick and blast the Plasmorb to an intended direction. 

The player should also be aware that the Goldbeams move slightly every second and the distance between them will shrink. The highest scoring goals are goals made when Goldbeams have disappeared across the horizon (Over The Horizon/OTH shots). A player may also attempt to steal possession of a Plasmorb by rushing beside the opponent and blast the Plasmorb away. The game ends when time runs out or a player wins 10 consecutive goals. If the game ends in a draw, over-time will apply and the first player to score will win the game.

Scoring

Close-in goals - 1 point
Goals near Goldbeams - 2 points
OTH shots - 3 points
Players may steal points from each other by making goals. 
The total combined score of both players cannot accede more than 10 points.
A player winning 10 consecutive points automatically wins the game.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports,Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Ballblazer es un juego de fútbol fu-turista.</synopsis>
      <genre>Deportes,Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Ballblazer est un jeu de football futuriste à un contre un.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sport,Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport,Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Esporte,Ação</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Lucasfilm Games LLC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari - Lucasfilm</publisher>
    <date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Barroom Baseball">
    <id>38971A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Barroom Baseball</title>
      <synopsis>Barroom Baseball was a prototype game coded by Atari in 1983 for use within Atari 5200 arcade machines but it was never released. The game itself is essentially RealSports Baseball modified to remove some of the game options. It was also intended to be a timed game, requiring additional coins or tokens in order to continue with the game. As with RealSports Baseball, Barroom Baseball includes steals, nine different pitch types, hit-and-run plays, synthesized speech, a detailed scoreboard, tag-ups, dirt-colored base paths, the ability to control the speed of pitches and swings of the bat, and other such bells, whistles, and necessities</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Barroom Baseball fue un prototipo de juego codificado por Atari en 1983 para su uso dentro de las máquinas recreativas Atari 5200 pero nunca fue lanzado. El juego en sí es esencialmente RealSports Baseball modificado para eliminar algunas de las opciones del juego. También pretendía ser un juego cronometrado, que requería monedas o fichas adicionales para continuar con el juego. Al igual que con RealSports Baseball, Barroom Baseball incluye robos, nueve tipos de tono diferentes, jugadas de golpear y ejecutar, discurso sintetizado, un marcador detallado, etiquetas, senderos base de color sucio, la capacidad de controlar la velocidad de lanzamientos y cambios de el murciélago y otras campanas, silbatos y necesidades similares</synopsis>
      <genre>Deportes</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Battlezone">
    <id>38972A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Battlezone</title>
      <synopsis>A port of the arcade game Battlezone for Atari 5200. Like the arcade game you drive a tank around and shoot enemy tanks while trying to avoid their fire in a 3d environment. It was unfortunately never released and only exists in prototype form. The prototype seems mostly finished but the hit detection seems off at times and not perfected. It also replaces some of the vector based graphics of the arcade with raster likely due to limitations of the Atari 5200. You can also play this with two joysticks which is said to help with controlling the game versus single if you get used to it.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Un puerto del juego de arcade Battlezone para Atari 5200. Al igual que el juego de arcade, puedes conducir un tanque y disparar tanques enemigos mientras intentas evitar el fuego en un entorno 3D. Desafortunadamente nunca se lanzó y solo existe en forma de prototipo. El prototipo parece terminado en su mayoría, pero la detección de impacto parece a veces desactualizada. También reemplaza algunos de los gráficos basados ??en vectores del arcade con raster probablemente debido a las limitaciones del Atari 5200. También puede jugar esto con dos joysticks que se dice que ayudan a controlar el juego en comparación con el simple si se acostumbra.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Beamrider">
    <id>37919A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Beamrider</title>
      <synopsis>Beamrider is a 3-D arcade action game. You control a beam riding spaceship on a mission to clear 99 sectors of space from hostile aliens. The spaceship is located at the bottom of the screen and it can only stop on one of five beams. You are armed with both lasers and torpedoes; torpedoes are more powerful and can destroy more enemies compared to lasers, however you only get three per level. To complete a sector, you need to destroy fifteen white flying saucers. After all saucers are destroyed, the sector sentinel passes by which can be destroyed for extra points. Each even number sector up until sector 16 will add a new type of enemy to deal with. These additional enemies will just try to slow your mission, though, only the saucers need to be destroyed to advance. Occassionally a rejeuvinator will appear; if this is collected, you can earn an extra life. But be careful, because if you accidentally shoot the rejeuvinator it will turn into an enemy!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Beamrider es un juego de acción arcade 3-D. Controla una nave espacial que lleva una viga en una misión para limpiar 99 sectores de espacio de extraterrestres hostiles. La nave espacial se encuentra en la parte inferior de la pantalla y solo puede detenerse en uno de los cinco haces. Estás armado con rayos láser y torpedos; Los torpedos son más poderosos y pueden destruir a más enemigos en comparación con los láser, sin embargo, solo obtienes tres por nivel. Para completar un sector, necesitas destruir quince platillos voladores blancos. Después de que se destruyan todos los platillos, pasa centinela del sector que puede destruirse para puntos extra. Cada sector de número par hasta el sector 16 agregará un nuevo tipo de enemigo para tratar. Sin embargo, estos enemigos adicionales solo intentarán retrasar tu misión, solo los platillos deben ser destruidos para avanzar. Ocasionalmente aparecerá un rejuvenecedor; si esto se recoge, puede ganar una vida extra. Pero ten cuidado, porque si disparas accidentalmente al rejeuvinator se convertirá en un enemigo!</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Berzerk">
    <id>37921A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>BerZerk</title>
      <synopsis>You have been sent into a building infested with robots, and must do your best to clear it out. Each rooms has a number of walls through the middle, which restrict your movement. There will be a number of bad guys in the room - on early screens they may be immobile and not shoot at you, but after a few levels they become capable of shooting in multiple directions. You can shoot at them in 8 directions, but can't shoot diagonally while moving. There are gaps at the side of each room, through which you exit, before or after clearing the room (there is a bonus for clearance). You get an extra life every 2000 points.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Usted ha sido enviado a un edificio infestado de robots, y debe hacer todo lo posible para despejarlo. Cada habitación tiene una serie de paredes a través del medio, que restringen su movimiento. Habrá una cantidad de tipos malos en la sala; en las pantallas tempranas pueden estar inmóviles y no dispararle, pero después de algunos niveles se vuelven capaces de disparar en múltiples direcciones. Puede dispararles en 8 direcciones, pero no puede disparar en diagonal mientras se mueve. Hay espacios al lado de cada habitación, a través de los cuales sale, antes o después de despejar la habitación (hay una bonificación por la autorización). Obtienes una vida extra cada 2000 puntos.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Stern Electronics, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Black Belt">
    <id>44441A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Black Belt</title>
      <synopsis>This unreleased, unfinished game is similar to Broderbund's famous game, Karateka. Select your black belt level (difficulty level) and fight your way through eight rooms. The keypad is used to execute a variety of karate moves, although the game has no collision detection so you can't really fight your enemies. While the game looks promising, you cannot progress beyond eight rooms because you can't defeat your enemies.</synopsis>
      <genre>Fight</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>nnEste juego no publicado e inacabado es similar al famoso juego de Broderbund, Karateka. Selecciona el nivel de tu cinturón negro (nivel de dificultad) y lucha a través de ocho salas. El teclado se usa para ejecutar una variedad de movimientos de karate, aunque el juego no tiene detección de colisiones, por lo que no puedes luchar contra tus enemigos. Si bien el juego parece prometedor, no puedes avanzar más allá de ocho salas porque no puedes derrotar a tus enemigos.</synopsis>
      <genre>Combate</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Combat</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Kampf</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Blaster">
    <id>44442A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Blaster</title>
      <synopsis>Blaster developed by Vid Kidz for Williams was released for the arcades and is quite obscure. What is interesting however is that the Atari 5200 version that was not released was actually made before the arcade game.

An unofficial sequel to Robotron 2084 (As it takes place in 2085) Blaster is a 3d style shooter with impressive graphics for the time. In it the player takes the view from a spaceship cockpit so moving in the different directions shifts the entire screen. There are four levels you will play through avoiding obstacles, saving humans, and defeating alien enemies. Upon beating the four levels the game loops but will be more difficult.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Tir</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Viz Kidz</developer>
    <publisher>Williams</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Blueprint">
    <id>37922A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Blue Print</title>
      <synopsis>Your girlfriend Daisy is in trouble! Ollie Org is chasing her across the top of the screen, and you need to come to the rescue. To stop Ollie before time runs out, you need to construct a machine. The blue print for the machine is at the bottom of the screen, so all you need to do is locate the parts which are hidden in the numerous houses in a maze like town. When you locate a part, drag it back and place it on the blue print. When all parts have been located, press the start button and the machine is ready to go! To make your task more difficult, there are several obstacles that get in the way. If you enter a house which doesn't contain a part, you will instead be stuck with a bomb. You will need to hurry and diffuse any bombs in the bomb pit before they explode! From time to time, a flower pot will fall from above and then hop off the screen. Get hit by a flower pot, and you lose a life. You also need to be careful of Fuzzy Wuzzy, who wanders around the neighborhood randomly. An encounter with Fuzzy Wuzzy will also be deadly! Hiding in the bomb pit is Sneaky Pete; while he isn't deadly, he will occasionally appear and press the start button before your machine is complete. If this happens, you will need to drag Pete back to the bomb pit and reassemble all of the machine parts.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>¡Tu novia Daisy está en problemas! Ollie Org la está persiguiendo en la parte superior de la pantalla, y tienes que ir al rescate. Para detener a Ollie antes de que se acabe el tiempo, debe construir una máquina. La impresión azul de la máquina se encuentra en la parte inferior de la pantalla, por lo que todo lo que necesita hacer es ubicar las piezas que están ocultas en las numerosas casas de una ciudad laberíntica. Cuando ubique una pieza, arrástrela hacia atrás y colóquela en la impresión azul. ¡Cuando se hayan localizado todas las piezas, presione el botón de inicio y la máquina estará lista! Para hacer su tarea más difícil, hay varios obstáculos que se interponen en el camino. Si ingresas a una casa que no contiene una parte, en cambio estarás atrapado con una bomba. ¡Tendrás que apresurarte y difundir cualquier bomba en el pozo de la bomba antes de que exploten! De vez en cuando, una maceta caerá desde arriba y luego saltará de la pantalla. Ser golpeado por una maceta y perder una vida. También debes tener cuidado con Fuzzy Wuzzy, que deambula por el vecindario al azar. ¡Un encuentro con Fuzzy Wuzzy también será mortal! Oculto en el hoyo de la bomba es Sneaky Pete; si bien no es letal, ocasionalmente aparecerá y presionará el botón de inicio antes de que la máquina se complete. Si esto sucede, tendrá que arrastrar a Pete de vuelta al pozo de la bomba y volver a montar todas las partes de la máquina.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Bally Midway</developer>
    <publisher>CBS Electronics</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="17">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Boogie">
    <id>44443A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Boogie</title>
      <synopsis>Boogie was a demo was coded by Atari for internal use as a demonstration of the audio capabilities of the Atari 5200. The cartridge plays an impressive little boogie, then repeats. There is no game or graphics here, just the title screen and the musical score</synopsis>
      <genre>Music</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Bounty Bob Strikes Back!">
    <id>37924A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Bounty Bob Strikes Back!</title>
      <synopsis>Bounty Bob Strikes Back! is the sequel to Miner 2049er and features similar gameplay. As Bounty Bob, your goal is to claim every inch of 25 challenging mines. To do this, you must walk over each segment of the framework in the mines. To reach each segment of framework, you will need to figure out a way to jump, climb, or use one of the many devices occasionally available to get there. To you help you get around (or sometimes hinder progress) are ladders, slides, suction tubes, cannons, transporters, and other devices. Wandering about the mines are many dangerous mutants. If you come in contact with one of these, you will lose a life. Scattered throughout each mine are special food items; collect one of these, and you will temporarily be able to eliminate the mutants by walking into them. You will need to figure out a unique strategy for each level in order to complete it, plus there is a time limit so claim all the territory quickly!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Big Five Software</developer>
    <publisher>Big Five Software</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Bristles">
    <id>37925A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Bristles</title>
      <synopsis>The object of this game is to paint all the rooms of a building without losing your paint brushes (lives) and before time runs out. You and up to three friends can select from any of eight player sprites, male or female. There are six skill levels with eight buildings per level. After you finish a building, you will be given part of a special message. There are six messages, one per skill level. 

You get from floor to floor by way of elevators. Be sure the elevator is at your floor when you board or you will fall down the elevator shaft. There are also three ladders out of the basement. Watch out for Flying Half-Pints. They will appear on one side of the building at any floor except the basement and will move horizontally across. You must jump or duck to avoid them. 

Starting at building number two, you must also avoid Dumb Buckets. These will walk around and ride the elevators but they always move in a set pattern. Starting on building three and continuing every other building, you have to contend with Brenda, the superintendent's brat. She will put hand prints on your freshly painted walls, which will cost you forty points and require repainting to finish that building. You can grab the candy cane in these buildings and give it to her. This will stop her for fifteen seconds so you can repaint.

Starting with building four, you must beware of the Bucket Chucker. Unlike the Dumb Bucket, he does not follow a set pattern, he follows you. You cannot destroy the Bucket Chucker but there are two ways he can be trapped. One way is to use the paint mixer, a square within a square. You touch it to turn it on for four seconds and if the Bucket Chucker touches it while it is on, he will shake for four seconds. You can turn the paint mixer on over and over while the Bucket Chucker is in it, unlimited times. Another way to trap the Bucket Chucker is to go to the basement, lead the Bucket Chucker to the ladders, go up a ladder, avoiding the elevator, then go left or right. The Bucket Chucker will then be stuck in the basement until you lose a brush.

Starting on building five, you must jump over steam pipes or they will trip you, losing you a brush. In buildings six, seven and eight, your brush will run dry after eight, seven or six rooms, respectively. To refill, simply touch the large paint brushes in some rooms.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>First Star Software, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Atari2600.com</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="2004" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Buck Rogers - Planet Of Zoom">
    <id>37926A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Buck Rogers : Planet of Zoom</title>
      <synopsis>Fast and furious racing game taking place on a futuristic racetrack.  Guide your spaceship between the pylons and shoot down other enemy racers.

Based on the arcade game (which is even more loosely based on the Buck Rogers comic strips).</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="River Raid">
    <id>37978A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Carol Shaw's River Raid</title>
      <synopsis>River Raid is a vertically scrolling action game. You fly a jet up a river in an attempt to destroy bridges which are vital to the enemy. The river is heavily guarded, however, with balloons, ships, choppers, and enemy aircraft trying to stop you. Along the way you will need to fly over fuel stations to refuel your jet and keep flying.

The plane is armed with a cannon with unlimited ammo. It can be used to destroy the enemy vehicles and bridges, but a careless player can accidentally destroy a fuel station. Colliding with the riverbanks or with the enemy aircraft destroys your plane and makes you lose a life.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Castle Blast">
    <id>37927A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Castle Blast</title>
      <synopsis>This game is based on the fifth screen of the coin-op game Phoenix.

The object of this game is to destroy the Castle on the Mothership. You fire Vertical Trajectory Missiles, or VTMs, at the shield on the bottom of the Mothership. When you penetrate the shield, then blast the Castle. To score extra points, you can also shoot the enemy spaceships flying overhead.

If you destroy the Castle, you advance to the next level, where you will need to contend with Focused Energy Beams, or FEBs, fired from the Mothership. There will also be stars appearing in the sky, making it harder to target the spaceships.

If you manage to obliterate the Castle again, you will proceed to the next level, which adds ground-based tanks assaulting you. You have Horizontal Trajectory Missiles, or HTMs, to deal with this new enemy but do not lose sight of your primary goal.

Your joystick moves you left or right. The lower button fires VTMs, the upper button fires HTMs.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Ronen Habot</developer>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="2002" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Castle Crisis">
    <id>37928A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Castle Crisis</title>
      <synopsis>This is a version of the Atari coin-op game Warlords, designed to look and play as much like the coin-op version as possible. Use your shield to deflect fireballs away from your castle and towards your opponents. You can also capture fireballs and launch them at your opponents with even greater force.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Esta es una versión del juego de recreativas Atari (Coin-Operated) "Warlords", diseñado para verse y jugarse igual a la versión de recreativas. Usa tu escudo para repeler bolas de fuego lejos de tu castillo y lanzarlas a tus enemigos. También puedes atrapar bolas de fuego y lanzarlas a tus enemigos con mayor fuerza aún.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Centipede">
    <id>37929A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Centipede</title>
      <synopsis>In Centipede, the player is trapped in the Enchanted Forest. Armed with only a magic wand to ward off the forest's insect denizens, all of which apparently are attacking in the player in continuous waves. 

The player must use the magic wand to shoot sparks at approaching insects to score points by pressing the controller button. Holding down the controller button will set the wand to rapid fire shots. If the player is bitten by an insect, the player will be temporarily paralyzed and lose one of the three starting magic wands. 

Insect Opponents and Mushrooms
All enemy insects have a distinctive sound before attacking, which may help the player identify which insect is attacking. Enemies and objects in the game are as the following:

1. The Centipede
The Centipede will attack in 12 waves. In the first wave, the Centipede will have a head attached to 11 body segments. In the second wave, the Centipede will have a head attached to 10 body segments, in addition to a detached head. The third wave will have the Centipede with an attached head, 9 body segments, plus two detached heads. These body segments will transform into heads and continue to do so until Wave 12. In the last wave, the Centipede will have 12 detached heads, independently attacking the player. Centipede heads are worth more points than body segments.

Attacks from the Centipede will come from the top of the screen, moving downward. If a spark hits any part of the Centipede, that particular body segment will transform into a mushroom, while the body segment behind it will become the new Centipede head. When the Centipede is destroyed, it will briefly disappear and re-appear from the top of the screen again.

The Spider
The Spider will attempt to distract the player from attacking the Centipede. It will destroy any mushroom it touches. Spiders will score more points if it is hit in closer distances.

The Flea
The Flea will appear if the player has destroyed most of the existing mushrooms. It will drop down creating a new batch of mushrooms where it falls. The Flea will disappear after two hits. After the first hit, the Flea will drop down much faster.

The Scorpion
The Scorpion will appear in the third wave. It moves slowly but will pick up speed, moving faster. While doing so, it will poison any mushroom it touches.

Mushrooms
Mushrooms fill the Enchanted Forest and may act as obstacles or cover for the player, with added effects to enemy insects. It takes for shots to complete destroy a mushroom. There are two type of mushrooms: Magic Mushrooms and Poisonous mushrooms. Magic mushrooms are the default mushrooms in the game and are also the the result of the player destroying an insect or Centipede body segment. Poisonous Mushrooms are the result of the Scorpion touching a mushroom. Poisonous Mushrooms will prompt the Centipede near it to move straight towards the player through any mushroom. Losing a wand will restore any partially damaged mushroom.

Game Difficulty and Variations
The game offers four difficulty levels: Novice, Standard, Advanced, and Expert. Game Variations are as the following:

1. One Player
Two Player Alternating
Two players will take turns when the active player is bitten.
Dual Player Competition
Two players will appear on the screen at the same time. Scoring is separate. Shots fired from one player will paralyze the other player.
Team Play
Two players will appear on the screen at the same time. Scoring is combined. Shots fired from one player will not paralyze the other player.

Scoring
The player will win a bonus magic wand for every 12,000 points to a maximum of six wands. The game will end when all wands are lost. Scoring are as the following:

Centipede Head - 100 points
Centipede Body Segment - 10 points
Spider at close range - 900 points
Spider at medium range - 600 points
Flea - 200 points
Scorpion - 1,000 points
Flea - 200 points
Restored mushroom - 5 points
Destroyed mushroom - 1 points</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter / Vehicle, 1st person,Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Existe el mismo ataque implacable de ciempiés, escorpiones, pulgas y arañas. Un jardín de hongos. Cambiando los colores de la pantalla con cada nuevo ciempiés. Y cada nuevo se vuelve más rápido. Entonces los puntos se vuelven más difíciles. Y si quieres puntos, puedes obtener 10 veces más disparando por la cabeza.</synopsis>
      <genre>Tiro / Vehículo 1ª persona,Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Jouer un exterminateur chargé de détruire les envahisseurs. À l'aide de votre arme, vous devez détruire les vagues de Centipèdes (mille-pattes) qui descendent vers vous du haut de l'écran. Des champignons sont éparpillés sur l'écran, et le Centipède descend d'une ligne chaque fois qu'il rencontre un champignon. Vous devez également éviter et détruire les araignées, les puces et les scorpions, et faites attention aux champignons empoisonnés qui pourraient faire descendre le Centipede en spirale à votre niveau. Détruisez le Centipède pour avancer à la prochaine vague...</synopsis>
      <genre>Tir / Véhicule, 1ere personne,Tir</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Shooter / Fahrzeug, 1st Pers.,Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Tiro / Carro 1ª Pessoa,Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="17">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Choplifter!">
    <id>37930A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Choplifter!</title>
      <synopsis>Choplifter is a side-scrolling action/arcade game that puts you in command of an attack chopper.  Your mission: Go behind enemy lines and rescue up to 16 hostages per level.  Be careful, though, because tanks and enemy aircraft will try to stop you -- and they won't stop shooting while you are rescuing those hostages!

Originally released for Apple II home computers, Choplifter was later ported to the arcades and a number of video game consoles.  Many imitators and homages would follow.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Brøderbund Software, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Midway Games West, Inc.</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="9">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Combat 2 Advanced">
    <id>37931A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Combat II Advanced</title>
      <synopsis>This is the game Combat Two ported to the Atari 5200 with additional features.

You still can use tanks to shoot each other but now you have game variations with helicopters, jet planes and submarines. Each vehicle has two weapon modes, a primary and secondary. Also, you can play with up to three friends, simultaneously.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Mean Hamster Software, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Mean Hamster Software, Inc.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Congo Bongo">
    <id>37932A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Congo Bongo</title>
      <synopsis>An extremely faithful port of the famous jump-n-run platform arcade game.  Run, jump, and climb your way through a dangerous jungle while avoiding various animals and projectiles.

Includes the introductory animations and features the arcade version's sliding screen transitions.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Préparer vous à l'aventure avec cet explorateur qui doit avancer dans sa quête. A chaque scène un gorille, d'autres animaux ou des crocodiles vous empêchent d'avancer en vous lançant divers projectiles ou en vous attaquant. Assez difficile mais durée courte du jeu.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="8">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Countermeasure">
    <id>37933A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Countermeasure</title>
      <synopsis>Terrorists have seized control of several missile silos and are planning on launching missiles to blow up Washington D.C. Your job is to stop them! From a top down point of view, you control a tank over varied, scrolling terrain. To stop the missiles, you have two options: you can destroy all of the missiles, or attempt to guess the fail safe code. If you try to destroy all the missiles, you must do so in under ten minutes. The missiles silos have many defenses which the terrorists also control; pillboxes, tanks, jeeps, and cruise missiles are all capable of destroying your tank. Should you attempt to guess the fail safe code, clues can be found by docking at supply depots. The code is three letters long, and can consist of any combination of L, E and O. When you enter a war room, you have a very short time to enter the code correctly or the missiles will launch. When the missiles have been stopped (by either means), the level is complete and you continue on to the next, more difficult round.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Los terroristas han tomadot el control de varios silos de misiles y planean lanzar misiles para destruir Washington D.C. ¡Su trabajo es detenerlos! Controlas un tanque sobre un terreno variado y desplazable. Para detener los misiles, tienes dos opciones: puedes destruir todos los misiles o intentar adivinar el código de seguridad. Si intenta destruir todos los misiles, debes hacerlo en menos de diez minutos. Los silos de misiles tienen muchas defensas que los terroristas también controlan; tanques, jeeps y misiles de crucero que son capaces de destruir el tanque. Si intentas adivinar el código de seguridad, las pistas se pueden encontrar atracando en los depósitos de suministros. El código tiene tres letras y puede consistir en cualquier combinación de L, E y O. Cuando ingresas en la sala de guerra, tienes muy poco tiempo para ingresar el código correctamente o se lanzan los misiles. Cuando los misiles han sido detenidos (por cualquier medio), el nivel está completo y continúas hacia la siguiente ronda aun más difícil.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Midway Games West, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Midway Games West, Inc.</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Pitfall 2 - Lost Caverns">
    <id>37967A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>David Crane's Pitfall II : Lost Caverns</title>
      <synopsis>You play Pitfall Harry searching for the Raj diamond, his niece Rhonda, and a variety of treasures somewhere in the Andes. Poisonous frogs, eels, scorpions, bats and other hazards get in the way. Pitfall II is the sequel to Pitfall, the original platform game. Gameplay has remained pretty much the same, with each screen presenting a side view of obstacles to get past, and potentially treasures to collect. The landscape is more maze like, with a variety of paths and dead ends to search. Along the way there are checkpoints the player will encounter. When the player dies, Pitfall Harry will be sent back to the most recently crossed checkpoint.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción,Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action,Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action,Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Ação,Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Defender">
    <id>37934A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Defender</title>
      <synopsis>Defender put players in charge of a ship sent to protect mankind from wave after wave of attacking alien forces.

Armed with "smart bombs", and the ability to use hyperspace to move quickly around the planet, the player ship must fight against Bombers, Pods, Swarmers, Baiters, and Landers - that can capture the humanoids and transform them into deadly and relentless Mutants.  Fail to save the humanoids from freefall or Mutant transformation, and the planet is destroyed.

Eugene Jarvis'  Defender has been widely regarded as one of the most popular and addictive space shooters of the early 1980's</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Defender puso a los jugadores a cargo de una nave enviada para proteger a la humanidad de una oleada tras otra de fuerzas alienígenas atacantes.nnnnArmado con "bombas inteligentes" y la capacidad de usar el hiperespacio para moverse rápidamente por el planeta, la nave del jugador debe luchar contra Bombers, Pods, Swarmers, Baiters y Landers, que pueden capturar a los humanos y transformarlos en mutantes mortales e implacables.nnSi no se salvan a los humanos de caer o de ser transformados en Mutantes, el planeta se destruye.nnnnDefensor de Eugene Jarvis ha sido ampliamente considerado como uno de los tiradores espaciales más populares y adictivos de principios de los 80</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Defendez-vous des ennemis qui envahissent votre espace aérien. Grace à votre radar vous pouvez les localiser rapidement. De plus, ne laisser pas les ennemis enlever des habitants.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Williams Electronics Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Dig Dug">
    <id>37935A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Dig Dug</title>
      <synopsis>Dig Dug is a 1-2 player arcade game in which you have to use your shovel to dig your way through the earth. Stopping you from doing this are two monsters, called Pooka and Fygar, who will continually chase you around. The only weapon that you carry is an air pump, which you can use to inflate the monsters to the point where they explode. (if you start to inflate them but stop doing so, the monsters will get turned back to their normal selves.) Furthermore, rocks are scattered throughout the earth, and you can use these rocks to squash them. If the monsters do not find you for several seconds, they will eventually get turned into ghosts, which are able to walk through the earth. They are invincible and cannot be killed. From time to time, vegetables will appear in the center, and you can get these for points.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Dig Dug es un juego de arcade para 1-2 jugadores en el que debes usar tu pala para abrirte paso en la tierra. Trataran de detenerte dos monstruos, llamados Pooka y Fygar, que continuamente te perseguirán. La única arma que llevas es una bomba de aire, que puedes utilizar para inflar los monstruos hasta que exploten. (Si comienzas a inflarlos pero dejas de hacerlo, los monstruos volverán a su estado normal). Además, hay rocas que están dispersas por toda la tierra, y puedes usar estas rocas para aplastarlos. Si los monstruos no te encuentran se convertirán en fantasmas, que pueden atravesar la tierra. Son invencibles. De vez en cuando, apareceran verduras en el centro, y puedes obtenerlas para obtener mas puntos.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Dig Dug, quel nom bizarre mais quel bon jeu. Vous etes une sorte de taupe qui creuse des trous, et qui doit eviter de ce faire manger par des autres betes. Et votre seule arme est de tirer la langue pour les avaler.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <synopsis>Die Spielfigur gräbt sich durch die Erde und muss mit Hilfe einer Pumpe die Widersacher zum Platzen bringen. Die Alternative ist es sie mit einem Fels zu zerquetschen. Neben den normalen Feinden, den Pookas, welche bei Berührung töten, gibt es auch noch besonders fiese, Fygar genannt. Die Fygars können Feuer speien, sogar durch das Erdreich hindurch. Gibt man einem Pooka oder Fygar genug Zeit, so verwandeln sie sich in einen Geist und das Erdreich ist für sie kein Hinderniss mehr. Erreichen sie dabei einen Tunnel, so nehmen sie wieder Gestalt an.
Man schaut auf einen Querschnitt eines Stücks Erdreich. Darin sind Hohlräume, in denen sich Gegner befinden. Außerdem gibt es Steine die herunterfallen, wenn die Erde unter ihnen weggegraben wird. </synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Final Legacy">
    <id>44444A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Final Legacy</title>
      <synopsis>This is a battle on three fronts. You are the captain of the ship Legacy. Your ultimate goal is to destroy the Warmongers' missile bases but you must also protect your cities.

You begin the game in command mode. You select your other modes with the joystick. Up for navigation, down for torpedo, left for sea-to-air and right for sea-to-land.

The Atari 5200 version of this game was never released but is however mostly identical to the Atari 8-Bit version that was released.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Esta es una batalla a tres bandas. Eres el capitán del barco Legacy. Tu objetivo final es destruir las bases de misiles Warmongers, pero también debes proteger tus ciudades. Comienzas el juego en modo comando. Puedes seleccionar sus otros modos con el joystick. Arriba para navegación, abajo para torpedo, izquierda para mar-aire y derecha para mar-tierra. La versión Atari 5200 de este juego nunca se lanzó, pero es más parecida a la versión Atari 8-Bit que se lanzó.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Frisky Tom">
    <id>44445A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Frisky Tom</title>
      <synopsis>A prototype game that was never officially released for the Atari 5200, Frisky Tom is a port of the obscure Nichibutsu coin-op of the same name in which you play a plumber who must climb up and fix broken pipes to keep a steady stream of water flowing from the tank at the top of the screen to the reservoir at the bottom.  Unfortunately this house is infested with mice which roam the screen, gnawing through pipes and generally causing problems for our man Tom.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Frogger">
    <id>37937A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Frogger</title>
      <synopsis>Your task in this arcade conversion is to guide a frog across a treacherous road and river, and to safety at the top of the screen. Both these sections are fraught with a variety of hazards, each of which will kill the frog and cost you a life if contact is made.

The road is full of cars and trucks, at variable speeds. The river water itself is fatal, as are the snakes which hover within on later levels. Frogger must use the arrangement of logs, turtles (which are only there for a short time) and alligators (but stay away form their faces), and then jump into one of the open home-cells, ideally one containing a fly for extra points. Once all holes have been filled, you move onto the next, harder, level.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>El objetivo en esta conversión arcade es guiar a una rana a través de una carretera y un río traicioneros a la seguridad en la parte superior de la pantalla. Ambas secciones están llenas de peligros, cada uno de los cuales matará a la rana y perderemos una vida.nnnnEl camino está lleno de automóviles y camiones, a diferentes velocidades. El agua del río en sí es fatal(ironico), al igual que las serpientes que flotan en niveles posteriores. Frogger debe usar los troncos, las tortugas (que solo están allí por un corto tiempo) y los caimanes (pero quédate lejos de sus caras), y luego saltar a una de las celdas vacias, a ser posible una que contenga una mosca para puntos extra.nnnnUna vez que todos los agujeros se hayan llenado, pasará al nivel siguiente, mas dificil que el anterior.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Vous êtes incarné en grenouille (eh oui il y a mieux mais il y a pire aussi) qui doit traverser la route en évitant les voitures et ensuite traverser la rivière sur des troncs d'arbres. Amusant quelques minutes.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Frogger 2 - Threeedeep!">
    <id>37938A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Frogger II : Threeedeep!</title>
      <synopsis>In Frogger II, you need to guide your frog to safety in three different locations. Starting out underwater, reach the top of the pond while avoiding dangerous alligators and fish (you can ride a turtle for safety!). Once on top of the pond, hop across logs, birds, and even a whale to the life preserver trailing behind a tugboat. In the third location you have to hop across a flock of birds to reach a cloud at the top of the screen. Each frog has a time limit to safely reach one of the homes on each of the three screens. You move on to the next level when a frog has safely reached each of the homes on all screens.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>El objetivo de Frogger II es maniobrar cada rana en una litera en la parte superior de la pantalla. Una vez que se llenan todas las literas, el jugador pasa al siguiente nivel. A diferencia de su predecesor, el juego presenta tres pantallas consecutivas para cada nivel en lugar de una pantalla por nivel, con literas en la parte superior de cada una de las tres pantallas que deben llenarse.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Le but de Frogger II est de manoeuvrer chaque grenouille vers une couchette en haut de l'écran. Une fois que toutes les couchettes sont remplies, le joueur passe au niveau suivant. Contrairement à son prédécesseur, le jeu comporte trois écrans consécutifs pour chaque niveau plutôt qu'un écran par niveau, avec des couchettes en haut de chacun des trois écrans qui doivent être remplis.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Parker Brothers</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="17">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Galaxian">
    <id>37939A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Galaxian</title>
      <synopsis>Galaxian is a shoot 'em up in which the player is at the bottom of the screen, with an arrangement of aliens at the top. The player moves left and right to aim at an alien, then shoots a bullet up the screen, and the alien it hits is killed. The aliens are classed as Drones, Emissaries, Hornets and Commanders, with those higher up the screen scoring more points when destroyed. At set intervals an enemy will move down the screen towards you, escorting a bomber, which is a moment of high danger. Clear a wave and another is generated.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Vous êtes un petit vaisseau, et vous devez détruire les autres vaisseaux qui descendent sur vous. C'est un des tout premiers jeux de ''combats aériens'', et peut être le meilleur...</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Gorf">
    <id>37940A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Gorf</title>
      <synopsis>Gorf is a game similar to Space Invaders, alien vessels approach closer and closer in their threatening row formation.

The game itself consists of four levels:

1. The first level has you behind a defensive shield, defending against an alien attack. The level is a top-down view, with your ship &amp; shield on one side and the aliens on the other side;

The second level is similar to the first, only your defensive shield is gone, and the enemies tend to swoop down over the level as opposed to those row formations. Bonus ships also tend to appear in this level;

The third level is a change, and has you entering hyperspace. Your only goal is to survive to the end of your journey. The viewpoint switches from a top-down view to a behind-the-ship view and in effect you are heading "towards" your destination. Alien vessels flying in circular formation try to stop you;

The fourth and final level is similar to the first again, with some key differences. You do not fight a wave of enemies, but a single one. A mothership with a glowing weak spot. Hitting the weak spot will instantly destroy it. The mothership also has that same shield that was yours in the first level.

Finishing the game increases your rank and starts the game over at level 1 with a faster game speed for more challenge.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Bally Midway</developer>
    <publisher>CBS Electronics</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Gremlins">
    <id>37941A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Gremlins</title>
      <synopsis>Gremlins is an action game based on the Steven Spielberg movie of the same name. The game takes place just after midnight when there are Gremlins and Mogwai running around Billy's living room!

You control Billy from a 3rd person point of view. On each level, your goal is to catch all of the Mogwai and return them to their cage (located in the upper right corner of the screen) and to destroy all of the Gremlins with a sword. Each level has a time limit - at 6:00 am when the sun rises. You move on to the next level by completing your tasks or just surviving until 6:00, although more points are awarded for the former. You will also receive bonus points for each Mogwai returned to the cage. 

On many of the levels there will be various types of food lying about the screen. If a Mogwai eats any food, it will turn into a gremlin. There may also be  puddles of water; if a Gremlin or Mogwai runs into the water, it will split into two. Some levels also contain a refrigerator or popcorn machine which will throw food out onto the screen, or a television which will distract the Gremlins. 

You also begin the game with a limited number of flash cubes; if you get into trouble, you can use these to temporarily stun all of the Gremlins and Mogwai. As the levels progress gameplay becomes faster and the Gremlins and Mogwai more numerous.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>¿Quién no conoce a estos pequeños hámsters que nos aterrorizaban siendo pequeños? Si recuerdas, los pequeños relojes que comen después de la medianoche se vuelven infernales y se multiplican en contacto con el agua. Bueno, están de vuelta. . . En un juego que me hace pensar un poco '' Zelda ''. Buen juego para descargar.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Qui ne connaît pas ces gentils petits hamsters qui nous terrorisaient étant petits? Si rappelez-vous, les petits montres qui sils mangent après minuit deviennent infernaux et se multiplient au contact de leau. Et bien là, ils sont de retour . . . Dans un jeu qui me fait penser un peu a ''Zelda''. Bon jeu a télécharger.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="18">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Gyruss">
    <id>37942A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Gyruss</title>
      <synopsis>The entire solar system is being attacked by the vicious Gyrusians, and it's up to you to save the day! You will need to fly your spaceship to each of the nine planets and then clear three stages of enemies to rid that planet of the Gyrusians. You start the game with a single canon, and can gain a double canon after shooting a power up satelite. After clearing each planet, there is another bonus stage where additional weapons and bonus points can be collected. Gyruss is an arcade action shooter, however instead of piloting your spaceship horizontally or vertically, you move in a circle around the perimeter of the screen. The NES version of Gyruss adds to the original arcade version additional music, additional weapons, new enemies, and a large boss at the end of each level.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter / Run and Shoot,Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Tiro / Corre y Dispara,Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Vous devez rejoindre la terre et avancer de planètes en planètes avant d'y parvenir. Vos déplacements sont circulaires sur tout l'écran et vous permettent d'éliminer vos assaillants et autres météorites. Un fois les ennemis détruits, vous passez à une autre planète. Bonne route.</synopsis>
      <genre>Tir / A pied,Tir</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Shooter / Run and Shoot,Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Tiro / Corra e Atire,Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="9">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="H.e.r.o.">
    <id>37944A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>H.E.R.O.</title>
      <synopsis>There is trouble in the mines! Volcanic activity has trapped numerous miners, and it is your job to save them. As Roderick Hero, you need to make your way through the dangerous mineshaft avoiding the dangerous creatures and lava, and find out where the miners are located before you run out of energy. To help on your mission, Roderick Hero has several useful types of equipment. A prop pack will allow you to hover and fly around the mineshaft and (hopefully) avoid the many dangers within. Your helmet features a short range microlaser beam which can be used to destroy the bats, spiders, snakes, and other creatures you'll encounter in the mines. From time to time, your path through the mine may be blocked by stone or lava walls. You begin each mission with six sticks of dynamite which can be used to destroy these obstacles (be careful you don't blow yourself up, though!) If you run out of dynamite, your laser beam can also be used to destroy the walls, though this will take longer and use up more energy. As the levels progress, the mine shaft will become longer and more maze-like, creatures will more frequently block the path, and lava walls and pools will appear which are dangerous to the touch.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>¡Hay problemas en las minas! La actividad volcánica ha atrapado a numerosos mineros, y tu trabajo es salvarlos. Como Roderick Hero, tienes que atravesar el peligroso pozo minero evitando las criaturas y la lav para descubrir dónde están los mineros antes de que te quedes sin energía. Para ayudarlo en su misión, Roderick Hero tiene varios tipos de equipos útiles. Un paquete que te permitirá flotar y volar alrededor del pozo de extracción y (con suerte) evitar los muchos peligros que existen dentro. Su casco cuenta con un rayo microlaser de corto alcance que puede usarse para destruir murciélagos, arañas, serpientes y otras criaturas que encontrará en las minas. De vez en cuando, su camino a través de la mina puede ser bloqueado por muros de piedra o de lava. Empiezas cada misión con seis cartuchos de dinamita que pueden usarse para destruir estos obstáculos (¡ten cuidado de no volverte loco!) Si te quedas sin dinamita, tu rayo láser también puede usarse para destruir las paredes, aunque esto tomará más tiempo y consumirá más energía. A medida que los niveles progresan, el pozo de la mina se alargará y, con más laberintos, las criaturas bloquearán con más frecuencia el camino, y sera mas dificil.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Haunted House 2 3d">
    <id>37943A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Haunted House II 3D</title>
      <synopsis>This is an updated version of the game Haunted House with a three dimensional perspective to the rooms.

You enter a mansion with thirty or sixty rooms, depending of your selection. You are searching for treasure but beware of the ghosts and creeps that haunt the mansion. You can turn on a light in any rooms to find hidden items. Somewhere in the maze of rooms is a sword that will make you immune to most bad guys. Once you have the treasure, make your way to the south wall of the starting point to exit and win.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Mean Hamster Software, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Mean Hamster Software, Inc.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="2002" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="James Bond 007">
    <id>37945A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>James Bond 007</title>
      <synopsis>In James Bond 007 you control James Bond in his multi purpose craft. This craft can travel on both land and sea, can jump over danger, or fire at enemies on the many different levels. Each horizontally scrolling level in the game is loosely based on a different James Bond movie. The levels included are Diamonds Are Forever, The Spy Who Loved Me, Moonraker, and For Your Eyes Only. Each level has a variety of enemies trying to destroy you, and a unique goal that must be accomplished to continue on (for example, you may have to land on a hidden oil rig to stop Seraffino, or find Stromberg's undersea laboratory and destroy it). If you can complete all the missions, you win the game! Good luck, Mr. Bond.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Parker Brothers</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="6">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Joust">
    <id>37946A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Joust</title>
      <synopsis>In Joust, players take control of a knight with a lance who rides their flying ostrich (or stork, for Player 2) to do battle against computer-controlled evil knights who ride atop vultures.

Players must flap their steed's wings to hit the enemy from a higher jousting point to destroy the vulture and its rider. Once the enemy has been hit, an egg falls to one of the platforms below. The heroic knights must destroy the eggs before they hatch and release new and increasingly more difficult knights. The three strengths of enemy knights are Bounder (red knight), Hunter (white knight), and Shadow Lord (blue knight). These enemy knights are not the only challenge to be found in the game. Players must also contend with crumbling platforms, lava trolls who attempt to pull knights into the fire, and the dreaded "unbeatable"(?) pterodactyl.

The game was novel for its time for being one of the few two-player simultaneous games in the arcade.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>En jOUST, el jugador controla a un caballero amarillo que monta una avestruz o una cigüeña voladora, desde el punto de vista de la tercera persona, en medio de las plataformas de roca flotante y por encima de las cuencas de lava. El objetivo es derrotar Grupos de caballeros enemigos que montan boquillas que pueblan cada nivel, llamadas "ola". Al final de una ola, comienza una ola más fuerte subsiguiente. El juego presenta tres tipos de caballeros enemigos, Bounder, Hunter y Shadow Lord, que valen diferentes cantidades de puntos. Un pterodáctilo casi indestructible aparece después de un tiempo predeterminado para perseguir a los héroes, como incentivo para completar el nivel. Un segundo jugador puede unirse al juego.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Dans jOUST, Le joueur contrôle un chevalier jaune chevauchant une autruche ou une cigogne volante , du point de vue de la troisième personne,au milieu des plates-formes rocheuses flottantes et au-dessus des bassins de lave.L'objectif est de vaincre des groupes de chevaliers ennemis qui montent des buses qui peuplent chaque niveau, appelé «vague». À la fin d'une vague, une vague subséquente plus difficile commence. Le jeu propose trois types de chevaliers ennemis - Bounder, Hunter et Shadow Lord - qui valent différentes quantités de points. Un ptérodactyle presque indestructible apparaît après un laps de temps prédéterminé pour chasser les héros, comme une incitation à compléter le niveau.Un deuxième joueur peut rejoindre la partie</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Williams Electronics Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="17">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Jr. Pac-man">
    <id>44446A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Jr. Pac-Man</title>
      <synopsis>Jr.Pac-Man was never released for the Atari 5200, however a prototype does exist. In this Pac-man spin off you now take control of junior who has to contend with much more than his parents did! The mazes are so large now they require the screen to scroll. On top of that the items that appear will cause the dots to enlarge. This gives Junior more points when he eats them but also slows him down a bit making it difficult to avoid the ghosts. What's worse is if they hit a power pellet they will destroy it!

Like other Pac-Man games intermissions are shown between levels. They mainly have to do with Junior and a ghost girl falling in love despite their parents disapproval.</synopsis>
      <genre>Arcade</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari Inc.</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Jum's Pong">
    <id>123004</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Jum's Pong</title>
      <genre>Action</genre>
      <synopsis>A Simple 2 player Pong game.

Fun for a while.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Jum</publisher>
    <date year="2000" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Jum</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Jungle Hunt">
    <id>37947A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Jungle Hunt</title>
      <synopsis>Jungle Hunt offers four unique adventure experiences, which repeat with greater difficulty once all four have been survived.  If you don't survive these adventures, you will not only lose your own life but that of the lovely Penelope, who has been captured by cannibals!

The first part challenges your Tarzan skills - can you swing on the vines without plummeting to your doom?  The second part pits you against a whole bunch of nasty crocodiles in a mighty river.  Fortunately, you have a knife to fight back with.  Don't forget to go up for air!  In the third part, you face a battle against oncoming boulders of varying sizes and physics.  Once you've cleared all these treacherous hazards, you still must confront the dreaded cannibal, who is armed with a wicked spear.  Can you get past him and save the lovely Penelope?

Gameplay involves much strategic jumping and knife play (in the river/crocodile phase).  The view is always a side view, much like Pitfall! and later platform games.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="K-razy Shoot-out">
    <id>37953A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>K-Razy Shoot-Out</title>
      <synopsis>K-Razy Shootout is an arcade action game similar to Berzerk. You are in a maze filled with dangerous robots. Your goal is to shoot as many of the robots as you can to earn points. If you collide with a robot, robot fire, or the maze walls you lose a life. The game ends when all of your reserve lives have been lost. Each sector of the game has a timer bar; if you complete a sector while the bar is in the green or yellow section, bonus points are earned. If the timer runs out, you lose a life. Each sector will have one or more exits in the maze; you may exit a maze at any time, but if you leave before all of the robots are destroyed then you will have to go back two sectors.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>K-Byte</developer>
    <publisher>CBS Electronics</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Kaboom!">
    <id>37948A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Kaboom!</title>
      <synopsis>The mad bomber is on the loose! As he races back and forth at the top  of the screen, you need to catch the bombs he drops in buckets of water. One point is earned for each bomb caught, but miss one of the bombs, and Kaboom! As the levels progress, the mad bomber will move faster and faster and drop more and more bombs. You start the game with three buckets, and lose one each time a bomb is missed. The game ends when all of your water buckets are gone.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>¡El loco bombardero anda suelto! Mientras corre de un lado a otro en la parte superior de la pantalla, debes atrapar las bombas que deja caer en cubos de agua. Se gana un punto por cada bomba atrapada, pero si se caen...., ¡Kaboom! A medida que los niveles progresan, el bombardero loco se moverá más y más rápido y lanzará más y más bombas. Comienzas el juego con tres cubos y pierdes uno cada vez que se pierde una bomba. El juego termina pierdas todos los cubos.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Kangaroo">
    <id>37949A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Kangaroo</title>
      <synopsis>Baby Roo has been kidnapped by monkeys, and it's up to Mama Roo to come to the rescue! Your kangaroo starts out at the bottom of the screen. You need to guide the kangaroo up the various ladders and platforms to the top where Baby Roo is being held captive. The monkeys will be trying to stop you by throwing or dropping apples and knocking you off the platforms. Your kangaroo has boxing gloves, however, and can knock out the monkeys with a single punch! Along the way various types of fruit can be collected to earn bonus points.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Sun Electronics Corp.</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Keystone Kapers">
    <id>37950A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Keystone Kapers</title>
      <synopsis>The notorious thief Harry Hooligan is on the loose! You play the part of Officer Keystone Kelly, sent in to capture Harry. Harry is trapped in a four story mall, and is running as fast as he can to reach the exit at the top. Your job is to catch up to him and send him to prison. You will need to use either the escalators at the end of each floor, or the elevator in the middle to go from floor to floor. The escalators may be further away, but the elevator moves pretty slowly so you will need to decide which route will be faster in getting you closer to your goal. If Harry can make it to the top before you catch him, you will have to retry that level. Harry has no intention of letting you catch him easily, and is hurling everything he can find in an attempt to slow you down. Shopping carts, bouncing balls, biplanes, and more will all be flying past on the screen and will either slow you down or send you back to the beginning if you get hit. As the levels progress, Harry will run faster and faster, and more objects will be tossed your way to duck and jump over.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Harry está atrapado en un centro comercial de cuatro pisos, y corre rápido a medida que avanza. Tu trabajo es ponerse al día con él y enviarlo a prisión. Deberá usar las escaleras mecánicas al final de cada piso, o el elevador en el medio para ir de un piso a otro. Las escaleras mecánicas pueden estar más lejos, pero el elevador se mueve y estará mucho más cerca de su objetivo. Si Harry puede llegar a la cima antes de que lo atrapes, tendrás que volver a intentar ese nivel. Harry no tiene intención de dejarte atraparlo fácilmente, y está lanzando todo lo que puede encontrar en un intento de ralentizarte. Carritos de compras, pelotas que rebotan, biplanos y más volarán hacia ti.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="17">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Klax">
    <id>37951A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Klax</title>
      <synopsis>An action/puzzle game, the object is to catch assorted color falling tiles and create rows, columns, or diagonals of a single color. Each level requires a different pattern to be made, and the tiles fall faster, more at a time, and in an increasing number of colors as the game progresses.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Ação,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari2600.com</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Koffi - Yellow Kopter">
    <id>37952A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Koffi : Yellow Kopter</title>
      <synopsis>Koffi is a little kopter so when the emergencies came, the big kopters wouldn't let him go. But now he has heard that Pyro the thundercloud is using lightning to start fires in the forest. The fire needs to be put out, the animals need saving. Koffi wasn't allowed to help the big kopters but he can't just ignore this until they return.

You, as Koffi, must gather water from the raindrops or snowflakes and destroy Pyro. You destroy him by bumping into him but watch out for his lightning. After Pyro is gone, you must hover close to the fire then press your button to release water to put out. If you don't have enough water, grab more raindrops or snowflakes but don't delay or the fire will rage out of control. You can get bonus points by shoving the animal under the trees off the screen. The forest areas are mountain valley, coniferous forest and windy vines, where you have to watch that you are not blown into lightning. After you clear the three forest areas, you must face Pyro's mom, and she is not happy that you beat up on her son. You kill her the same way as her son but she throws longer and faster lightning and there is an angry cloud moving up and down and slowly towards you. Once she is dead, you restart mountain valley at a harder level.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>2002</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Ron Lloyd</developer>
    <date year="2003" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Looney Tunes Hotel">
    <id>44448A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Looney Tunes Hotel</title>
      <synopsis>Looney Tunes Hotel was a nearly completed video game that was going to be released for the Atari 5200. Players were to play on a set of hotels, but Atari never got to finishing the game.</synopsis>
      <genre>Platform,Stealth</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Mario Bros.">
    <id>37954A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Mario Bros.</title>
      <synopsis>Mario and Luigi, the best plumbers in the world, have a real job on their hands. A host of characters have taken over the sewers, and the brothers must clear them out of the pipes.

The platform puzzle which first introduced Luigi to the world has both single and multiplayer action with two differing game types, but with the same objective.
Crabs, turtles and fighter flies must be cleared out by jumping underneath the platform they sit on, then kicking them away. Each level is cleared when a set number of coins is collected.

For the two player mode, the first to collect the set amount of coins wins.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Mario Bros. est un jeu de plateforme d'abord sorti en arcade puis porté sur NES, Atari 2600 et bien d'autres machines. C'est l'occasion de rencontrer Luigi pour la première fois.

Dans ce jeu, jouable à 2 simultanément, on doit débarrasser les égouts de vilaines créatures en les renversant puis en leur donnant un coup de pied. Seuls les Shellcreepers persisteront dans l'univers de Mario en devenant les Koopas.

Le jeu est très amusant à 2 car on peut jouer en coopération ou se faire des crasses entre joueurs comme se placer sous une créature renversée pour la réactiver au moment où l'autre joueur va pour lui donner un coup de pied.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Nintendo</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Meebzork">
    <id>44449A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Meebzork</title>
      <synopsis>An unfinished prototype game that was originally planned as a shooter but the last available version ends up being more an action/adventure game. There is an early build available of the shooter as well.

You are a warrior named Meebzork who can practice or play through 6 different levels (not including another level that was going to be after you completed a board and would allow you to choose a next one). All 6 levels are different in what they require. While unfinished and unpolished you can see a lot of potential.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Megamania">
    <id>37955A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>MegaMania</title>
      <synopsis>Megamania is an arcade action game with gameplay similar to Space Invaders. You control a spaceship at the bottom of the screen and need to defend yourself from numerous waves of attackers. But in Megamania, the attackers much more bizarre than invading aliens. There are hamburgers, diamonds, steam irons, bow ties, space dice, and more! You need to earn points by destroying as many of these strange attackers as you can before your energy supply becomes depleted.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Meteorites">
    <id>37956A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Meteorites</title>
      <synopsis>Meteorites is an arcade action game featuring gameplay similar to Asteroids. You control a spaceship surrounded by numerous asteroids; your goal is to destroy them! Each time you shoot an asteroid, it will break up into smaller asteroids. Eventually the pieces will be small enough that you can destroy them. When you have destroyed all of the asteroids, you will move on to the next, more difficult level. To make the game more difficult, a flying saucer will also appear from time to time and try to shoot your spaceship. To get out of trouble quickly, your spaceship also may enter hyperspace transporting you to a new location on the screen. Be careful, though, sometimes the new location is worse than the one you left!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Electra Concepts International Corp.</developer>
    <publisher>Electra Concepts International Corp.</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="10">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Microgammon Sb">
    <id>44450A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Microgammon SB</title>
      <synopsis>Microgammon SB originally started out as an Apple IIe game.  According to programmer Steve Baker, he had originally developed the game for the Apple when he decided to port it to the Atari 5200.  Since the 5200 possessed a high resolution mode that was on par with the Apple's, the conversion was pretty straightforward.  However one side effect of using the 5200's high-res mode was that the graphics were in black &amp; white only.  However most players find that this really doesn't distract much from the game since it uses black and white pieces anyway.</synopsis>
      <genre>Traditional</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari Inc.</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Millipede">
    <id>44451A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Millipede</title>
      <synopsis>An unreleased prototype conversion of the arcade game Millipede. It was completed but never released due to Atari abandoning the 5200 near it's completion.

The goal is to survive wave after wave of various insects while trying to destroy a Millipede that makes its way down the screen towards your player. While very similar to Centipede it adds quite a few new quirks such as new insects to contend with and DDT bombs that when shot will destroy what is around them.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Miner 2049er">
    <id>37957A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Miner 2049er Starring Bounty Bob</title>
      <synopsis>You play the part of Bounty Bob, and it is your mission to explore every inch of an abandoned mine. As you walk over floor sections in the mine, the floor will change color. When all of the floor sections have been changed in color, you can move on to the next, more challenging level. To reach all of the floor sections, you will need to figure out how to get there! You can jump (be careful not to fall too far though, or you will be squished), climb up and down ladders, and use different transportation devices that can be found on the levels (such as an elevator, slides, a springboard, or a canon!) Wandering around the mine are numerous radioactive creatures which get in Bounty Bobs way. Also scattered throughout the mines are various artifacts left behind; if Bounty Bob collects one of these, the creatures will temporarily become vulnerable. If Bounty Bob runs into one of the creatures in this state the creature will be destroyed, but if he runs into a creature while it is glowing Bounty Bob will be destroyed! There is a total of ten different levels, and to complete them all you will need quick reflexes as well as figure out a unique strategy for each level.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Eres Bounty Bob, y tu misión es explorar cada centímetro de una mina abandonada. nnAl caminar por las secciones del piso de la mina, el piso cambiará de color. Cuando todas las secciones del piso han cambiado de color, puede pasar al siguiente nivel, con mayor dificultad.nnnnPara llegar a todas las secciones del piso, tendrás que descubrir cómo llegar allí. Puedes saltar (tenga cuidado con la altura, o le aplastarán), subir y bajar escaleras, y usar diferentes dispositivos de transporte que se pueden encontrar en los niveles (como un elevador, toboganes, un trampolín o ¡un cañon!).nnnnVagando alrededor de la mina hay numerosas criaturas radiactivas que ataracar a Bounty Bobs. También dispersos por las minas hay varios artefactos que le ayudaran; si Bounty Bob recolecta uno de estos, las criaturas se volverán vulnerables por un corto periodo de tiempo.Si Bounty Bob se encuentra con una de las criaturas en este estado, la criatura será destruida, pero !No las toque cuando brille! o Bounty Bob será destruido.nnnnHay un total de diez niveles diferentes, y para completarlos necesitarás reflejos rápidos y una estrategia única para cada nivel.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Le joueur contrôle Bounty Bob, un personnage qui explore les profondeurs d'une mine souterraine dans un futur radioactif. Il peut gratter le sol en marchant et doit esquiver ou écraser les monstres irradiés qui le côtoient. Les niveaux sont formés de poutres, d'échelles, de plates-formes coulissantes et de téléporteurs. Le joueur doit gratter chaque bout de sol pour atteindre le niveau suivant. Le jeu en compte dix ou onze selon la version</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Big Five Software</developer>
    <publisher>Big Five Software</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="20">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Miniature Golf">
    <id>44452A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Miniature Golf</title>
      <synopsis>Unreleased prototype game by Steve Baker for the Atari 5200. However it was completed and is fully playable. Due to the Hi-Res mode used the game has some odd choices for colors but other than that is quite well done and simulates Miniature Golf very well. 

Control is handled entirely by the keypad, so the non-centering 5200 joystick doesn't hinder the gameplay.  Pushing the # and * keys changes the direction the ball will be hit (represented by an arrow) and the 1-9 keys are used to indicate the power of the swing (1=lowest and 9=highest).</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Missile Command">
    <id>37958A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Missile Command</title>
      <synopsis>Aliens from the planet of Krytol are attacking your cities!! As the commander of a missile base, it is your responsibility to defend them. A variety of enemy weapons and planes will be incoming trying to destroy the six cities at the bottom of the screen. You need to fire missiles to destroy the incoming weapons. If anything gets through, one of your cities could be destroyed. When all of the cities are gone, the game is over. On each level you have a limited amount of ammo, so make sure most (if not all) of your shots are accurate or you could run out of ammo and leave your cities at risk! As the levels progress, there are more and more enemy weapons to destroy which come in at an increasingly faster rate.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="15">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Montezuma's Revenge">
    <id>37959A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Montezuma's Revenge featuring Panama Joe</title>
      <synopsis>You play as a treasure hunter named Panama Joe, whose goal is to find an ancient treasure hidden by Aztec warrior  deep inside catacombs. But beware, the catacombs are a large maze inhabited by monsters. Bouncing and rolling skulls, dancing spiders, disappearing and re-appearing chains and tons of fire await you. You'll have to find many keys and unlock doors in order to reach your goal. Panama Joe can jump and climb ladders, but doesn't have much to offer in terms of combat. That's why the monsters in the game should be avoided: a collision with an enemy leads to a premature death.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Parker Brothers</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Moon Patrol">
    <id>37960A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Moon Patrol</title>
      <synopsis>The moon is under attack from a horde of aliens, and you must stop them in your armed buggy. Drive along the surface shooting the aliens and avoiding their bullets. The surface is not flat, there are craters and rocks to avoid contact with, and landmines on the surface. Flying saucers create new craters when they crash. The 25 restart points are letter-coded.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>El jugador controla un vehículo terrestre en entornos lunares vistos de perfil. El vehículo se mueve a la derecha de la pantalla y el objetivo es eliminar los platillos voladores y los tanques enemigos. El terminal arcade tiene un joystick de dos vías (para cambiar la velocidad del vehículo) y dos botones: uno para disparar (el vehículo tiene un barril dirigido hacia adelante y otro dirigido hacia la parte superior), el otra para volar el vehículo (para evitar los cráteres, las minas y otros bloques de rocas presentes en el curso).</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Le joueur contrôle un véhicule terrestre dans des environnements lunaires visualisés de profil. Le véhicule se déplace vers la droite de l'écran et le but est d'éliminer les soucoupes volantes et les tanks ennemis qui se présentent. La borne d'arcade présente un joystick à deux directions (pour modifier la vitesse du véhicule) et deux boutons : l'un pour tirer (le véhicule possède un canon dirigé vers l'avant et un autre dirigé vers le dessus), l'autre pour faire sauter le véhicule (afin de contourner les cratères, mines et autres blocs de roches présents sur le parcours).</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Irem</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="18">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Mountain King">
    <id>37961A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Mountain King</title>
      <synopsis>Deep within a multi platformed diamond mine is a valuable crown. Your goal is to locate and retrieve the crown, then make it to the top of the mine alive! There are several steps that need to be completed before you can retrieve the crown. First you need to collect enough diamonds to earn 1,000 points. After you have enough points, you need to locate the flame spirit which is hidden somewhere within the mine. Since the mine is rather dark, you carry a flashlight with you which can be used to locate objects (such as treasure chests full of diamonds and the flame spirit.) Once you have the flame spirit, you need to find the entrance to the temple the crown is in. Offer the flame spirit to the skull spirit guarding the entrance, and you can get in and take the crown. Once you have the crown, you need to make it to the top of the mine before time runs out. To make this task more challenging, numerous cave bats fly around which can steal the crown. If this happens, you need to begin again! At the very bottom of the mine is a deadly spider; if you're not careful while exploring this region of the mine, you could become caught in it's web and be eaten. Each level has a time limit, and the more levels you complete the shorter the time limit becomes!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>E.F. Dreyer, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>CBS Electronics</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Mr. Do!'s Castle">
    <id>37962A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Mr. Do!'s Castle</title>
      <synopsis>Mr. Do!'s Castle is an action platform game which has you in a castle consisting of several floors, each of which contain a variety of blocks. You control Mr. Do! the clown who has a hammer which can be used to knock out the blocks in the floor. Wandering throughout the castle are deadly unicorns which are constantly trying to catch you. Your goal is to earn as many points as possible and to progress through the increasingly difficult castles. 

There are two ways to complete a castle; you can either destroy all of the deadly unicorns by crushing them with blocks, or you can knock out all of the blocks which have a cherry symbol on them. In addition to the cherry blocks, there are three blocks with a key. If all three key blocks are knocked out, the door on the roof of the castle unlocks. If you make it to the door, all of the unicorns will temporarily become harmless and will contain a letter. If you hit a letter unicorn, you will earn a letter in the word EXTRA. Spell the complete word, and you will earn an extra life. 

The last type of block you'll encounter has a skull on it. If you knock out two skull blocks, all of the blocks between them will also be knocked out and replaced with a bridge. As the castles progress, the castle layout will become trickier and the unicorns become faster and more numerous.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Universal Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Ms. Pac-man">
    <id>37963A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Ms. Pac-Man</title>
      <synopsis>In 1982, a sequel to the  incredibly popular Pac-Man was introduced in the form of his girlfriend, Ms. Pac-Man.  This sequel continued on the "eat the dots/avoid the ghosts" gameplay of the original game, but added new features to keep the title fresh.

Like her boyfriend, Ms. Pac-Man attempts to clear four various and challenging mazes filled with dots and ever-moving bouncing fruit  while avoiding Inky, Blinky, Pinky and Sue, each with their own personalities and tactics.  One touch from any of these ghosts means a loss of life for Ms. Pac-Man.

Ms. Pac-Man can turn the tables on her pursuers by eating one of the four Energizers located within the maze. During this time, the ghosts turn blue, and Ms. Pac-Man can eat them for bonus points (ranging from 200, 400, 800 and 1600, progressively). The Energizer power only lasts for a limited amount of time, as the ghost's eyes float back to their center box, and regenerate to chase after Ms. Pac-Man again.

Survive a few rounds of gameplay, and the player will be treated to humorous intermissions showing the growing romantic relationship between Pac-Man and Ms. Pac-Man, leading all the way up to the arrival of "Junior".</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>En 1982, se presentó una secuela del increíblemente popular Pac-Man en la forma de su novia, la Sra. Pac-Man. Esta continuación continuó con el juego "come y huye de los fantasmas" del juego original, pero agregó nuevas características para mantener el título fresco.nnnnAl igual que su novio, la Sra. Pac-Man intenta limpiar cuatro laberintos diferentes y desafiantes llenos de puntos y frutas que se mueven constantemente, evitando a Inky, Blinky, Pinky y Sue, cada uno con sus propias personalidades y tácticas. Un toque de cualquiera de estos fantasmas significa una vida menos para la Sra. Pac-Man.nnnnLa Sra. Pac-Man puede volver cambiar las tonas con sus perseguidores comiendo uno de las capsulas ubicadas dentro del laberinto. Durante este tiempo, los fantasmas se vuelven azules, y la Sra. Pac-Man puede comerlos por puntos de bonificación (que van desde 200, 400, 800 y 1600, progresivamente). La capsula solo dura un tiempo limitado, cuando los ojos del fantasma flotan de regreso a su caja central, y se regeneran para perseguir a la Sra. Pac-Man nuevamente.nnnnSupera algunas fases de juego, y el jugador será deleitado con interrupciones humorísticas que muestran la creciente relación romántica entre Pac-Man y la Sra. Pac-Man, que lleva hasta la llegada de "Junior".</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>General Computer Corporation|Midway</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Pac-man">
    <id>37964A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Pac-Man</title>
      <synopsis>One of the most popular and influential games of the 1980's, Pac-Man stars a little, yellow dot-muncher who works his way around to clear a maze of the various dots and fruit which inhabit the board.

Pac-Man's goal is continually challenged by four ghosts: The shy blue ghost Bashful (Inky), the trailing red ghost Shadow (Blinky), the fast pink ghost Speedy (Pinky), and the forgetful orange ghost Pokey (Clyde).  One touch from any of these ghosts means a loss of life for Pac-Man.

Pac-Man can turn the tables on his pursuers by eating of the four Energizers located within the maze.  During this time, the ghosts turn blue, and Pac-Man can eat them for bonus points.  This only lasts for a limited amount of time, as the ghost's eyes float back to their center box, and regenerate to chase after Pac-Man again.

Survive a few rounds of gameplay, and be treated to humorous intermissions between Pac-Man and the ghosts.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Pengo">
    <id>37965A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Pengo</title>
      <synopsis>The player uses a joystick and a single button as controls. Pressing the button while pushing the joystick will cause Pengo to push forward the ice block he is facing, which will slide until it hits a wall or another ice block, crushing any intervening Sno-Bees. Crushing more than one Sno-Bee at once will increase the number of points awarded. There are a total of sixteen levels, which repeat in order starting on the seventeenth round.
As the player crushes those on patrol, new Sno-Bees hatch from eggs located within ice blocks. At the start of each level, blocks that contain these eggs are briefly identified by flashing the color of that level's Sno-Bees. Eggs can be eliminated by crushing the ice blocks that contain them. If Pengo pushes a side wall the water "vibrates", any adjacent Sno-Bees will be briefly stunned, and are eliminated (for 100 points) if Pengo walks over them in this state. Eliminating all Sno-Bees in a round will progress the player to the next.
Diamond blocks are unbreakable; when connected in a horizontal or vertical line the player earns bonus points: 10,000 points if aligned without being against a wall or if only one diamond block is touching a wall, 5,000 points if all three are against the wall. Alignment will also temporarily stun all Sno-Bees.
After 60 seconds elapse in a round without a death, the game enters into sudden death mode; the music tempo and movement of the Sno-Bees accelerates. If a single Sno-Bee remains in the round, a jingle plays and the Sno-Bee accelerates in an attempt to reach a corner where it safely fades away.
The game will always start with the same maze on power up. Once the game has gone through the attract mode, the maze will change.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>nnEn Pengo, debes derrotar al enemigo empujando bloques de hielo para aplastarlos. También puedes capturar uno si están conmocionados y mareados. También hay un límite de tiempo para hacerlo un poco más difícil.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Dans Pengo, vous devez vaincre l'ennemi en poussant des blocs de glace ensemble pour les écraser. Vous pouvez également en capturer un si elles sont choquées et étourdies. Il y a aussi une limite de temps pour le rendre un peu plus difficile.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Coreland|SEGA Enterprises Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="17">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Pitfall!">
    <id>37966A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Pitfall!</title>
      <synopsis>Pitfall! is a platform action game. You play Pitfall Harry who is on a quest to locate treasure deep in the jungle. With a little luck you'll be able to find money bags, silver bars, gold bars, and diamond rings. But many obstacles will get in the way, some of which merely deduct points from your score, while others are fatal. Rolling logs and falling down a hole will deduct points, and scorpions, alligators, snakes, bottomless pits, swamps, and fires will cause Pitfall Harry to lose a life. You have 20 minutes to try to collect all of the treasures on the numerous screens, if you can live that long!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="15">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Pole Position">
    <id>37968A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Pole Position</title>
      <synopsis>Pole Position is the conversion of the arcade racing game. Enter the Grand Prix, race against other racing cars to achieve the highest score possible in the shortest amount of time.

Before the player can enter the Grand Prix, the player must first qualify by competing in the Qualifying Lap within 73 seconds or less. If the player however, does not qualify in the Qualifying Lap, the player may continue to race until the Race Timer runs after 90 seconds. The player will score 50 point per 5 meters and additionally 50 points for every racing car passed. When the time runs out - Game Over. The player will have to restart the Qualifying Lap.

Qualifying will enable the player to start in one of the eight available positions. The faster the lap time was, the better the starting position in addition to bonus score points. The number one starting position, is the Pole Position.

During the Grand Prix, the player will compete against the Race Timer as well as against other racing cars. If the player fails to beat the Race Timer in any lap, the player drops out of the race - Game Over. Completing the race by reaching finishing line will grant the player 200 points per each second left on the Race Timer, bonus score for distance covered, and passing bonus points.

Scoring

1. Every 5 meters driven: 50 points
Passing Car Bonus: 50 points per racing car
Time Bonus: 200 points per second left on the Race Timer

Positions

1. Pole Position - Lap Time: 58"50 seconds - 4,000 points
2nd Position - Lap Time: 60"00 seconds - 2,000 points
3rd Position - Lap Time: 62"00 seconds - 1,400 points
4th Position - Lap Time: 64"00 seconds - 1,000 points
5th Position - Lap Time: 66"00 seconds - 800 points
6th Position - Lap Time: 68"00 seconds - 600 points
7th Position - Lap Time: 70"00 seconds - 400 points
8th Position - Lap Time: 73"00 seconds - 200 points</synopsis>
      <genre>Race, Driving</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Carreras, Conducción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Pole Position, est un des seuls jeux de course sur Atari 5200. Pole position, est un jeu de Formule 1.</synopsis>
      <genre>Course, Conduite</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rennen, Fahren</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="15">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Popeye">
    <id>37969A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Popeye</title>
      <synopsis>Popeye is a conversion of the arcade action/platform game. As Popeye, you are trying to win Olive Oyl's love! She is at the top of the screen dropping tokens of her love, and you need to collect them before they hit the ground. After you have collected the required number of items, you can move on to the next, more difficult level. There are many obstacles trying to stop you from completing your task, though! Brutus wanders around the screen and is constantly trying to catch you. If you collect a can of spinach, you can temporarily knock him out, otherwise Brutus will knock you out. Other objects such as bottles or birds are also flying around the screen and will cause you to lose one of your lives if you are hit. Each level features a different layout of platforms and ladders, and will have you collecting different items as they float towards the bottom of the screen!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Popeye es una conversión del juego de arcade de acción / plataformas. Como Popeye, intentas ganar el amor de Olive Oyl! Ella está en la parte superior de la pantalla dejando caer objetos de su amor, y necesita recogerlos antes de que caigan al suelo. Después de haber recogido el número necesario de objetos, puedes pasar al siguiente nivel, más difícil. Sin embargo, hay muchos obstáculos que tratan de impedir que completes tu tarea. Brutus se pasea por la pantalla y está constantemente tratando de atraparte. Si recoges una lata de espinacas, puedes noquearlo temporalmente, de lo contrario Brutus te noqueará. Otros objetos tales como botellas o pájaros también vuelan por la pantalla y te harán perder una vida si te golpean. Cada nivel cuenta con un diseño diferente de plataformas y escaleras, y tendrás que recoger diferentes objetos a medida que caen hacia el suelo!</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Nintendo</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Q*bert">
    <id>37970A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Q*bert</title>
      <synopsis>Q*bert is a conversion of the popular arcade game. The goal is to change all of the tiles on a pyramid to the target color. To do this you guide Q*bert around the pyramid, and every tile he hops on will change color. On early levels, a single hop will change the tile to the desired color, but on later levels you may need to hop on a tile multiple times or even avoid hopping on a tile multiple times! Trying to stop Q*bert are many different creatures which wander around the board, including Coily the snake, Slick and Sam, and falling balls. On the edge of the board are floating discs; if Q*bert jumps on one of these discs when the snake is in pursuit, the snake will fall off  the board while Q*bert is safely transported to the top.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>D. Gottlieb &amp; Co.</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Qix">
    <id>37971A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>QIX</title>
      <synopsis>In this game, you guide a marker which must draw rectangles and other weird objects in order to claim your territory, and you can either draw these rectangles fast or slow. Drawing the rectangles using the "slow" method awards you the most points. Once a rectangle has been made, it will be colored in to show that you have claimed your territory. While drawing the rectangles, you need to watch out for Qix (pronounced "kicks"), a series of colored lines that crawl the screen. In addition to Qix, you also need to avoid the Sparks who travel around the border, as well as any lines that you have made, as well as The Fuse, who travels along the line that you are drawing. Once you have claimed enough territory, you proceed to the next level.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="15">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Quest For Quintana Roo">
    <id>37972A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Quest for Quintana Roo</title>
      <synopsis>You are Yucatan Sam on a quest to explore the temple of Quintana Roo. Your goal is to find the vault which is hidden somewhere within and return with the treasure that is inside. You begin your quest outside the temple; climb your way up the side of the temple in order to get inside. Poisonous snakes and deadly lightning bolts will block your progress here. Once inside the temple, you have a limited air supply so you need to explore quickly. Hidden in various rooms of the temple are numerous keys which are needed to unlock the vault. The keys and some other useful items are hidden in secret rooms which you need to locate by using your trusty pick axe or the flasks of acid you carry. To help figure out which rooms may contain hidden objects, you carry a geiger counter with you;  the higher the reading, the closer you are to something of interest! The rooms you'll be exploring are guarded by snakes, spiders, and even mummies! To deal with these enemies you carry a gun, and you can also use the acid flasks against them (ammo is limited, so use it wisely). If you are successful in your mission, you may receive a secret code which can be used to begin the game at later levels. Good luck!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Eres Yucatan Sam y estas en una misión para explorar el templo de Quintana Roo.
Tu objetivo es encontrar la bóveda oculta y regresar con su tesoro. Empiezas tu búsqueda fuera del templo; sube por el lado del templo para entrar. Las serpientes venenosas y los relámpagos mortales bloquearán tu camino. Una vez dentro del templo, tienes un suministro de aire limitado, por lo que debe explorar rápidamente. Ocultos en varias salas del templo hay numerosas teclas que se necesitan para desbloquear la bóveda. Las llaves y algunos otros artículos útiles están escondidos en las habitaciones secretas que debes localizar usando tu fiel pico o los frascos de ácido que llevas. Para ayudar a determinar qué habitaciones pueden contener objetos ocultos, llevas contigo un contador geiger; ¡Mientras más alta sea la lectura, más cerca está de algo de interés! ¡Las salas que explorarás están custodiadas por serpientes, arañas e incluso momias! Para lidiar con estos enemigos llevas un arma, y ??también puedes usar los frascos de ácido contra ellos (la munición es limitada, así que úsala con prudencia). Si tiene éxito en su misión, recibiras un código secreto que puede usarse para comenzar el juego en niveles posteriores. ¡Buena suerte!</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción,Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action,Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action,Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Ação,Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>VSS, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sunrise Software, Inc.</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="10">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Realsports Baseball">
    <id>37973A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>RealSports Baseball</title>
      <synopsis>Baseball is an action game which can be played by two players or one player against the computer. The game allows you to bunt the ball or try for a homerun, steal bases, and throw several types of pitches from a fast ball to a curve ball. Several game variations are included which allow you to select whether the home or visiting team is at bat first, and whether or not a player can swing only at pitches that are a strike, or they can swing at any pitch.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports,Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Deportes,Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport,Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport,Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Esporte,Ação</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Realsports Basketball">
    <id>44453A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>RealSports Basketball</title>
      <synopsis>There are two significantly different versions of Realsports Basketball for the Atari 5200, both programmed by Patrick Bass. This version is what would become the final version of the game, which seems fairly complete, including easter eggs. However, like the Atari 2600 game of the same name, Realsports Basketball was never released for sale. It's unknown why Atari programmed two different versions of the game.

Sadly, Patrick Bass died in an automobile crash in 1998. Patrick's brother, Ben Bass, worked with Ken Van Mersbergen to ensure this final version of the game would be shared with the public.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari Inc.</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Realsports Football">
    <id>37974A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>RealSports Football</title>
      <synopsis>Football is an action football game for two players or one player against the computer.  The game is played from a top down point of view of the field which scrolls to follow the action. There is a variety of offensive and defensive plays that can be called, along with several skill levels for each player. Each game will last for one fifteen minute quarter, whichever team has the most points at the end wins!</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>"Realsports Football" es un juego de fútbol de acción para uno o dos jugadores. Se juega desde un punto de vista superior del campo que se desplaza para seguir la acción. Hay una variedad de jugadas ofensivas y defensivas que se pueden realizar, junto con varios niveles de habilidad para cada jugador. Cada juego tendrá una duración de un cuarto de 15 minutos, ¡el equipo que tenga más puntos al final gana!</synopsis>
      <genre>Deportes</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="6">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Realsports Soccer">
    <id>37975A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>RealSports Soccer</title>
      <synopsis>The game is played from an angled overhead point of view of the field which scrolls to follow the action. If your team has the ball, you control whichever player is currently dribbling the ball, otherwise you can control any one player at a time while the computer controls the rest of your team. Various time lengths can be selected for each game, you can kick the ball low, medium or high, and there are throw-ins, corner kicks, goal kicks. When playing against the computer several different skill levels are available.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Deportes</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="10">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Realsports Tennis">
    <id>37976A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>RealSports Tennis</title>
      <synopsis>Realsports Tennis is a tennis game for two players or one player against the computer. The game follows standard tennis rules, and allows you to hit forehand or backhand shots to all areas of the court as well as serves and lobs. You can play a game of singles or doubles, and multiple skill levels are included.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Realsports Tennis es un juego de tenis para uno o dos jugadores. El juego sigue las reglas estándar del tenis y te permite lanzar golpes de derecha o de revés a todas las áreas de la cancha, así como servicios y faltas. Se pueden jugar partidos individuales o dobles, con varios niveles de dificultad.</synopsis>
      <genre>Deportes</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="8">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Rescue On Fractalus!">
    <id>37977A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Rescue on Fractalus!</title>
      <synopsis>Rescue on Fractalus is an action game played from a 3D first person point of view. Your mission is to rescue stranded pilots on the planet of Fractalus. You begin each mission from the mother ship, and when your quota of pilots has been rescued you must return there so you can move on to the next level. To help locate the pilots and navigate the tricky terrain, your spaceship is equipped with various instruments, such as a compass, altimeter, and scanner. Your enemy, the Jaggi's, have numerous forces on this planet and will be attempting to stop you. Gun emplacements, flying saucers, and the Jaggi themselves are all capable of destroying your ship if you don't destroy them first. To defend yourself from these threats, your ship is equipped with torpedoes. As the levels progress, the Jaggi defenses become more aggressive, and you will even need to fly some night missions where visibility is limited!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Ce jeu d'action en 3D se déroule sur une planète extraterrestre connue sous le nom de Fractalus. Le joueur incarne un pilote de vaisseau devant retrouver et sauver d'autres pilotes s'étant écrasé sur la planète, les missions de sauvetages devenant plus difficile lorsque des aliens, les Jaggies, commencent à défendre leur planète.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Lucasfilm Games LLC</developer>
    <publisher>Atari - Lucasfilm</publisher>
    <date year="1986" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Road Runner">
    <id>44454A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Road Runner</title>
      <synopsis>An unreleased prototype game staring the popular Road Runner cartoon character. Thought to have been based on perhaps a port of the arcade game Locomotion before being re skinned with Roadrunner and Wiley E Coyote.

At the start of each level a birdseed truck will weave its way through the maze dropping off piles of birdseed as it goes.  The goal of Roadrunner is to move the tiles around so Wiley Coyote eats as much birdseed as he can before the Roadrunner gets it.  Each tile contains a portion of the road which Wiley and the Roadrunner walk on, by sliding the tiles around you can make paths leading to the piles of birdseed or to the tunnels on the side of the board.  The tunnels connect one side of the screen to the other, and can be useful for warping across the screen.  Unfortunately some of these tunnel entrances are really just painted on, so if Wiley attempts to enter one he'll knock himself out.  The only way to tell if a tunnel is real is to watch the Roadrunner and see which tunnels he takes.

Wiley can die if he either runs off the end of the tile or runs into a false tunnel.  The Roadrunner appears to be able to back up from dead end track pieces and tunnels so he is impossible to kill, but you can trap him on two dead end pieces and complete the level at your leisure.  Once all the birdseed is gone the game moves to the next level.  If you happen to run into the Roadrunner you will score 10 points, and you the Roadrunner will be transported back to your starting points.  Wiley also scores 35 points for each tile he crosses, and 50 points for each pile of birdseed he collects.

- Excerpt from AtariProtos.com</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Puzzle</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Un juego prototipo inédito del popular personaje de dibujos animados Road Runner (o el Coyote y el Correcaminos. nnSe cree que se basó en tal vez en un port del juego de arcade "Locomotion" antes de ser rediseñado como "Correcaminos y El Coyote".nnnnAl comienzo de cada nivel, un camión de alpiste recorrera el laberinto, dejando caer montones de alpiste a medida que avanza. El objetivo del Correcaminos es mover las fichas para que el Correcaminos coma tanto alpiste como pueda antes de que el Coyote lo atrape. nnnnCada azulejo contiene una porción de la carretera sobre la que El Coyote y Roadrunner caminan, deslizando las baldosas a su alrededor puede hacer senderos que conducen a las pilas de alpiste o a los túneles en el costado del tablero. Los túneles conectan un lado de la pantalla con el otro y pueden ser útiles para recorrer la pantalla. nnDesafortunadamente, algunas de estas entradas de túnel están pintadas, así que si El Coyote intenta entrar en una, se quedará inconsciente. La única forma de saber si un túnel es real es observar al Correcaminos y ver por que tuneles pasa. El coyote puede morir si cae al otro lado del azulejo o se encuentra con un túnel falso.nnnnEl Correcaminos parece ser capaz de retroceder y pasar por túneles sin salida, por lo que es imposible matarlo, pero puedes atraparlo en dos zonas sin salida y completar el nivel cuando lo desees. nnnnUna vez que todo el alpiste se acaba, el juego pasa al siguiente nivel. Si te topas con el Correcaminos, obtendrás 10 puntos y el Correcaminos será transportado de regreso al punto de inicio de partida. Wiley también gana 35 puntos por cada ficha que cruza, y 50 puntos por cada monton de alpiste que colecciona. - Traduccion de Extracto de AtariProtos.com</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Robotron - 2084">
    <id>37979A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Robotron 2084</title>
      <synopsis>This is a port of the arcade game of the same name.

You are a mutant human, who by some freak of nature has the ability to shoot energy pulses from his body in eight different directions! Your job is simple: save humanity from their own creation -- the ROBOTRONS! The gameplay is pretty unique for the time. You can move and fire in any of eight directions. You get thrown in a room with various evil baddies strewn about, you've got to kill all the robots while at the same time finding some way to grab humans and avoid death.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Williams Electronic Games, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Sinistar">
    <id>37980A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Sinistar</title>
      <synopsis>"Beware! I live!"

This is a port of the Williams arcade game.

In the game, you must fly your ship about, shooting the floating asteroids to release Sinisite crystals. These crystals must be gathered to create Sinibombs. Also gathering crystals are worker drones. They are gathering crystals to build Sinistar, who wants to destroy the universe. As the workers will sometimes steal your mined crystals, feel free to blast them. Also flying about are warrior ships who want to blast you to protect the workers and Sinistar.

Once Sinistar is completed, he will announce "Beware! I live!" and begin chasing you. Hopefully, you have made enough Sinibombs to destroy him. As he chases you, press the fire button to release Sinibombs to damage him. Once he is completely destroyed, you are off to the next, harder, level.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>"Beware! I live!"

Este es un port del juego arcade de Williams.

En este juego, debes volar ensobre tu nave, disparando los asteroides para liberar cristales de sinisita. Estos cristales deben ser reunidos para crear Sinibombs. En estos cristales hay drones de trabajando. Están reuniendo cristales para construir Sinistar, que quiere destruir el universo. Como los drones a veces roban tus cristales minados, no dudes en dispararles. Cuidado con la naves que quieren bombardearte para proteger a los trabajadores y Sinistar.

Una vez que se complete Sinistar, se mostrara "Beware! I live!" y te perseguira. Con suerte, si has hecho suficientes Sinibombs podras destruirlo. Mientras te persigue, presiona el botón de disparo para liberar a Sinibombs y dañarlo. Una vez que este completamente destruido, podras pasar de nivel.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>AtariAge</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Dungeon">
    <id>37981A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Space Dungeon</title>
      <synopsis>Space Dungeon is an arcade style shooter. You control a spaceship within the space dungeon which consists of numerous rooms. Located throughout are treasures, and your goal is to collect as many of these treasures as you can and then proceed to the dungeons exit (called "collect bonus"). You don't need to collect every treasure to complete a level, but more bonus points are earned the more treasures you collect. Many of the rooms contain dangerous enemies, including death squares, guards, enforcers, pikers, and more. To fight off the enemies, your spaceship is equipped with a laser which can fire in eight different directions. To help find your way around, a map at the top of the screen will indicate where you are, where you've been, and what rooms visited so far still have enemies in them. Also located in the dungeons is a thief; the thief has the same goal as you, and will try to steal the treasures before you can. The thief can't be destroyed, but shooting it will cause it to drop any treasures it may be carrying. If you lose a spaceship at any point by crashing into an enemy or enemy fire, you will be sent back to the starting location and all the treasure you were carrying will be left in the room where you died. The game ends when you have lost all of your reserve spaceships.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="15">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Invaders">
    <id>37982A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Space Invaders</title>
      <synopsis>Earth is under attack from rows of bomb dropping aliens, and you need to defend it! The rows of aliens begin at the top of the screen, and you control a laser cannon at the bottom of the screen. Your goal is to earn points by shooting the aliens before they can land. The aliens march back and forth, and each time the end of the screen is reached they will drop one row closer to the bottom. Shoot them all, and you move on to the next (tougher) level, but if even one of them lands the game is over. From time to time a flying saucer will pass by along the top of the screen; shoot this to earn extra points. Just above your laser canon are three shields; these can be used to hide from the alien's bombs, but will also block your own shots. You begin the game with a limited number of laser canons, and if all of them are bombed the game ends.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Space Shuttle - A Journey Into Space">
    <id>37983A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Space Shuttle : A Journey Into Space</title>
      <synopsis>Space Shuttle is a simulation game where you are the pilot of space shuttle Discovery. Your goal is to launch the Discovery, establish an orbit around the Earth, open the cargo bay doors and recover a satellite to perform repairs, and finally land the Discovery successfully, all while using as little fuel as possible. Each time the complete mission is accomplished, it will then repeat at a higher difficulty level (in the higher difficulty levels the satellite has a more erratic flight path). The game is played from a first person perspective in the space shuttle cockpit where you can control everything from the shuttles engines to cargo bay doors. When the game is over you will be given a ranking which is based on the number of successful dockings and the amount of fuel that was used. In addition to the full flight mode, two easier game variations (autosimulator and simulator mode) are included. The autosimulator mode is the easiest; the computer will control the flight (you can take over at any point you wish) and the controls are simplified. The simulation mode is closer to the full game, however you have an unlimited amount of fuel so there is no time pressure, and the computer will help compensate for inaccurate maneuvering.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Spitfire">
    <id>44455A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Spitfire</title>
      <synopsis>Of all the prototypes that have passed through my hands over the years, Spitfire is definitely one of the strangest.  Part Zaxxon and part Star Raiders, Spitfire appears to have been Atari's first attempt into the realm of 3D shooters.  While the current known prototype may not be very complete (approx. 50%), it shows that the 5200 was indeed capable of 3D graphics.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari Inc.</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Sport Goofy">
    <id>44456A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Sport Goofy</title>
      <synopsis>An unreleased prototype for the Atari 5200. You take control of goofy as he competes in two events, the Marathon Dive and the Pogo Pop.

The Marathon Dive is a game in which you must guide Goofy up a series of platforms so he can reach the diving platform and jump off before the timer runs out.  As Goofy climbs up the platforms he must avoid little armored tanks, which will chase Goofy around.  Thankfully these tanks can't jump, reverse direction, or use the ladders, so they can be avoided by jumping over them or leading them into a hole (which will cause them to fall down to the next level).  Also hindering Goofy's progress are large gaps in the platforms which must be carefully jumped over.  If Goofy falls through a hole he'll fall down one level but is otherwise unharmed, however if he is hit by a tank he'll loose a life.
 
If Goofy makes it to the top of the platform he will run off the end, making it about halfway across the screen before realizing that he's running in mid-air.  Now Goofy will begin to fall, and you must guide him down to the little floating platform below.  However the floating platform is constantly moving in an erratic fashion, so hitting it can be tough.  If you successfully reach the platform, Goofy will smash into it and have his parachute open a second too late (in typical cartoon fashion).  If you miss the platform Goofy will fall into the water and drown (I guess he doesn't know how to swim).  As the levels progress the tanks will begin to move faster and faster, the diving platform has more holes in it, and the floating platform moves more erratically.  Eventually the difficulty will wrap around however, and the game will get very easy again.

Pogo Pop takes place on a series of squares where Goofy bounces up and down on a pogo stick in an effort to touch every tile.  This may sound easy but there's a catch, every time you jump one of the tiles disappears, so the tile that was below you may not be there when you land.  As the levels progress the frequency of the tiles disappearing increases, making it harder and harder not to fall through the floor.  
 
While you're jumping on tiles you can attempt to pop the Mickey Mouse balloons floating above you for extra points.  The balloons come in several different colors and are worth a varying amount of points.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Raiders">
    <id>37984A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Star Raiders</title>
      <synopsis>As the pilot of an interstellar starship, your mission is to destroy all of the Krylon fighters which are closing in on your starbases! There are three different types of fighters roaming throughout the galaxy; cruisers, fighters, and basestars. With the help of your galactic map, you can find the sectors of the galaxy where these fighters are located and then warp there to destroy them. When all of the fighters in a sector are destroyed, you can warp to a new location for the next battle. Be sure to keep an eye on your starships energy; warping to new locations, being hit by enemy fire, or colliding with an asteroid will drain your energy. If you completely run out of energy, your starship will be destroyed, however you can warp back to a starbase to refuel at any time. Returning to a starbase will also repair other types of damage your starship can receive, such as faulty engines, loss of your shield, and faulty photon torpedoes. When all of the Krylon that are visible on your galactic map have been destroyed, you win this round and can advance in rank (or even be demoted if you performed poorly on a mission).  The games difficulty will gradually increase as you rise in rank from ships cook up to captain.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Como piloto de una nave espacial interestelar, tu misión es destruir a todos los cazas Krylon que se están acercando a tus bases estelares. 
Hay tres tipos diferentes de naves vagando por toda la galaxia; cruceros, naves de ataque y bases estelares. Con la ayuda de su mapa galáctico, puedes encontrar los sectores de la galaxia donde se encuentran estas naves para destruirlas. Cuando todos los enemigos en un sector son destruidos, puedes dirigirte a una nueva ubicación para la próxima batalla. Asegúrate de vigilar la energía de tus naves estelares. Si te quedas completamente sin energía, tu nave espacial será destruida, sin embargo, puedes volverte hacia una base estelar para repostar en cualquier momento. Volver a una base estelar también reparará otros tipos de daños que tu nave espacial puede recibir, como motores defectuosos, pérdida de tu escudo y torpedos de fotones defectuosos. Cuando todos los Krylon visibles en tu mapa galáctico hayan sido destruidos, ganas esta ronda y puedes avanzar en rango (o incluso ser degradado si tuviste un desempeño pobre en una misión). La dificultad de los juegos aumentará gradualmente a medida que aumente en rango desde los buques hasta el capitán.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Ação,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Trek - Strategic Operations Simulator">
    <id>37985A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Star Trek : Strategic Operations Simulator</title>
      <synopsis>Star Trek: Strategic Operations Simulator is an arcade action game where you take control of the Starship Enterprise. Your mission is to save the Federation from NOMAD! Before you get a chance at destroying NOMAD, you'll have to battle your way through ten levels (each consisting of multiple rounds). In each round you may encounter Klingon fighters, deadly anti-matter saucers, asteroid fields, and deadly meteors, all of which are capable of depleting the Enterprises energy. The game ends when your energy supply has completely run out. To fight these dangers, the Enterprise is equipped with an unlimited supply of phasers and a limited supply of photon torpedoes. Each round also contains one or more starbases; if you dock at a starbase, some of your supplies (such as energy and torpedoes) will be replenished. The game is played from two points of view; the top of the screen contains a third person view of the Enterprise (along with the ships gauges), and on the bottom of the screen is a first person point of view</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Star Trek: Strategic Operations Simulator es un juego de acción arcade en el que tomas el control de la nave espacial Enterprise. ¡Tu misión es salvar a la Federación de NOMAD! Antes de que tengas la oportunidad de destruir a NOMAD, tendrás que recorrer diez niveles (cada uno compuesto por múltiples rondas). En cada ronda puedes encontrar combatientes klingon, platillos mortíferos antimateria, campos de asteroides y meteoritos mortales, todos los cuales son capaces de agotar la energía de la Enterprise. El juego termina cuando te quedas sin energia. Para combatir estos peligros, la Enterprise está equipada con un suministro ilimitado de phasers y un suministro limitado de torpedos de fotones. Cada ronda también contiene una o más bases estelares; si atracas en una base estelar, algunos de sus suministros (como energía y torpedos) se repondrán. El juego se juega desde dos puntos de vista; la parte superior de la pantalla contiene una vista en tercera persona de la Enterprise (junto con los indicadores de los buques), y en la parte inferior de la pantalla hay un punto de vista en primera persona.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Wars - Return Of The Jedi - Death Star Battle">
    <id>37987A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Star Wars : Return of the Jedi, Death Star Battle</title>
      <synopsis>"Death Star Battle" is loosely based on the events of "Star Wars, Part 6: Return of the Jedi". Your task is to destroy the Death Star before its construction is finished. You start the task outside the shield perimeter of the Death Star. There you'll have to combat different imperial vessels and avoid the death ray while waiting for an opportunity to slip through one of the random openings in the energy shield. After reaching the Death Star you must reduce its structure up to the point where you can hit the core. In the following blow up of the station you must avoid collision with Death Star debris.

After successful destruction the game will restart with increased difficulty (faster enemies, faster Death Star build up, etc).

Overall difficulty can also be adjusted before starting the game.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Parker Brothers</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="6">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Star Wars">
    <id>37986A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Star Wars : The Arcade Game</title>
      <synopsis>Conversion of Atari Games' first-person shoot 'em up based around the original Star Wars film. You take on the role of Luke Skywalker, aiming to destroy the Death Star - which, as any fan knows, involves attacking the 'weak spot' near the exhaust. To even get to this you have to pass swarms of TIE Fighters. Complete the game and it loops back around at ever-increasing difficulty. The game uses vector graphics, which allow lots of action at high speed on comparatively slow systems.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="8">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Stargate">
    <id>44457A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Stargate</title>
      <synopsis>An unreleased prototype port of the popular Williams game Stargate.

The sequel to Defender and much like the arcade game you fly around blasting aliens and trying to survive long enough to save humanoids. You also have a Hyperspace button that can teleport you to a random area which can be good or bad. Also new in Stargate was an Inviso button that would cloak your fighter for a limited time.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Breakout">
    <id>37988A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Super Breakout</title>
      <synopsis>Super Breakout features similar gameplay to the original, but with several new game variations. Your goal is to earn as many points as possible by destroying the bricks at the top of the playfield. To do this, you need to use the paddle at the bottom of the screen to keep a bouncing ball within the playfield. There are four different game variations included. The first is 'Breakout', and plays the same as the original game. 

This leaves three new gameplay concepts. In 'Progressive' the brick walls will slowly drop towards the bottom of the screen and the ball moves progressively faster and faster. When there's room, a new layer of bricks will appear at the top. 

The other two games add a second paddle. In 'Double Breakout' you have two balls to keep in play and score with. In 'Cavity' there is a single ball in play when you start, but two additional balls trapped within the bricks. These are freed when their surrounding bricks are destroyed.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Super Breakout presenta una mecánica de juego similar a la original, pero con algunas variaciones de juego nuevas. Tu objetivo es ganar la mayor cantidad de puntos posible destruyendo los ladrillos de la parte superior del campo de juego. Para hacer esto, necesitarás utilizar la paleta de la parte inferior de la pantalla para mantener la pelota rebotando dentro del campo de juego. Hay cuatro variaciones de juego diferentes incluidas. El primero es 'Breakout', y se juega igual que en el juego original.

Además tenemos tres nuevos conceptos de juego. En 'Progresivo', las paredes de ladrillo caerán lentamente hacia la parte inferior de la pantalla y la pelota se moverá progresivamente más y más rápido. Cuando hagamos espacio en esta pared de ladrillo, una nueva pared de ladrillos caerá de la parte superior.

Los otros dos juegos agregan una segunda paleta. En 'Doble Breakout' tienes que mantener dos pelotas en juego y anotar con ellas. En 'Cavity' hay una sola pelota en juego cuando comienzas, pero dos pelotas adicionales atrapadas dentro de los ladrillos. Estas se liberan cuando se destruyen los ladrillos que las rodean.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Cobra">
    <id>37989A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Super Cobra</title>
      <synopsis>Super Cobra is a side scrolling shooter based on the arcade game. You're a chopper pilot on a surveillance mission in enemy territory; your goal is to make it through the various obstacle courses alive and score as many points as possible. Tall buildings, mountains, narrow tunnels, and various enemies (such as tanks, rockets, mines, and more) can all get in the way and destroy your chopper if you aren't careful. To help defend yourself, the chopper is armed with a machine gun and bombs which can be used to destroy the enemy tanks and rockets. To make the task more difficult, your chopper has a limited amount of fuel. Throughout the landscapes are fuel tanks; if one of these is shot or bombed, you will be awarded extra fuel. As the levels progress, the enemies become more aggressive, fuel becomes more scarce, and the landscape becomes trickier to navigate.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Super Cobra es un juego de disparos de desplazamiento lateral basado en el juego de arcade.nnEres un piloto de helicópteros en una misión de vigilancia en territorio enemigo; tu objetivo es superar las diversas carreras de obstáculos y obtener tantos puntos como sea posible. nnLos edificios altos, las montañas, los túneles estrechos y varios enemigos (como tanques, cohetes, minas y más) pueden interponerse en tu camino y destruir su helicóptero si no tienes cuidado.nnPara ayudar a defenderte, el helicóptero está armado con una ametralladora y bombas que pueden usarse para destruir los tanques y cohetes enemigos.nnPara hacer la tarea más difícil, tu helicóptero tiene una cantidad limitada de combustible. nnA lo largo de los paisajes hay tanques de combustible; si uno de estos se dispara o bombardea, se le otorgará combustible extra.nnA medida que los niveles progresan, los enemigos se vuelven más agresivos, el combustible se vuelve más escaso y el paisaje se vuelve más complicado de recorrer.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="10">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Pac-man">
    <id>44458A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Super Pac-Man</title>
      <synopsis>In a very good adaptation of one of the lesser-known Pac-Man sequels, Super Pac-Man for the Atari 5200 speeds up the action -- and drastically shortens the effectiveness of the power pills and super power pills gobbled up by Pac-Man. If you think you've mastered the original arcade version -- either with the benefit of a lot of quarters or Namco Museum -- this version of Super Pac-Man may yet humble you with its faster pace. Graphically, this is a better translation of its source material than the original Pac-Man for the 5200 was, and the sound is almost a dead-ringer for the arcade game.</synopsis>
      <genre>Arcade</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>En una adaptación de una de las secuelas de Pac-Man menos conocidas, Super Pac-Man para el Atari 5200 acelera la acción y acorta drásticamente la efectividad de las pastillas de poder y pastillas superpotentes engullidas por Pac-Man . nnSi crees que has dominado la versión arcade original, esta versión de Super Pac-Man aún puede humillarte con su ritmo más rápido. Gráficamente, esta es una mejor traducción de su material de origen que el Pac-Man original para el 5200, y el sonido es casi un calco del juego de arcade.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari Inc.</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Tempest">
    <id>44459A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Tempest</title>
      <synopsis>Tempest is a shooter using wire-frame graphics. Each Wireway is taken on in turn, and has a network of lines guiding the movement paths of both yourself and the aliens. You remain on the outside and keep shooting as the aliens move towards you. Any that reach the outside are fatal to touch, thus limiting your range of movement greatly if 2 or more achieve this. Some aliens move sideways - in dealing with these, plan ahead allowing for the time your shots to take to travel.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Activision Decathlon, The">
    <id>37915A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>The Activision Decathlon</title>
      <synopsis>Up to four players compete in the ten different events of a real-life decathlon, either in sequence or individually. The events are -


100-Meter Dash
Long Jump
Shot Put
High Jump
400-Meter Race
110-Meter Hurdles
Discus Throw
Pole Vault
Javelin Throw
1500-Meter Race</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Deportes</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Dreadnaught Factor, The">
    <id>37936A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>The Dreadnaught Factor</title>
      <synopsis>The Zorban Dreadnaughts are spaceships that are 140,000 feet long and weigh 970 megatons, making them the largest, most heavily armoured spaceships ever created. A fleet of these large battlecraft are now heading towards your home planet, and it is your job to stop them! The game is played from a side scrolling overhead point of view as your small but agile spaceship flies past the dreadnaughts. On each pass your spaceship makes, you need to try and bomb as many of the energy vents as possible. When all energy vents on a dreadnaught are destroyed, that dreadnaught will explode. Time is limited, though, and if you make too many passes to destroy the energy vents the dreadnaught will be within firing range of your home planet and will destroy it. Each of the dreadnaughts are heavily armed; guns, canons, missiles, and other weapons are located on each dreadnaught and will be trying their best to end your mission. Multiple skill levels are included which alter the number of dreadnaughts you must destroy, as well as their speed and firing capabilities.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Cheshire Engineering</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Last Starfighter, The">
    <id>44447A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>The Last Starfighter</title>
      <synopsis>"Greetings Starfighter. You have been recruited by the Star League to defend the Frontier against Xur and the Ko-Dan armada."

The Last Starfighter is based on the 80s movie. Unfortunately despite being finished it wasn't released for the Atari 5200. However it does exist in prototype form and was eventually officially released for the Atari XE/XL as Star Raiders II with some minor changes. Also an arcade version was supposed to be released but was canned as well. On top of all that this game wasn't even originally The Last Starfighter and instead was originally called Orbiter that was retooled. Quite a history for a prototype!</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Track And Field">
    <id>44460A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Track and Field</title>
      <synopsis>An unreleased prototype game for the Atari 5200 based on the popular arcade game. While it went unreleased it was ported and released for the Atari 8-Bit computers. Players take part in 6 events.

100 Meter Dash â Running by quickly alternating button presses.

Long jump â Running by alternating button press and correct timing for jump. Hold jump button to set angle (42 degrees is optimal).

Javelin throw â Running by alternating button presses and then using action button correct timing for angle (43 degrees is optimal).

110 Meter Hurdles â Running by alternating button presses and using action button to time hurdles

Hammer throw â Spinning initiated by pressing a run button once and then correctly timed press of action button to choose angle (45 is optimal).

High jump â Running (speed set by computer) and then action button must be held down to determine angle of jump. Once in the air, the run button can be rapidly pressed for additional height.

Gameplay screenshot of the long jump event.

In each event, there is a qualifying time or level that the player must achieve to advance to the next event; failing to qualify (in one heat for running events or three tries in the other events) will reduce the player's number of lives by one, but if none are present in his/her disposal, the game will end.</synopsis>
      <genre>Arcade</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>A l'aide de votre manette que vous agitez de droite à gauche le plus rapidement possible pour prendre de la vitesse, participez aux épreuves olympiques. Il faut impérativement réussir si l'on veut continuer.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="4">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Atari Inc.</developer>
  </game>
  <game name="Vanguard">
    <id>37990A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Vanguard</title>
      <synopsis>Vanguard is an arcade style shooter for one or two players. Your goal is to pilot your spaceship to the City of Mystery which is located at the end of a heavily guarded tunnel, and once there destroy the creature Gond. The tunnel is broken up into several different zones, called the mountain zone, rainbow zone, stick zone, stripe zone, bleak zone, and City of Mystery. Each zone features different types of enemy spaceships to deal with, and can scroll either horizontally or vertically. In the mountain zone or stripe zone, you may also come across an energy pod marked with an 'E'. If you fly through this, your ship temporarily becomes invincible to the deadly cave walls and numerous enemies which are trying to stop you. When not invincible, your space ship is equipped with lasers to help destroy enemies. You can fire in four different directions, however your speed is decreased when firing. You also need to keep an eye on your fuel gauge; your fuel will deplete at a rapid rate, and your ship will crash if it runs out. Fuel is gained each time you destroy an enemy, so make sure you destroy as many as you can! When you finally make it through all the various zones of the tunnel and defeat Gond, the game will repeat at a more difficult skill level.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Vanguard es un shooter de estilo arcade para uno o dos jugadores.
Su objetivo es pilotar su nave espacial a la Ciudad del Misterio que se encuentra al final de un túnel fuertemente guardado, y una vez allí destruir la criatura Gond.
El túnel se divide en varias zonas diferentes, llamadas la zona de la montaña, la zona del arco iris, la zona del palillo, la zona de la raya, la zona desolada, y la Ciudad del Misterio. Cada zona cuenta con diferentes tipos de naves enemigas para hacer frente, y puede desplazarse horizontal o verticalmente.
En la zona de montaña o zona de rayas, también puede encontrar una vaina de energía marcada con un 'E' que siendo recogida otorga invencibilidad temporal ante las paredes de la cueva mortales y numerosos enemigos que están tratando de detenerle.
Cuando no es invencible, su nave espacial está equipada con láseres para ayudar a destruir a los enemigos. Puedes disparar en cuatro direcciones diferentes, sin embargo tu velocidad disminuye al disparar.
Usted también necesita mantener un ojo en su indicador de combustible; Su combustible se agotará a una velocidad rápida, y su nave se estrellará si se agota. El combustible se gana cada vez que destruyes un enemigo, así que asegúrate de destruir todo lo que puedas. Cuando finalmente lo hagas a través de todas las diferentes zonas del túnel y derrotas a Gond, el juego se repetirá a un nivel de habilidad más difícil.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>La planète Aterria est animée par des ennemis qui ont hâte d'abattre votre vaisseau alors que vous vous dirigez vers la Cité des Mystères pour faire face au Gond. Vous aurez besoin de beaucoup de compétences pour traverser le système de tunnels afin de traverser les sept zones de tunnels. Une zone novice vous permet de perfectionner votre habileté et les ennemis ne tirent pas sur vous et vous avez un carburant sans fin. Profitez-en ... ça devient plus difficile! N'oubliez pas que vous pouvez appuyer sur la touche pour un tir continu.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>SNK</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="17">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Wizard Of Wor">
    <id>37991A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Wizard of Wor</title>
      <synopsis>Wizard of Wor is an arcade shooter played from a top-down point of view.

The player controls a warrior who is trapped in a dungeon. The goal is to earn as many points as possible by shooting the numerous enemy creatures which wander about the maze like corridors. The creatures wander about at various speeds, may shoot darts at the player, and some even have the ability to disappear temporarily. At the bottom of the screen the player has a radar which can be used to locate creatures that are invisible.

When the the player completes a maze, a Worluk sometimes appears. This creature moves rapidly and will only be on the screen momentarily. If the player destroys the creature before it escapes, the next dungeon will become a double score dungeon and all creatures will be worth twice as many points. Occasionally the Wizard of Wor himself may appear! He moves quickly and can teleport around the maze. If they destroy him, the player will earn a large amount of points.

The game may be played by one player or two players simultaneously.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Bally Midway</developer>
    <publisher>CBS Electronics</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Xari Arena">
    <id>44461A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Xari Arena</title>
      <synopsis>An unreleased prototype game for the Atari 5200.

Your goal is to destroy all the Xari's that come out of the well in the center of the screen before they can destroy all your blocks. You can use the joystick or the trackball controller.
 
Each player resembles a hollow paddle (like a capsule), which you can move around your side of the screen.  Your paddle can catch and hold up to three fireballs (the little star looking things that the Xari's shoot), and each stored fireball allows you to destroy one Xari by running into it.  If you hit a Xari without any fireballs stored in your paddle, it is temporarily stunned and you cannot catch or deflect any shots for a few seconds.  If you already have three fireballs stored up, your paddle will start reflecting the fireballs back at the Xari's (a great tactic for those hard to reach guys that won't come near you) and at your partner (which is not so good).  You can choose to reflect shots even if you don't have three fireballs stored up by pressing the bottom controller button.
 
If things start to get out of control you can activate your fire extinguisher (using the top controller button) to temporarily protect your blocks.  The fire extinguisher coats your blocks with foam and will destroy any shots that touch it.  the foam moves quickly down your blocks and only lasts for a few seconds so you have to use it wisely (like when fireballs get behind your blocks).  You get one new fire extinguisher each level, which can be stored for later use.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1983" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Xevious">
    <id>44462A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Xevious</title>
      <synopsis>An unreleased prototype based on the popular Namco shooting game.

It's a nightmare, but it's true.  Scientific research has determined that we are the actual aliens on Earth and the evil Xevions are the original inhabitants.  Now the Xevions want Earth back. minus the humans! Earth's last hope is an experimental fighter plane known as the Solvalou.  The mission is dangerous, success isn't guaranteed, and odds are this is a one-way trip.  But at this point it's do or die!

As Earth's last hope, you must successfully defeat the Xevion assault fleet before they reclaim earth.  However this won't be an easy task, the Xevions have had over a millennia to develop the biggest, nastiest, and most destructive ships Earth has ever seen.  Thankfully the Solvalou is armed with the latest in weapons technology which will cut through the Xevion hordes like a hot knife through butter.  The Solvalou has two main weapons, a laser blaster for taking out air targets, and a photon bomber for destroying ground targets.  Over the course of the game you'll run into numerous enemy types which can only be destroyed using the appropriate weapon, so mastering the dual shot (air and ground) technique is vital.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Tiro</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Tir</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Yellow Submarine">
    <id>44463A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Yellow Submarine</title>
      <synopsis>Yellow Submarine was a prototype coded by an unknown Atari programmer to demonstrate directional control and the ability to move off one side of the screen and reappear on the opposite side. The Beatles yellow submarine graphic was not used in any Atari 5200 video game and was perhaps nothing more than an inspiration by the original programmer. There is no game here only the ability to control the yellow submarine on and around the screen</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Atari</developer>
    <publisher>Atari</publisher>
    <date year="1982" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Zaxxon">
    <id>37992A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Zaxxon</title>
      <synopsis>The Zaxxon defence system must be destroyed in this isometric-viewed shoot 'em up which was originally hugely successful in the arcades. The game has 3 stages, first taking you through Asteroid City, which is heavily protected by aircraft, guns and missiles. Many barriers are alarmed, leaving you with limited space to progress through, and fire must constantly be dodged.

Stage two is a space shoot out against hordes of enemy aircraft - those you failed to destroy in the first part of the task. Complete this and you reach the final battle with Zaxxon, with the game looping with increased difficulty if you can survive the first time. There are 3 distinct skill levels, while controls involve using forward to dive and back to climb, in the manner of flight simulation.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>A bordo de su nave espacial, ingresa a una fortaleza gigante donde puede recibir armas y aviones enemigos. Para cruzarlo también deberá elegir la altitud correcta (gracias a una graduación indicada en la pantalla) para atravesar aberturas estrechas en las paredes.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>A bord de votre vaisseau spatial, vous pénétrez dans une forteresse géante où vous accueillent canons et avions ennemis. Pour la traverser vous devrez en plus choisir la bonne altitude (grâce à une graduation indiquée à l'écran) pour passer dans des ouvertures étroites dans les murs.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Zenji">
    <id>37993A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Zenji</title>
      <synopsis>Zenji is an action/strategy game where you control a rolling face throughout a maze. Each section of the maze can be rotated by the face. The goal is to turn the entire maze green by connecting each section of the maze to the source at the center of the screen. After all sections of the maze have been connected, you can move on to the next, more challenging level. In addition to having a time limit to complete your task, you need to avoid the flames and sparks which wander about the maze. From time to time a number will appear in a maze section and count down from 9 to 0. If you touch the number before it disappears, bonus points are earned. As the levels progress, the mazes become larger, trickier and more flames will appear.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Zenji es un juego de acción / estrategia en el que controlas una cara rodante en un laberinto. Cada sección del laberinto puede ser girada por la cara. El objetivo es hacer que todo el laberinto sea verde conectando cada sección del laberinto a la fuente en el centro de la pantalla. Después de que se hayan conectado todas las secciones del laberinto, puede pasar al siguiente nivel, más difícil. Además de tener un límite de tiempo para completar su tarea, debe evitar las llamas y las chispas que recorren el laberinto.</synopsis>
      <genre>Acción,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Zenji est un jeu d'action / stratégie où vous contrôlez un visage roulant dans un labyrinthe. Chaque section du labyrinthe peut être tournée par le visage. Le but est de rendre vert le labyrinthe entier en reliant chaque section du labyrinthe à la source au centre de l'écran. Après que toutes les sections du labyrinthe ont été connectées, vous pouvez passer au niveau suivant, plus difficile. En plus d'avoir une limite de temps pour terminer votre tâche, vous devez éviter les flammes et les étincelles qui errent dans le labyrinthe.</synopsis>
      <genre>Action,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Ação,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="18">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Zone Ranger">
    <id>37994A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Zone Ranger</title>
      <synopsis>Zone Ranger is an arcade action game somewhat similar to Asteroids. You are the pilot of a spaceship in a deadly region of space. Large killer rocks, rogue satellites, boomerangs, and more all fill this region of space. Using your ships lasers you need to destroy as many of these as you can to earn points. Each level also contains some warp holes; enter one of these and you will be transported to a new location, which could be useful if you get in trouble. You will also occasionally come across some sonic sparklers; touch one of these, and you will temporarily become invincible. Another oddity you may come across is a super portal, which will transport you to the inner sanctum where bonus dots can be found. Lastly, on level one only a warp to the seventh dimension can be found. Lots of points can be earned there, but it's quite difficult so if you take this warp you probably won't last long!</synopsis>
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Acción</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Action</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <date year="1984" month="" day=""/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
</datafile>
