<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<datafile xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="wiitdb.xsd">
  <WiiTDB version="201812041646" games="83"/>
  <game name="Aa! Megami Sama">
    <id>38413A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Ah! Megami-Sama</title>
      <synopsis>The game is a remake of the  computer game of the same name. It adds an animated intro, voice-overs, and two mini-games.

The story is based on the manga/anime series Ah! My Goddess, depicting the adventures of Keiichi, a Japanese teenager who accidentally summoned the Norse goddess Verdandi (misspelled "Belldandy" in the romanization) and made a wish for her to stay with him forever, which led to all kinds of troubles. What's more, other powerful beings out there are seeking to harm Keiichi's divine girlfriend, so a simple date ends in an unexpected way...

The game is a "digital comic", meaning that the adventure elements are reduced to the bare minimum: being able to choose dialogue lines or make other decisions from time to time. The mini-games are a timed exercise of putting puzzle pieces together, and a card-matching game against two female opponents.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Banpresto</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Akazukin Cha-cha - Osawagase! Panic Race!">
    <id>38414A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Akazukin Cha-Cha: Osawagase! Panic Race!</title>
      <synopsis>The game is based on the manga Akazukin Cha-Cha ("Red Riding Hood Cha-Cha") by Min Ayahana, and subsequently on the animated TV series that followed it. The manga tells the story of a little girl named Cha-Cha who lives with her teacher on a mountain and studies magic. In the anime, the story was expanded to include the villainous Demon King, whom Cha-Cha and her best friend Riiya, a werewolf boy, must eventually defeat.

Akazukin Cha-Cha is a game for up to six players. Each player corresponds to a character from the TV series. It is also possible to play just as Cha-Cha and to let the AI control the other characters. Each player advances on the board by throwing dice. Landing on different fields leads to different results: finding items, being attacked, etc. The game's strategy elements are expanded by giving each character unique statistics and abilities, that have to be used under special circumstances. Certain obstacles are only solvable if two or more characters gather on the same field. 

Taking a cue from Battle Heat, "Akazukin Cha-Cha" accompanies every single move by an anime-style FMV.</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>NEC Interchannel, Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Angelique Special">
    <id>38415A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Angelique Special</title>
      <synopsis>Angelique Special is a remake of the original  Angelique for SNES. There are no changes gameplay-wise (a mixture of adventure, strategy, and "dating sim") or story-wise (a simple girl named Angelique Limoges must befriend nine Guardians to become a queen). The remake features better graphics, CD-quality music, voice acting, and anime-style cut-scenes.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Koei</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1995" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Angelique Special 2">
    <id>38416A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Angelique Special 2</title>
      <synopsis>Following the events of the  first Angelique game, Angelique Limoges has become the queen of Cosmos, and her former rival Rosalie - her aid. Now a whole new Cosmos has appeared, and it's time to choose a new queen for it. The candidates this time are Angelique Collet (the protagonist of the game) and Rachel Hart.

The gameplay system remains largely unchanged in this sequel. Once again, Angelique has to use diplomacy to make the Nine Guardians lend her their powers (making the inhabitants of her land happy), or develop stronger feelings for her. New in this sequel is the ability to work with three different instructors, developing mind, sense, or dignity of the heroine, which will influence the way she interacts with other characters and also affect the behavior of the Guardians.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Koei</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Angelique Tenkuu No Requim">
    <id>38417A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Angelique: Tenk no Requiem</title>
      <synopsis>The first RPG entry in  Angelique universe, adventure/dating simulation games specifically created for female players and revolving around young girls on a quest to become queens of various planets. Player takes the role of Angelique Collet, the heroine of  Angelique Special 2. Angelique Limoges, the protagonist of the  first game, and now the queen of Angelique Collet's home planet, is threatened by a mysterious man named Leviath. Her Guardians are imprisoned and her life is in danger. Angelique Collet must liberate the Guardians and save her homeland.

The game plays like a traditional Japanese RPG, with top-down view, turn-based battles, etc. However, the dating simulation element from other Angelique games is also present in this RPG. The heroine is able to have conversations with the male characters in her party. Depending on her answers and decisions, she will become involved with one of those characters.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Koei</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1998" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Arcade Flight Simulator">
    <id>65614A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Arcade Flight Simulator</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Arcade Trivia Quiz Simulator">
    <id>65636A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Arcade Trivia Quiz Simulator</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Arubarea No Otome">
    <id>38423A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Arubarea no Otome</title>
      <synopsis>In "Arubarea no Otome", you play one of the three girls who were summoned to the castle of the Queen of Arubarea to study fighting and magical arts (you can name your heroine as you like). As an additional reward - beside the graduation - you can try to impress and ultimately to win the heart of one of the five great knights of the kingdom. Your goal in the game is to make sure you become stronger and more charming than your two rivals, and to make a good impression on the Queen and the knights.

You must plan a schedule for your studies in castle. You can choose which classes to visit and which not. Learning increases your abilities (for example, attending magic class will make your spells more powerful). Once in a while you'll have to help one of the knights to fight monsters. The battles take place on an isometric battle field, on which you can freely move your characters and attack or use spells when there are enemies in range. Your goal in battles is not only to win, but to make sure the heroine does some attacking instead of letting the powerful knights do the job.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Simulação,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Aruberea's Maiden">
    <id>103591</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Aruberea's Maiden</title>
      <synopsis>In Aruberea's Maiden you play one of the three girls who were summoned to the castle of the Queen of Aruberea to study fighting and magical arts (you can name your heroine as you like). As an additional reward - beside the graduation - you can try to impress and ultimately to win the heart of one of the five great knights of the kingdom. Your goal in the game is to make sure you become stronger and more charming than your two rivals, and to make a good impression on the Queen and the knights.

You must plan a schedule for your studies in castle. You can choose which classes to visit and which not. Learning increases your abilities (for example, attending magic class will make your spells more powerful). Once in a while you'll have to help one of the knights to fight monsters. The battles take place on an isometric battle field, on which you can freely move your characters and attack or use spells when there are enemies in range. Your goal in battles is not only to win, but to make sure the heroine does some attacking instead of letting the powerful knights do the job.</synopsis>
      <genre>Life Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Gimmick House</publisher>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Batter Up">
    <id>65615A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Batter Up</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Battle Heat">
    <id>38424A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Battle Heat</title>
      <synopsis>In a desolate and cruel world, two clans are fighting for domination: the noble Republic of Kriph, led by the warrior Kai, and the evil Holy Dark Empire, led by Alamis and the mysterious armored Götz von Dark. The player can choose to play as any of the good and evil characters (four for each clan) - but it is only possible to fight warriors of the opposing party.

Battle Heat's biggest innovation as a fighting game is the fact that every single move is viewed as a full-motion anime-style sequence. Each of the controller's buttons is assigned to a specific move (including jumping), and the moment the player presses it, it triggers the movie. The game features many different movies, including specific ones when, for example, a character is kicked down and immediately reacts with an attack of his own.

It is possible to play the game in a tournament mode (for Republic of Kriph only), or choose a free battle, which also makes it possible to play as the bad guys.</synopsis>
      <genre>Fight</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Combate</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Combat</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Kampf</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1994" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Blue Breaker - Ken Yori Mo Hohoemi O">
    <id>38425A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Blue Breaker: Ken yori mo Hohoemi o</title>
      <synopsis>The world of Blue Breaker is called "the path in the middle of empty sky": floating islands connected with each other by bridges. It is the tradition of the people in this world that a fighter's full initiation can be completed only when he finds his true love and marries her. Such day has come now in the life a young warrior named Kain, the hero of the game. His father explains to him that besides the usual warrior's goal of defeating the evil Dark Lord, Kain also has to find the girl of his dreams. He introduces to him a young sorceress named Asha, who becomes his first companion. But on his journey Kain meets many other young women, and it won't be so easy to choose one to whom he can give his heart!

Labeled as Love Role-Playing, "Blue Breaker" is a genre-crossing game that combines traditional Japanese RPG with town and dungeon exploration, party-based combat, etc., with "love adventure", in which your behavior towards girls influences the story. "Blue Breaker" features branching story progressing: events appear depending on the progress you have made with your female companions. Your typical RPG activities will influence your relationship with the girls. For example, if you fight too much, the girls will be tired; if you give a girl too many orders in battle (you can set battle in auto mode and only interfere occasionally) she will be displeased, and so on. It is also important to form a party in which the girls will have as few internal conflicts with each other as possible.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>HuneX Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Boundary Gate - Daughter Of Kingdom">
    <id>38426A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Boundary Gate: Daughter of Kingdom</title>
      <synopsis>Long time ago, the First Mother created the world and blessed it with five magical symbols that would keep it in balance. The symbols were hidden deep in a sacred temple, to protect everything and everyone around them.

Many years later, an adventurer named Finn was looking for work in the city of Ambrose. There was indeed much work to do: monsters roamed the country, the threat of war was more real than ever. One night Finn was strolling through the city when he suddenly spotted a young girl attacked by a monster. Naturally, he defeated the monster and saved the girl, who turned out to be a princess hoping to restore her father's kingdom. The two decide to work together and venture to the nearby city, that lies in ruins, overrun by monsters...

Boundary Gate is an old-fashioned RPG with dungeon-like 3D layout. The game is viewed from first-person perspective, with the exception of battles, where the heroes can be seen from an "over-the-shoulder" view. The attacks are animated. Enemies are random, and combat is turn-based, the party members using equipped weapons to attack or magical spells. Important locations are presented as 2D pictures. There is also voice acting for important conversations.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Pack-In-Video Co., Ltd</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Buster Ball">
    <id>65616A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Buster Ball</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Buster Fight">
    <id>65617A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Buster Fight</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Caesars Palace">
    <id>65618A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Caesars Palace</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Can Can Bunny Extra">
    <id>38427A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Can Can Bunny Extra</title>
      <synopsis>The fifth  Can Can Bunny game is also the first direct sequel within the series. The story is very similar to the one of the  previous game: once again, the hero is lonely and is anxious to get a girlfriend, or, to be more precise, to have sex with different girls. And once again, the benevolent and gorgeous goddess Swatty is here to provide assistance, together with her side-kicks, the Seven Lucky Gods from the Japanese mythology.

Even though the story is pretty much the same as in the previous game,  the gameplay underwent significant enhancements. The interface is still traditional Japanese-style menu commands, but there are many more locations now, many of which can be freely accessed by clicking on them while on the main map. Once the player has reached the point where he can begin the physical seduction of the girl, the interface switches to point-and-click, with context-sensitive cursor for touching, kissing, etc. It is necessary to try different actions more than once to understand what the girl considers pleasant and what not, otherwise the girl might get angry and the game will be over. There are many more girls to seduce here than in the previous game, ranging from a school girl to a Catholic nun (seriously). There are also various extras (as the title implies), including an extensive album that arranges various pictures of the girls so that they tell her story, and an additional collection of stories, in which the hero can learn more about the girls he had met in the main game, and even interact with them again.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Cocktail Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Cocktail Soft</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Car Licence">
    <id>65619A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Car Licence</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Championship Hockey">
    <id>65620A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Championship Hockey</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Chip Chan Kick!">
    <id>38428A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Chip Chan Kick!</title>
      <synopsis>This is a platform game similar in style to  Bubble Bobble and particularly to  Parasol Stars. There are two playable characters, both of which are little girls. There is no difference between them gameplay-wise: both use a large blob-like animal to hit enemies from a short distance in a yo-yo-like fashion. It is possible to choose one of them as a single player, or to use them both cooperatively in the two-player mode.

Each level of the game is divided into 10 stages, all of which are single screens with platform constructions. The player must eliminate all the enemies who wander around the stage before being able to advance to the next one. Once the enemy is successfully hit with the blob, the enemy becomes stunned for a short while. It is then possible to kick him off screen. Defeated enemies turn into random power-ups, which include speeding up the character, making her have two or even three blobs instead of one, adding an extra life, making her invincible for a while, etc. The 10th stage of each level requires the player to defeat a boss. The bosses have two forms: the first is a character the same size as the player character, which takes a while to defeat and which has the ability to revive regular enemies; the second form is a traditional platform game over-sized monster. The monsters have different attacks, including projectiles and generating smaller enemies, and have to be hit many times with the blob to go down.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <developer>Custom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Tyoushin Heiki Zeroigar">
    <id>38429A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Chshin Heiki Zeroigar</title>
      <synopsis>The Galactic Emperor Zemu is conquering one planet after the other, planning to expand his empire to the known limits of the galaxy. The reason for his success are huge robots who fight in his armies, developed with the technology invented by the genius scientist Dr. Lulu. But the doctor understands herself that her inventions have caused misery and destruction to other nations. She runs away, taking design plans for the giant robots with her. She arrives on the Earth ( Japan, to be exact) shortly after World War II, and with the help of local scientists, develops a powerful robot, that alone can protect Earth from Zemu's attacks: Super God Trooper Zeroigar!

 Zeroigar is the only shooter for the PC-FX system, continuing the legacy of vertically scrolling shooters from the PC Engine (TurboGrafx) era. The player controls Zeroigar as a plane and as a robot (for boss battles). As in most shooters, power-ups appear frequently. Every level starts with the default weapon, which can be enhanced with these power-ups. Secondary weapons (bombs, torpedoes, etc.) can also be found. A somewhat unusual feature of "Zeroigar" is its leveling-up system. The player is awarded experience points, depending on his performance during a stage. After completing a stage (or after a Game Over screen), the player is able to use those points to increase Zeroigar's parameters (health, defense, weapon power, etc.). The player is given unlimited continues, but he has to begin the level from the first screen each time. Anime-style movies advance the story between levels.</synopsis>
      <genre>Shooter</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Fupac|Winds Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Cj Elephant Fugitive">
    <id>65621A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>CJ Elephant Fugitive</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Cliffhanger">
    <id>65622A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Cliffhanger</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Cocktail Pack">
    <id>38430A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Cocktail Pack</title>
      <synopsis>Cocktail Pack contains two famous adult adventures by  Cocktail Soft:

1.   Pia Carrot e Youkoso!!
2.   Can Can Bunny Extra DX</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Cocktail Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Cocktail Soft</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Comic Road">
    <id>38431A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Comic Road</title>
      <synopsis>Comic Road is a "life simulation" game, starring a young girl (whom the player names themselves) who dreams of becoming a manga artist. In order to become successful, she has to do more than just draw well; it is important to develop other aspects of her personality, and also keep an eye on the finances, otherwise working too much might deteriorate her drawing skills. Social life, physical exercises, reading - everything has consequences!

The gameplay consists mainly of making decisions (through menu choices); there is no player character navigation in the game, except shops, which are viewed from first-person perspective. There is a variety of ways to manage the girl's life. The player can make a schedule for a whole month, or decide every day what to do. Every action has an effect on the heroine's parameters. For example, just resting every day reduces physical shape and appeal. Working on the manga increases respective skills. It is possible to call friends and spend time with them, or go shopping. There are many items in the game, all of which influence the heroine's stats in that or another way - for example clothes, drawing accessories, books, or even a PC-FX console, that can be bought in an electronics store for about 20000 yen.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Cocktail Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Crayon Shin-chan - Taiketsu! Kantam Panic!!">
    <id>65623A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Crayon Shin-chan - Taiketsu! Kantam Panic!!</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Crazy Faces">
    <id>65624A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Crazy Faces</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Cutey Honey">
    <id>38432A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Cutey Honey</title>
      <synopsis>The game is based on Go Nagai's manga, that was later made into anime TV series. Rather than following the plot of the manga, the game has the player assume the role of a nameless male detective, who is headed to a fictional country called Austral Island in search of a missing girl. When the hero arrives on the island, he soon discovers that there is some sort of a supernatural organization that might be the reason for the girl's disappearance. Then he hooks up with Honey Kisaragi, the heroine of the manga and TV series, who is an android that can assume various combat forms and fight evil creatures.

This is an adventure game with simple interaction (point-and-click), the cursor turning blue for looking at objects and yellow for using them or talking to people. At some screens there are multiple dialogue choices. There are no puzzles in the game, but sometimes the player controls Honey in combat sequences, which play like a mini-game that involves pressing a button as many times as possible within a time limit, and choosing vulnerable spots on the enemy's body to execute attacks. There is also a map of the island which the player can navigate the main character on. 

Unlike many other Japanese adventures, characters are animated on almost every screen in Cutey Honey, and a large portion of the game is occupied by anime-style movies.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Datawest</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Daffy Duck In Hollywood">
    <id>65625A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Daffy Duck in Hollywood</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Der Langrisser Fx">
    <id>38433A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Der Langrisser</title>
      <synopsis>"Der Langrisser" is a sequel to the game that was known outside of Japan as  Warsong, and is in fact a remake of the Genesis game  Langrisser II.

The Blue Dragon Knights of the Rayguard Empire are trying to steal the virtuous sorceress Riana. Their goal is to make her serve the evil Emperor Bozel, whose intention is to find the most powerful evil sword in the land, the Alhazard. Naturally, the main hero of the game, the knight Elwin, has not only to rescue Riana, but to retrieve the legendary holy sword Langrisser, the only artifact that is more powerful than Alhazard. At first, Elwin automatically follows the "good" path, but as the game progresses, he can choose whether to continue being good, to become an ally with Rayguard, or to side with the forces of Chaos whose goal is utter destruction.

"Der Langrisser" features a complex character creation process, during which you must answer morally ambiguous questions,  Ultima-style, that will determine the class and the attributes of the main hero. The game is a strategy RPG in which you control your party only during battles. You just hire soldiers and unite them under commands of generals. When your units attack the enemy, an automatic battle sequence occurs. You can also use magic spells to heal your troops or to harm enemy soldiers.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Role playing games,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Juegos de rol,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Jeu de rôles,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Rollenspiele,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <synopsis>"Der Langrisser" é uma sequela do jogo que se conhecia fora do Japão como Warsong e, de fato, é um remake do jogo Genesis Langrisser II.

Os Cavaleiros do Dragão Azul do Império Rayguard estão tentando roubar a feiticeira virtuosa Riana. Seu objetivo é fazê-la servir o imperador Bozel malvado, cuja intenção é encontrar a espada malvada mais poderosa na terra, o Alhazard. Naturalmente, o herói principal do jogo, o cavaleiro Elwin, não só tem que resgatar Riana, mas também recuperar a legendária espada sagrada Langrisser, o único artefato que é mais poderoso do que Alhazard. Em primeiro lugar, Elwin segue automaticamente o caminho "bom", mas, à medida que o jogo progride, ele pode escolher se deve continuar sendo bom, se tornar um aliado com o Rayguard, ou para se juntar com as forças do Caos, cujo objetivo é uma destruição total.

"Der Langrisser" apresenta um processo complexo de criação de personagem, durante o qual você deve responder perguntas moralmente ambíguas, Ultima-style, que determinarão a classe e os atributos do herói principal. O jogo é um RPG de estratégia no qual você controla sua festa somente durante as batalhas. Você apenas contrata soldados e os unifica sob comandos de generais. Quando suas unidades atacam o inimigo, ocorre uma seqüência de batalha automática. Você também pode usar feitiços mágicos para curar suas tropas ou prejudicar soldados inimigos.</synopsis>
      <genre>Aventura, Jogos de RPG,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Crosstalk Inc.|NCS Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <date year="1996" month="04" day="26"/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Doukyusei 2">
    <id>38434A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Dkysei 2</title>
      <synopsis>Dokyusei 2 is a classic "love adventure", a genre that is also referred to (quite erroneously) as "dating simulations". You are a high-school student, whose father is a famous archaeologist traveling around the world, and whose mother died when he was a child. It is now your third year at the 88 High School, and naturally, your primary concern is your love life. Will you be able to date successfully and to come to a happy ending with one of the fifteen lovely female classmates?

The game mechanics are a lot like in a "standard" adventure game (examine objects, visit various locations, talk to people, make decisions), but the plot centers exclusively around your relationship with the girls. The game has its own internal clock. You can move around your character on a "city map", visiting different locations. Every visit takes 20-30 minutes of game time. You can make appointments and visit various places at a specific time. The decisions you make influence the story.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Elf Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Avenue, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Donald No Magical World">
    <id>65626A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Donald no Magical World</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Doraemon - Waku Waku Pocket Paradise">
    <id>65627A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Doraemon - Waku Waku Pocket Paradise</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Double Dragon">
    <id>65628A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Double Dragon</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Doukyuusei 2">
    <id>126147</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Doukyuusei 2</title>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
      <synopsis>"Doukyuusei 2" is a classic "love adventure", a genre that is also referred to (quite erroneously) as "dating simulation".

You are a high-school student, whose father is a famous archaeologist traveling around the world, and whose mother died when he was a child. It is now your third year at the 88 High School, and naturally, your primary concern is your love life. Will you be able to date successfully and to come to a happy ending with one of the fifteen lovely female classmates?

The game mechanics are a lot like in a "standard" adventure game (examine objects, visit various locations, talk to people, make decisions), but the plot centers exclusively around your relationship with the girls. The game has its own internal clock. You can move around your character on a "city map", visiting different locations. Every visit takes 20-30 minutes of game time. You can make appointments and visit various places at a specific time. The decisions you make influence the story</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Elf Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Corporation</publisher>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Dragon Knight 4">
    <id>38435A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Dragon Knight 4</title>
      <synopsis>This is a sequel to the well-known hentai RPG  Knights of Xentar, which is originally called "Dragon Knight 3". Years have passed after Takeru (a.k.a. Desmond, the hero of "Knights of Xentar") defeated the ultimate evil. He married his sweetheart Luna, and they had a son named Kakeru. This 15-year-old boy has one weakness: he likes naked female elves... But soon he learns the evil wizard Lushifon wants to turn all people into stones, and to control the whole world without being disturbed by them. Together with the mysterious swordsman Eto, and many other heroes, Kakeru must perform his ultimate quest and to defeat Lushifon and his minions.

This is a strategy RPG: during battles, you control nine units, assigned according to the class of the character who leads the unit. Your opponents also form similar groups, and are also divided into classes. Each class has its own range, strengths, and weaknesses. There are many characters you can recruit to your party, and they belong to different classes (barbarians, archers, magicians, etc.).

Note: the adult content (hentai scenes which include nudity) has been removed in SNES, Saturn, and Playstation versions. Playstation version has updated graphics and CG animations. The game was released exclusively in Japan.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Role playing games,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Juegos de rol,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Jeu de rôles,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Rollenspiele,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura, Jogos de RPG,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Elf Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Avenue, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="7">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Dunk Kids">
    <id>65630A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Dunk Kids</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="F1 - World Championship Edition">
    <id>65631A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>F1 - World Championship Edition</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Farland Story">
    <id>38436A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Farland Story</title>
      <synopsis>"Farland Story" in the first in the row of successful Japanese strategy RPG games. The main hero of the game is a knight named Arc, who is in love with the beautiful priestess Ferio. One day, when Arc and his best friend Randia are out of town, a hostile army under the command of a mysterious Black Knight invades the town and kidnaps Ferio. Thus begins Arc's quest to defeat the enemies and to rescue his beloved one from their clutches.

"Farland Story" consists entirely of battles (save cut scenes and the ability to shop if you are near a town after a battle). During battles, you move Arc and his party over the terrain, and attack when there are enemies in range. The party consists of different classes - knights attack with swords, archers specialize in long-ranged combat, priestesses heal, etc. Every attack leads to a counter-attack, from the enemy's side as well as from yours. You gain experience points for every attack, and can level up in the middle of a battle.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre> Jogos de RPG,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Technical Group Laboratory, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Fire Woman - Matoi-gumi">
    <id>38437A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Fire Woman: Matoi-gumi</title>
      <synopsis>The protagonist of this game is an exchange student who just got transferred to the Shirosagi high school. Upon his arrival he witnesses a boy bullying a school girl. Naturally, he comes to her rescue, but gets badly beaten by the boy and his friends. To his astonishment, three high school girls arrive and defeat the ruffians. The hero learns that those girls belong to an organization called "Matoi-gumi". Well-trained in martial arts, these girls protect the campus from hooligans and alike. The hero decides to join Matoi-gumi. Maybe he will save enough girls to make one of them grateful and become his girlfriend!

Fire Woman: Matoi-gumi is an RPG, though not in the traditional sense. There are no supernatural occurrences in the game. Character growth is determined by training, not by fighting enough battles to level up. Learning martial arts, playing basketball, participating in chemistry class - everything has an effect on the hero's parameters. There are no random battles in the game; the fights are story-related and usually occur when the hero attempts to rescue a girl. The battles are turn-based, but have a timer for each turn; before the time runs out, the player has to input a combination of four moves for the hero (including punches, kicks, etc.). 

There is also a "dating sim" element in the game. "Important" girls can be seen on a special screen called "GPS" ("Gal Positioning System"). If they are in trouble, they will have sweat on their faces. It is up to the player to decide whether to rescue the girl or not. Sometimes it is possible to become friendly with the girl through other means, such as participating in a club she likes. Walking the girl home increases her affection. By the end of the game, the hero will end up with the girl who likes him most and whom he has spent the most time with. The game has a schedule, keeping track of events such as holidays, girls' birthdays, etc., though the actual game is not real-time - a day ends when the player decides to have the hero go home, or as a conclusion of a story-related event.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Tokuma Shoten Publishing Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="First Kiss Story">
    <id>38438A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>First Kiss Story</title>
      <synopsis>Sadly known as the last game originally released for PC-FX (it was later ported to Playstation), First Kiss Story has the player assume the role of a high school boy (whom the player must name himself), whose parents left town one month before his graduation. So during this month, he will live by his parent's friends, the Orikura family, which consists of two sisters, Kana and Manami, and their mother, a young and attractive widow. Yes, you've guessed it - the hero (and the player) can conquer the hearts of all three, plus a dozen more lovely girls that populate the city of Akitsuki - and that is pretty much what the story is about.

First Kiss Story is what is commonly called a "visual novel", with even less interaction than a typical Japanese adventure with its menu-based commands. All the player can do here is to access locations from the town map, and sometimes choose a dialogue option. The locations with a "girl event" in them are marked with a heart on the map. Depending on the decisions taken by the player, the hero will end up with one of the pretty girls. 

Despite suggestive themes and some mildly erotic images, there is no nudity in this game.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>HuneX Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Fray - Shugyou Hen">
    <id>65632A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Fray - Shugyou Hen</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Fred Couples' Golf">
    <id>65633A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Fred Couples' Golf</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Frogger">
    <id>65634A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Frogger</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="From Tv Animation - Slam Dunk - Shouri E No Starting 5">
    <id>65635A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>From TV Animation - Slam Dunk - Shouri e no Starti</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Fushigi No Kuni No Angelique">
    <id>38439A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Fushigi no Kuni no Angelique</title>
      <synopsis>This game is a variation on the  Angelique story: an ordinary school girl named Angelique becomes involved in a struggle to become the Queen of Cosmos, for which it is necessary to befriend the handsome and powerful Guardians of the Elements. The game features the same world and graphics as  Angelique Special, with a slightly different story: Angelique falls asleep outside near a tree, and dreams that she fell through a rabbit hole (in an Alice in Wonderland fashion) into the magical land where she encounters her eternal rival Rosalia.

Unlike other Angelique games, Fushigi no Kuni plays like a board game, with the kingdom divided into fields on which Angelique moves. There are no visible dice, but the amount of fields Angelique can walk on is determined randomly by clicking on the "move" button. Fields can either be empty, placed inside a location (like Angelique's own room), trigger events, conversations, etc. In some places it is possible to find items, which can then be used on another field to help Angelique advance more quickly, increasing her chances to become the queen.</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Koei</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Graduation">
    <id>38441A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Graduation</title>
      <synopsis>Graduation is a Japanese anime "life-sim" game which are popular in Japan. Except for Princessmaker 2, which was never officially released, this is the only game of its type that I know of which was ever translated to English.

In Graduation you take the role of a homeroom teacher who is given the responsibility of teaching five girls in their last year of high school. You determine their class schedules, do guidance counseling, interfere with their weekend plans, and occasionally take to the streets to make sure they're not getting into trouble. Each of the girls have their own individual personality and problems, and the choices you make will determine whether they graduate from high school, what they do with their lives afterwards, and whether or not they wind up hating your guts. Get them all into top colleges and your boss will praise your genius. If they all flunk or wind up wanting to marry you, you'll obviously be fired.

Despite what common sense and knowledge of the Japanese psyche might lead you to believe, this is not an adult (or hentai) game and there's no nudity and only an average amount of anime sexploitation.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <developer>Headroom</developer>
    <publisher>Riverhill Software Inc.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="J.b. Harold - Blue Chicago Blues">
    <id>38442A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>J.B. Harold: Blue Chicago Blues</title>
      <synopsis>Following  Murder Club, this is another detective story about the fearless private investigator J.B. Harold. This time, an unknown woman in a red dress was murdered in Chicago. A female detective who began investigating the murder was killed as well, and this time the killer made it look like a suicide. J.B. Harold arrives at Chicago and has now to work together with the local police and to solve the mystery.

J.B. Harold: Blue Chicago Blues is an interactive movie. Most of the player's time is spent watching movie footage (with real actors and scenery). At certain points, the movie freezes, and the player is presented with a screen with two or more choices. Each choice advances the clock, so it is necessary to plan well in order not to run out of time and to successfully solve the case.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Riverhill Software Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Kishin Douji Zenki Fx Vajura Fight">
    <id>38443A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Kishin Dji Zenki FX: Vajra Fight</title>
      <synopsis>Kishin Doji Zenki FX: Vajra Fight is based on the manga Kishin Doji Zenki by Kikuhide Tani. Once upon a time the Japanese priest Enno has fought and defeated the demon lord Zenki. Zenki was sealed for centuries in the magical bracelet than the Enno family carried through generations. But now, in modern-day Japan, demons called Seeds of Karuma, who worship an ancient evil goddess, began to appear on the Earth, bringing death and destruction. Enno's descendant, a lovely young girl named Chiaki, has no choice but to use her bracelet to summon Zenki! But while being sealed, Zenki has reverted to the form of a nasty, greedy little boy. Chiaki must evoke the power of bracelet to make Zenki fight on her side, and destroy the demons!

Vajra Fight is what is commonly called a beat-em-up game, similar to games like  Final Fight and others. Controlling either Zenki or Chiaki (or both in two player mode), the player must typically eliminate a number of enemies on a screen until he/she is allowed to proceed. Zenki fights melee-style, while Chiaki uses ranged energy balls; she can also summon Zenki with the bracelet power-up to inflict massive damage. Zenki and Chiaki can also execute various special attacks, which can be mapped to the controller for quicker access. There are many boss fights in the game, some stages consisting of one large-scale boss battle.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Kokuu Hyouryuu Nirgends">
    <id>38444A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Kok Hyry Nirgends</title>
      <synopsis>Koku Hyoryo Nirgends tells the story of a young man named Dünn Bit, who was just recruited for a special military unit called "Windmühle". Led by the young and pretty captain Eis Schwarz, this unit specializes in unique airplanes that can transform into giant combat robots called "Divers". They have recently began operation in the country of Vidar, where enemy activity has been spotted. Dünn has to prove himself as a capable pilot and fighter, and perhaps also to make impression on the gorgeous captain or other people in his team, most of which are pretty girls...

The game is a mixture of Japanese-style adventure and airplane combat simulation (with the addition of giant robot fights). The adventure parts follow a standard procedure: navigating an overview map of a location, and choosing menu commands ("Look", "Talk", "Think", etc. to interact). The combat is a simulation of a plane from the pilot's point of view, which includes managing fuel and ammunition, positioning the plane, tracking enemies on the radar, customizing plane parts, etc. Transformation into a diver can be done at any time during battles, and has its own advantages and disadvantages.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura,Simulação</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Micro Cabin Corp.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Konpeki No Kantai">
    <id>38445A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Konpeki no Kantai</title>
      <synopsis>Konpeki no Kantai is based on the anime series Deep Blue Fleet, which, in its turn, is based on the novel of the same name by Yoshio Aramaki. The game follows the story of the anime since the first episode. It is set in an alternate universe, following a fictional story of a real historical character, admiral Isoroku Yamamoto (1884 -1943), the commander of the Japanese fleet during World War II. In reality, he was killed during a plane attack by American forces. However, in the anime (and the game) he is miraculously transported on board of the ship Nisshin, shortly after the battle of Tsushima, in 1905. Afterwards, he uses his knowledge from the future to make sure that Japan will be the most powerful country in the world.

The game re-creates the pseudo-historical battles against USA during the alternate World War II, such as depicted in the anime. It is a turn-based strategy game with heavy emphasis on naval combat. Controlling the Japanese Deep Blue Fleet, the player has the ability to micro-manage every aspect of it, including customizing waships, assigning soldiers, and even creating new weapons to be deployed in battles.</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Micro Cabin Corp.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1995" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Last Imperial Prince">
    <id>38446A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Last Imperial Prince</title>
      <synopsis>When an army of monsters attacked the castle Camelot and forced the Emperor to resign, the whole country fell under their rule, and the Emperor's son Radius had to flee. But in his heart, the young prince still hopes to reclaim the land that is rightfully his, and to defeat the monstrous conquerors. With the aid of his best friend, the wandering monk Nova, and a female fighter Mirion, Radius begins his quest.

Last Imperial Prince is an action RPG that plays from a platform perspective. Radius and his AI-controlled party fight enemies (who appear on set locations) in real time, using melee attacks and magic. The party members level up, learn new spells, can equip weapons and armor and buy items in stores.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Cuando un ejército de monstruos atacó el castillo de Camelot y obligó al emperador a dimitir, todo el país cayó bajo su dominio, y el hijo del emperador Radius tuvo que huir. Pero en su corazón, el joven príncipe todavía espera recuperar la tierra que es legítimamente suya, y derrotar a los monstruosos conquistadores. Con la ayuda de su mejor amigo, el monje errático Nova, y una luchadora Mirion, Radius comienza su búsqueda. Last Imperial Prince es un RPG de acción que juega desde una perspectiva de plataforma. Radio y su partido controlado por la IA luchar contra los enemigos (que aparecen en las ubicaciones establecidas) en tiempo real, utilizando ataques cuerpo a cuerpo y magia. Los miembros de la partida suben de nivel, aprenden nuevos hechizos, pueden equipar armas y armaduras y comprar artículos en las tiendas.</synopsis>
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Nihon Application Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Lunatic Dawn Fx">
    <id>38447A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Lunatic Dawn FX</title>
      <synopsis>In spite of its Japanese origin, Lunatic Dawn is in fact much more similar to very old-school Western RPGs than to its Japanese brethren. It has virtually no story and relies entirely on exploration and strategic combat. Set in a medieval world with little to no distinguishing characteristics, "Lunatic Dawn" throws the player immediately into the game world, which is open for him to explore. The player is able to choose the main character's gender, race (human, elf, etc.), class, and even age - older characters are more powerful, but have a more limited play time.

Indeed, the entire gameplay process is timed. Traveling to a remote city or dungeon can take up to several game days. The player has to provide sufficient food for his party during this time. Player party consists of pre-generated characters, who have different names and belong to different races and classes, but have virtually no personality. Food and other supplies can be acquired in towns, through which the player moves in a  Wizardry-like fashion - viewing locations from first-person perspective and selecting menu commands.

When the party enters a dungeon, the view switches to isometric. The dungeons are large and maze-like, with enemies visible on screen. Upon contact with an enemy, a battle initiates. The battles are turn-based but fast-paced, reminding somewhat the Infinity Engine battles from  Baldur's Gate series. The participants can freely move on the battle field. The player directly controls only the main characters, but can assign general commands to the party members.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Artdink</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1995" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Mahjong Gok Tenjiku">
    <id>38448A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Mahjong Gok Tenjiku</title>
      <synopsis>Mahjong Gokuu Tenjiku is a mahjong tournament between characters from Xi You Ji ("Journey to the West"), the classic Chinese novel. The player can choose to play as either of the four "good" characters from Xi You Ji: the Buddhist monk Xuan Zang, the famous monkey Sun Wukong, the pig Bajie, and Xuan Zang's pupil Wujing. They compete against the variety of Xi You Ji villains. The player can choose a location to set a mahjong game in, and adapt most of mahjong rules to his own liking in a special menu.</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Chat Noir</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Makeruna! Makendou Z">
    <id>38449A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Makeruna! Makend Z</title>
      <synopsis>Makeruna! Makendo Z takes place in the same universe as the  Makeruna! Makendo, known outside of Japan as Kendo Rage. However, unlike the first game (or its  sequel), this is a Japanese-style RPG. Like the other  Makeruna! Makendo games (the name means Don't lose, magic kendo!), it has comedy elements. The story takes place in a highschool, attended by two sisters, Hikari and Mai. Their cousin Saya just came back to Japan from the USA, where she was sent as an exchange student. Due to an unfortunate experiment, the gate to the demon world opens in the school. Using their magic kendo powers, the girls have to find portals to the demon world, defeat the demons, and restore peace in the school.

Makeruna! Makendo Z  plays like a traditional Japanese RPG, with top-down navigation and random turn-based battles viewed from first-person perspective. The gameplay system is simplified even compared to other Japanese RPGs: game progression is strictly linear, and the girls cannot equip anything. They have, however, access to magic spells and various kendo techniques. 

The game features anime-style movies and still shots. Every kendo technique, for example, is displayed as a full-screen anime-style picture.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Fill in Café Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="9">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1998" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Megami Tengoku 2">
    <id>38450A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Megami Tengoku II</title>
      <synopsis>The second game based on the Megami Paradise anime series is not directly related story-wise to the  first one, and also belongs to a different genre. The game is set in a magical land ruled by women, namely the benevolent goddess Mamamega, with the dark goddess Yamimama constantly trying to defeat her and take over. Each goddess is surrounded by "shrine maidens", all of which are young and pretty girls. 

The game lets the player control any of the eight shrine maidens, four on Mamamega's side (Rurubell, Lilith, Stashia. and Juliana), and four on Yamimama's side (Rouge, Pastel, Angela, and Maharaja). It is possible to switch between girls on the same side, but not between those of the opposing camp. The goal of the game is to gather as many followers as possible. The player navigates his favorite shrine maiden through the vast top-down world of Megami Paradise, trying to recruit as many people as possible on their side. The girls can talk to people using different approaches (sweet, passionate, etc.). They can buy a variety of items to increase their parameters and hence their appeal factor to the average citizen. Changing clothes also helps sometimes. There are also some battles, which utilize a slot machine system, and other mini-games. The game has a night/day cycle (much faster than real time); some places will be open only during the day or vice versa. The goal has to be achieved within a year of game time.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Simulação,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>HuneX Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Minimum Nanonic">
    <id>38451A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Minimum Nanonic</title>
      <synopsis>A scientist has been conducting an experiment that went wrong... very wrong. An explosion shattered the house. Afterwards, a cute little toy named Michael opened his eyes... to find out that he is, indeed, alive. He can think, talk, and walk now. The first decision he makes is to check on the three lovely daughters of the scientists: Hikari, Nozomi, and Tsubasa. To his (and their) astonishment, the failed experiment made all the three girls tiny! Now Michael and the girls have to find the crazy Dad and somehow revert everything back to normal.

Minimum Nanonic is a traditional Japanese adventure, with the story either unfolding automatically, or triggered by selecting verbs from the menu ("Look", "Think", etc.). There are no wrong choices, and it is impossible to die in the game. If Michael makes a wrong decision, he will simply refuse to do what he chose, and the player will have to try another option.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>NEC Interchannel, Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Miraculum - The Last Revelation">
    <id>38452A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Miraculum: The Last Revelation</title>
      <synopsis>In the world of Miraculum, there lived a powerful king named Siegwald. But his power was not enough for him, and he revived an ancient demon who had been sealed in a statue. But instead of granting him his power, the demon consumed the king's soul and possessed his body. He then swore to destroy humanity once and for all.

After several years, the fake Siegwald led his armies to conquer lands and to expand his empire. At that time, a warrior named Jay arrived at the port city of Heles. Now he must find loyal allies and eventually stop the Emperor's evil plans.

Miraculum: The Last Revelation plays like a traditional Japanese-style RPG, with a world map, towns and dungeons to visit, and enemies to defeat in random battles with turn-based combat. The setting is mostly medieval fantasy, but there are sci-fi elements as well. The player's party can use a variety of moves in battles, and it is also possible to set the characters on AI mode, only assigning them general strategies. Graphically the game resembles typical 16-bit Japanese RPGs, but it has some anime-style cut scenes, CD-quality music, and voice-overs for important conversations.</synopsis>
      <genre>Role playing games</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Juegos de rol</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Jeu de rôles</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Rollenspiele</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>RayForce Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Ojousama Sousamou">
    <id>38453A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Ojsama Ssam</title>
      <synopsis>Ojosama Sosamo is based on the anime series Debutants Detective Corps, which tells the story of a group of young girls, led by the wealthy Ayanokouji sisters, which have received a threatening letter and decide to work as detectives to find out who has sent it. However, the game doesn't follow this story and instead puts the player into the shoes of a nameless male thief, whose goal is to outsmart the girls and to steal valuables successfully!

This is an adventure/puzzle game. The player navigates the thief through isometric locations. Each location typically contains dangerous spots that would deplete the thief's HP, and puzzles to solve, for example complex mazes with one-way-tiles. If the girls are close, the thief will hear a warning voice. Once a girl appears, it is possible to fight her in turn-based combat, but that requires weapons or other items, which should be found and which are not always readily accessible. If the hero's HP reaches zero, he is caught by the girls and put in prison.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Headroom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Pachio-kun Fx - Maboroshi No Shima Daikessen">
    <id>38454A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Pachio-Kun FX: Maboroshi no Shima Daikessen</title>
      <synopsis>Pachio-Kun FX is a  pachinko game. The popular pachinko mascot Pachio-kun, who looks like a pachinko ball with legs, is setting up a pachinko tournament on the Ghost Island. The player can choose to control one of the several available characters; even though the choice doesn't affect the gameplay, choosing different characters leads to different anime FMVs displayed during pachinko moves. The goal is to defeat the 7 pachinko masters, who can be met and challenged to a battle at different locations on the island. The battles involve not only using your own pachinko machine, but also freezing the ball the opponent is currently playing for an amount of time. This can be done by playing alone in various pachinko parlors and gathering balls and special points.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Coconuts Japan Entertainment Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Pia Carrot E Ykoso!!">
    <id>38455A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Pia Carrot e Ykoso!!</title>
      <synopsis>In Pia Carrot e YÅkoso!!, the player controls Yusuke Kinoshita, a 18-year-old male Japanese high-school student. He intends to have a cool summer vacation, but realizes he has no money. Having no choice, he takes a job in his father's restaurant, "Pia Carrot". Thus begins an adventure much more exciting than the summer vacation he has dreamed about: he gets to know many beautiful girls in the restaurant, and has to decide which one is the love of his life...

The game is a true dating simulation, with the gameplay focusing on making schedules and choosing activities for the protagonist. In the beginning of each day, the player typically choose an action before it's time to go to work. These actions range from giving a call to any of the girls the hero meets during the game, going to different locations, simply resting, etc. While at work, the player should make a schedule for Yusuke, sending him to work in different places (kitchen, basement, counter, etc.). After work, it's time to choose which girl to talk to. There are also many events that prompt the player to choose an action or a conversation option.

All these actions influence Yusuke's statistics, ultimately making him more (or less) attractive to the various girls he meets on his path. Depending on the way the player shapes and schedules the activities of the main character, he will follow one of the many different narratives, meet different people, and eventually - if the player is persistent enough - win the heart of the girl he loves.

The computer and the PC-FX versions feature scenes with explicit nudity and sexual situations.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Cocktail Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Cocktail Soft</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Power Dolls Fx">
    <id>38456A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Power Dolls FX</title>
      <synopsis>In the 25th century, mankind has colonized all known space. Earth became somewhat of an Empire, ruling over all the colonies, the Terran government known for its ruthless methods. Finally, the planet Omni could not bear the tyranny of Earth any longer. The military of the planet assembled an all-female special giant robot combat unit called "Power Dolls" ("dolls" standing for Detachment Of Limited Line Service), led by the lovely and athletic Hardy Newland. The battle for freedom begins!

Power Dolls FX is the second game in  Power Dolls series. Like its predecessor, it is a tactical turn-based strategy game. The player can customize the robots, replacing and upgrading their weapons, etc. Navigating the six robots on a top-down battle map, the player can attack enemies when they are in weapon range. Enemy units include other giant robots, tanks, ships, etc. There are two modes in the game: story mode and scenario mode. The story mode has the battles evolve in a linear fashion, with cut scenes between missions. In the scenario mode, the player is free to play any of the story mode scenarios in any order.</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Kogado Studio, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Return To Zork">
    <id>38457A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Return to Zork</title>
      <synopsis>You are standing behind the white house. There is something in the mailbox. A video message from a wizard informing you that you are the sweepstakes winner to the Valley of the Sparrows... right now, by magic flight. Upon arriving at this mysterious place however, not everything is as it should be. There's nobody to meet you and those who you do come across don't seem to have any knowledge about a sweepstakes. It looks like this is a private vacation and you'll need to find your own way through this land.

Return to Zork is a 1st person adventure game using video, and the revival of the famous Zork series by Activation. Similar to Myst in interface, you must rotate your viewpoint to discover new areas and uncover items that can be used or picked up. Various characters will be met along the way and spoken to via a system of dialog choices.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Datawest</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <date year="1995" month="05" day="27"/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="10">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Ruruli Ra Rura">
    <id>38458A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Rururi Ra Rura</title>
      <synopsis>Rururi Ra Rura is a platformer/puzzle game. The player has to find the right way through the vast, maze-like world, using different characters to overcome various obstacles. For example, Axid can use his sword to cut wood or ropes, Reinas uses fire magic to melt ice, etc. As the game progresses, more and more characters will join, each with unique abilities needed to advance, including a frog with long-range jump and a liquid character who can squeeze himself though cracks. Every location has at least one camp, where the player can switch characters.

The large locations have multiple exits, and it is often necessary to return to a location with different characters to unlock new areas or an exit to a new location. There are various enemies in the game, who can be defeated by using physical attacks or character-specific magic. Boss battles are take place on separate screens. There are also plenty of stat-rising and healing items scattered around.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>NEC Interchannel, Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1998" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Same Game Fx">
    <id>152776</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Same Game Fx</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Shanghai The Great Wall">
    <id>103592</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Shanghai The Great Wall</title>
      <genre>Traditional</genre>
      <synopsis>Another version of the ancient game of Mah-Jong. The player is presented with an arrangement of tiles, lined up together and stacked, with either 2 or 4 of each of an array of patterns. These must be removed by matching pairs, but only tiles which are visible and have a space to the left or right can be removed.

This release in the Activision's Shanghai series includes three games along with the Classic Shanghai. In The Great Wall, the tiles are stacked vertically, and fall when lower tiles are removed, a lá Tetris. In Beijing, gaps are created to slide groups of tiles along. The Golden Tile sees two players attempt to clear a set layout at once.

The Triple-theme continues with three game modes: Solitaire, 2-player "Pandamonium", and Arcade. 

Three themed tile sets complete the "Triple Threat".</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Ask Kodansha</publisher>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Shanghai - Triple-threat">
    <id>38459A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Shanghai: Triple-Threat</title>
      <synopsis>Another version of the ancient game of Mah-Jong. The player is presented with an arrangement of tiles, lined up together and stacked, with either 2 or 4 of each of an array of patterns. These must be removed by matching pairs, but only tiles which are visible and have a space to the left or right can be removed.

This release in the Activision's Shanghai series includes three games along with the Classic Shanghai.  In The Great Wall, the tiles are stacked vertically, and fall when lower tiles are removed, a lá Tetris. In Beijing, gaps are created to slide groups of tiles along. The Golden Tile sees two players attempt to clear a set layout at once.  The Triple-theme continues with three game modes: Solitaire, 2-player "Pandamonium", and Arcade.  Three themed tile sets complete the "Triple Threat".</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Ask</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="16">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Sotsugyou - Graduation">
    <id>38460A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Sotsugy: Graduation Real</title>
      <synopsis>A spin-off in the Sotsugyo/Graduation series, this game is just what its title implies: graduation with real people.
 
Instead of anime-style portraits of school girls, there are pictures (and a few full motion videos) of real Japanese young women. Gameplay follows the same formula as the other graduation games: as a high school teacher, the player's task is to successfully lead five high school girls to their graduation. Most of the activities consist of making schedules, organizing classes, and giving assignments to the girls. It is necessary to know the strength and the weaknesses of each girl, in order to choose correct activities. The teacher supervises not only everything the girls do in the school, but also some of their activities during leisure time, including making plans for the holidays.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Headroom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="14">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Sotsugyou 2 Fx - Neo Generation">
    <id>126148</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Sotsugyou 2 Fx - Neo Generation</title>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Sotsugyou R - Graduation Real">
    <id>103593</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Sotsugyou R - Graduation Real</title>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
      <synopsis>A spin-off in the Sotsugyō/Graduation series, this game is just what its title implies: graduation with real people. Instead of anime-style portraits of school girls, there are pictures (and a few full motion videos) of real Japanese young women.

Gameplay follows the same formula as the other graduation games: as a high school teacher, the player's task is to successfully lead five high school girls to their graduation. Most of the activities consist of making schedules, organizing classes, and giving assignments to the girls. It is necessary to know the strength and the weaknesses of each girl, in order to choose correct activities. The teacher supervises not only everything the girls do in the school, but also some of their activities during leisure time, including making plans for the holidays.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="1">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <developer>Headroom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Corporation</publisher>
    <date year="1998" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Sparkling Feather">
    <id>38461A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Sparkling Feather</title>
      <synopsis>Long time ago, there was a happy country called the Eternal Feather Kingdom. Protected by benevolent deities, it flourished until a disaster came: a demon destroyed the kingdom, and it disappeared off the face of the earth. But a few chosen ones, called "Feathers",  continued to keep sacred gemstones, which allowed them to use unique powers in the fight against the demonic army. Each Feather protects a gem, and the protector of the Ruby gem is the protagonist of the game - an ordinary high school boy from our modern world who at first wants nothing to do with ancient prophecies and heroic deeds. But as he receives new power from the leader of the Feathers, he understands that his destiny is to fight evil, and perhaps restore Eternal Feather to its former glory.

Sparkling Feather is a turn-based strategy game with slight RPG and "dating sim" elements. Large-scale battles of the Feathers against demons take place on isometric battle fields. The heroes move on the battle field, attack with weapons when an enemy is in range, and use offensive and healing magic. The party levels up automatically after having won a battle. Between battles, the player can play a roulette-type game, which may allow him to have a date with one of the Feathers (female and male!). During the date the player can choose conversation topics, and depending on his choices the parameters of the companions can increase or decrease.</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>HuneX Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Power League Fx">
    <id>38462A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Super Power League FX</title>
      <synopsis>Super Power League FX allows the player to participate in the most prestigious Japanese baseball league, Nippon Professional Baseball. The player can choose to lead one of the 12 official NPB teams to the title in the championship mode, or simply play separate matches against any team in single match mode. There is also a training mode and a possibility to create own teams, recruit players, and have them take part in the championship.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Deportes</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <date year="1996" month="04" day="26"/>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Super Real Mahjong Pv">
    <id>38463A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Super Real Mahjong PV</title>
      <synopsis>The fifth installment of the most famous strip mahjong series, which originated on the arcades. The player competes against three high-school girls, who take off their clothes when losing.

This is the only console version of Super Real Mahjong in which the girls undress completely. In the previous three games (on TurboGrafx CD) and later installments (mostly on the Saturn), the girls go only as far as underwear. The PC versions were, however, uncensored from the beginning.</synopsis>
      <genre>Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>SETA Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Team Innocent - The Point Of No Return">
    <id>38464A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Team Innocent: The Point of No Return</title>
      <synopsis>The events of the game are set in the future. The Galactic Police discovers that a scientist named Cronus has conducted genetic experiments on human beings. The police chief rescues three little girls, each one of whom bears the traces of these experiments. Fast-forward fifteen years: the three girls - Saki, Lilis, and Ariel - now work for the Galactic Police, determined to find out the truth about their origins and the nature of experiments. They are sent on three dangerous missions - missions they might not survive...

Team Innocent: The Point of No Return is an adventure game with action elements. The player controls each one of the three girls during the three missions. Each of the heroines must explore a large location, collecting items and solving puzzles on the way. The girls can also find and equip various weapons, from pistols to axes. The player can choose one of the three action modes for combat: melee attack, kicking, and shooting. The girls are navigated from third-person perspective  on pre-rendered backgrounds and constantly changing camera angles, much like in old  Resident Evil games, except for the girls being sprites and not 3D models. 

The game has many anime-style cut-scenes and voice-overs for all dialogues.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="15">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1994" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Tekipaki - Working Love Fx">
    <id>38465A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Tekipaki: Working Love FX</title>
      <synopsis>Tekipaki: Working Love FX is essentially an upgraded version of  Tekipaki: Working Love for Turbo CD. It adds several scenarios to the main game, which play mostly like a Japanese-style adventure - the player can choose dialogue options or a location to go to. Those scenarios add more background to the personalities of Naomi, Hikaru, and Edalt, the three extra-terrestrial heroines of the game (for example, in one of the scenarios Hikaru's Martian cat escapes from the zoo, and it's the player's job to find him). The PC-FX version of the game also adds an "omake" option, where it is possible to view pictures of the girls.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <synopsis>Tekipaki: Working Love FX es esencialmente una versión actualizada de Tekipaki: Working Love for Turbo CD. Añade varios escenarios al juego principal, el jugador puede elegir opciones de diálogo o una ubicación para ir. Esos escenarios añaden más antecedentes a las personalidades de Naomi, Hikaru y Edalt, las tres heroínas extraterrestres del juego. La versión PC-FX del juego también agrega la opción "omake", donde es posible ver fotos de las chicas.</synopsis>
      <genre>Aventura,Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <synopsis>Tekipaki: Working Love FX es esencialmente una versión actualizada de Tekipaki: Working Love for Turbo CD. Añade varios escenarios al juego principal, el jugador puede elegir opciones de diálogo o una ubicación para ir. Esos escenarios añaden más antecedentes a las personalidades de Naomi, Hikaru y Edalt, las tres heroínas extraterrestres del juego. La versión PC-FX del juego también agrega la opción "omake", donde es posible ver fotos de las chicas.</synopsis>
      <genre>Abenteuer,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura,Simulação</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>NEC Interchannel, Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="12">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1998" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Tenchi Muy! Ry-ki Fx">
    <id>38466A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Tenchi Muy! Ry-ki FX</title>
      <synopsis>Tenchi MuyÅ! RyÅ-Åki FX includes Tenchi MuyÅ! RyÅ-Åki with slightly better graphics (full-screen pictures instead of framed ones), and a whole new chapter, which is dedicated to officers of the Galaxy Police. The new chapter centers around the green-haired Hakua, who works for Mihoshi Kuramitsu, one of the game's main characters, and Detective Kiyone Makibi, Mihoshi's ex-partner.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <developer>NEC Interchannel, Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="13">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Tengai Makyu Karakuri Kakutouden">
    <id>38467A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Tengai Maky: Denn Karakuri Kakutden</title>
      <synopsis>The ancient demon Yomi is about to be revived once again, and warriors all over the land of Jipang have gathered to stop him. But only the strongest of them can fight Yomi, after he has defeated all the others - because this story is but an excuse for fights between familiar characters from Tengai MakyÅ universe!

This fighting game uses the same system as the previously released Battle Heat: each and every move of the characters is displayed as an anime-style movie. The player presses appropriate buttons for offensive and defensive moves (also controlling the power of the move), after which an anime sequence is shown. In both versus mode (against a computer opponent and two-players mode), it is possible to play as some of the most remarkable Tengai MakyÅ heroes (Ziria, Manjimaru, Kabuki, and others), as well as some of the villains - like the recurrent stupid monkey Mantou.</synopsis>
      <genre>Arcade</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="15">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1995" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Tokimeki Card Paradise - Koi No Royal Straight Flush">
    <id>38468A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Tokimeki Card Paradise: Koi no Royal Straight Flus</title>
      <synopsis>Tokimeki Card Paradise includes four card games: Poker, Blackjack, Speed, and the Japanese card game Papanuki. Each of those games can be played against one or more pretty young female opponents. The girls take their clothes off whenever they lose a turn, until they disrobe completely if they lose the whole game. In a true PC-FX fashion, every undressing move is presented as an anime-style movie.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <synopsis>Tokimeki Card Paradise inclue 4 jeux de cartes : POker, Blackjack, Speed, ainsi qu'un jeu de cartes japonais nommé "Papanuki".
Chaque jeu se joue face à une ou plusieurs adversaires, féminines bien entendu. Les filles retirent un vêtement à chaque fois qu'elles perdent un tour, jusqu'à se retrouver complètement nues.
Dans la plus pure lignée des jeux de ce genre, chaque séquence de strip-tease est présentée sous la forme d'une petite video de type anime.</synopsis>
    </locale>
    <developer>Sonnet Computer Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Sonnet Computer Entertainment</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Tonari No Princess Rolfee">
    <id>38469A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Tonari no Princess Rolfee</title>
      <synopsis>The official mascot of the PC-FX console is now the star of her own game. Rolfee is a princess of a magical land which is threatened by demons. So Rolfee and her family - including a cute little animal called Nyai - move to Japan. Rolfee has to go to high school, and she hopes to study well and make friends. Will she have success in the school? Will she be liked by her classmates? Will she not quarrel too much with her family? It all depends on the player!

Tonari no Princess Rolfee is a Japanese-style adventure game with some mild simulation elements (Rolfee has parameters than can increase or decrease, depending on the player's actions). Most of the interaction consists of choosing which location to go to (through a menu command). A somewhat unusual feature of the game are its random events. Going to a certain location will trigger random appearances of characters, so there are no clear and secure ways to  make certain events happen. Triggering different events leads to different consequences in the story and different endings.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Fupac|Winds Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1997" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Voice Paradise">
    <id>38470A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Voice Paradise</title>
      <synopsis>The hero of the game is in his space ship, on the way to his home planet. But the space ship crash-lands on the Earth. The hero is on an important intergalactic mission and has to be on his home planet no later than in one month. He tries to figure out what caused the crash, and discovers that it was a voice that interfered with the ship's radio waves. Suddenly, three anime girls appear in front of him. They are Citron, Jasmine, and Cinnamon, the heroines of a TV anime series called "Elfin Triangle". They explain that the voice that caused the disturbance was that of a famous Japanese voice actress.... they just don't know which one. To get a sample of this voice would be the only hope to repair the ship... so the hero and his three lovely companions have to find out who the voice belongs to!

Voice Paradise plays, for the most part, like an adventure game with an internal schedule. A visit to every locations costs one game day, and the hero has only 30 days to find the voice actress. The locations include TV studio, CD shop, and other locations that have anything to do with anime and voice acting. The game contains plenty of material about Japanese voice actresses, so it can be described as educational. In order to successfully locate the actress, it is necessary to gather as much information as possible and take part in quiz that would narrow down the search and bring the hero nearer to the goal.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Various</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Varios</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Divers</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Verschiedene</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura,Variados</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Ask</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1996" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Wakusei Kgekitai - Little Cats">
    <id>38471A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Wakusei Kgekitai: Little Cats</title>
      <synopsis>Little Cats is somewhat similar to Sakura Taisen games, with adventure and dating elements reduced, and simulation elements added. David has to make schedules for the girls and decide how much and what exactly they should train. Running competitions, shooting range, robot navigation - everything can be trained, but at the expense of the girls' stamina, which means they will need to rest as well. During the simulation mode, it is also possible to wander around the space station and spend time with the girls.

The strategy part consists of navigating the robots over a battle field in turn-based fashion. The robots have a wide range of attacks, and it is possible to change their weapons and use items in combat. Once the robots attack each other, an automatic attack sequence is shown.</synopsis>
      <genre>Simulation,Strategy</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Simulación,Estrategia</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Simulation,Stratégie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Simulation,Strategie</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Simulação,Estratégia</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Family Soft Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
  <game name="Zen-nihon Joshi Pro Wrestling - Queen Of Queens">
    <id>38472A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Zen-Nihon Joshi Pro Wrestling: Queen of Queens</title>
      <synopsis>Queen of Queens is a wrestling game featuring licensed stars from All Japan Women's Pro-Wrestling League, such as Aja Kong, Akira Hokuto, and others. The game follows the system introduced in Battle Heat: every move is shown as a full-motion video sequence. Unlike "Battle Heat", there are no graphics in "Queen of Queens", but videos of real wrestlers. 

There are two modes in the game: league or free battle. The league mode is an All Japan Women's Pro-Wrestling championship that follows the rules of the league. It is possible to play against the computer or in two-player mode.</synopsis>
      <genre>Sports</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Deportes</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Sport</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>HuneX Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="11">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
    <date year="1995" month="" day=""/>
  </game>
  <game name="Zoku Hatsukoi Monogatari - Shgaku Ryok">
    <id>38473A</id>
    <locale lang="EN">
      <title>Zoku Hatsukoi Monogatari: Shgaku Ryok</title>
      <synopsis>Zoku Hatsukoi Monogatari: ShÅ«gaku RyokÅ is a mixture of adventure and "love simulation" - more specifically, first love. The player takes the role of a male student and can choose any time period between ground school to college. Every time period has four different girls that the hero can fall in love with. The player must choose one of those girls as the main love object. The setting is the same in every time period: the class goes on vacation to different places in Japan. Most of the game consists of traveling from place to place, trying to be at the right place the right time and make the right decision. The player must assemble a schedule for each location. It is possible to manage the player character's finances, as well as buy items that can be given to the girls.</synopsis>
      <genre>Adventure,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="ES">
      <genre>Aventura,Simulación</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="FR">
      <genre>Aventure,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="DE">
      <genre>Abenteuer,Simulation</genre>
    </locale>
    <locale lang="PT">
      <genre>Aventura,Simulação</genre>
    </locale>
    <developer>Tokuma Shoten Intermedia Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <rating type="NOTE" value="">
		</rating>
    <input players="2">
      <control type="wiimote" required="true"/>
      <control type="nunchuk" required="false"/>
      <control type="classiccontroller" required="false"/>
      <control type="gamecube" required="false"/>
    </input>
  </game>
</datafile>
